We say every ISP
as just what we mean by
that first turnstile,
we will look at it
in a Venn diagram.
Then that means that
there's nothing in here.
Things in, there would be
things that are a but not B.
And if every a is B,
then there can't be
anything in here.
If I take the negation of that,
that is to say, if there
is something in here,
which I pictured down here with a
green represented gets inhabited,
then that means some a is not B,
which corresponds to saying
the negation of this thing.
It's not the case that every ISP,
that means it is the case
that somebody is not
p. If we look at this one,
this says, no a is B.
It's not the case that there is
anything which is both a and B.
So that's empty.
And here we say it is
the case that there is something
which is both a and B.
That's some a is b.
And you have to think
of it just to try
and get these things
in your head.
So it's useful to
have these notations.
We saw the object level
control positions.
That's the compositions
on either side of
the turnstile where we had the
turnstile without the not.
But if you just think of it,
these contour position's
work just as well.
If we take the NOX as if we
take the direct turnstiles.
You see you do nowadays when we,
when we do it on
concrete examples
like everyone on that side
of the room as a man,
you, you can see
now, it's not true.
What's it mean to
say it's not true?
It means there were
some women that
you need to be able to take
that and translate
it into symbols.
And the reason we want to
translate it into symbols,
then we can write
down rules like this.
That a much simpler
than trying to remember
complicated expressions
in English language,
which would amount to
saying the same thing
or in Greek or whatever
language you happen to have.
This language is nice
because we can
manipulate it easily.
It structurally very simple.
It's unambiguous.
Its logic. You'll
learn to love it.