Do the first bit for you.
We've got the hypotheses.
Some C is not a,
so this is inhabited.
And sum C is not
p. So your question
is, does this follow?
If it doesn't follow,
what could we find?
How can we show that
it doesn't follow?
It doesn't follow.
That means that there's
some Universe in which
we've interpreted a,
B, and C as predicates.
So there's some
collection of things.
Then there are three
subsets of that collection.
And they satisfy the
premises of this rule,
but they don't satisfy
the conclusion.
Now we start to discover
something interesting
about these models.
I want to make a model,
and I'm only talking
about three predicates,
then there are really
only a few kinds of things
that I can contemplate.
That could be something in
here or they could know.
There could be something in here.
Or they could know
or here, or here,
or all the way out here.
How many possible kinds
of thing are there?
When I'm just talking
about whether
their flowers, fungi, or plants.
There's the only things
I can say about them.
We'll say that things
which don't differ
in that way we'll
count is the same for
the moment because
I've got an example
of one of them.
Or I haven't any examples
doesn't matter if
I got 20 examples or one.
For this purpose.
We're just interested
whether there is
something in there,
nothing in there.
How many different kinds
of thing might I think of?
Who think seven.
Any advance on 78, y eight,
if I think of is there's an,
a two possibilities, yes or no.
Is this a pay another
two possibilities.
So altogether there's four
possibilities for the ice.
And please, let me have C,
two possibilities for
each of these four.
I can have one that
has or doesn't
have C. So that's
coupling it again.
So it's two cubed is eight.
And in general, if I had
n propositional letters,
there will be two to the
power n kinds of thing.
So when we're looking
for a model here,
what we're really
doing is saying,
which of these things
have something in them,
which go to make your model
checking for the moment.
Let's try and make a model with
as many kinds of things as
possible that still
makes this fall.
So let's say I don't want
to put anything in here.
So I won't put anything in there.
I will put something in here.
For all these other white ones.
I could put something in or not.
It would still make
the premises are true,
and it would still make
the conclusion false.
We have to put one in there to
make this conclusion false.
And that would be enough. But it
feels like a very strange model.
But we can put in all of
those and still make
this conclusion false.
So that's the largest
model we could make
that satisfies the premises.
But doesn't satisfy
the conclusion.
This is empty because
if the assumption,
this is empty because
we're trying to make it
so that C does satisfy B.
To show that this
thing isn't true.