Now we're going to take
some control positions and
we're going to make more rules.
So you remember that we made
the first rule barbara.
Then we put Nazi emphases.
Leprosy is putting a
different Lateran at
different predicate
Nazi instead of
C. But once we put
the Nazi law and we
could do control
positions because
B satisfies not c is the
same as c satisfies not B.
So we could just
swap those around.
Those two things mean
exactly the same,
but it gave us a new proposition.
We can do the same thing
now with other rules.
Look at this example.
The ruler at the top is
an exercise for you.
You should be able to derive
it from the mathematicians and
programmers syllogism we
derived in earlier video.
Suppose we have this
rule at the top.
Then we can do something
like substitute not b for b.
So here we've got NOT B and B.
Just by substituting not b for b,
we change that to a b to not
be just substituting justice we
before we substituted Nazi for C.
But when you substitute
not B and not B,
you get not, not p. So
you get a feedback.
And then we can say, Oh, look,
this can be contrapposto.
So we take that.
So this is another new rule.
How many new rules can you get?
Right? You will be expected
to remember all of these.
In fact, when they are
given in this form,
it's really hard even
if you are given
a rule to find out whether
it is one of the one snare,
cuz it's quite hard
to recognize a rule.
You do need to remember this one.
This is Barbara, and this
is where it all starts.
That's the rule that we all
know is valid the moment
we first think of it,
you didn't even have to think
if one thing is
contained in another,
is contained in another than
the first one is
contained in the third.
And it's so easy that we
don't even think about it.
What you should be
able to do is to say,
okay, how does this come
from the one above?
We just put Nazi.
How do we go from
this one to this one?
We direct transposition there.
Ok, where does this
one come from?
Philip at the tops and
the top of that is
the same as that
if I look at the bottom and
the bottom of this type,
just the contraposition, then we
know that when we do
that contraposition,
we are basically
saying the same things
or if one is valid,
the other one is.
So this rule is also valid.
How do we go from here to here?
We went here, we did that.
We swapped the first one.
We swap the second one.
And now what are we going to
do coming from here to here?
Swap the first one back.
We have the original, we
have the one substituted,
and then we can either
swap none of them,
swap one of them, swap
the other row, swap both.
That's what we did on Tuesday.
What happens now is we
can play another game.
We can go this way.
What I've done here is to say,
what happens if I take a
implies b and leave it alone.
But swap these two.
But of course, when we swap them,
it's just like the
alcohol in Scotland.
The conclusion is false.
Then we know that one of
the assumptions is false.
So I've taken the conclusion
and said we know it's false.
One of the assumptions,
and this is the same, it's
the conclusion you
may say it's false.
But we've taken the other of
the assumptions of this
retains that assumption.
This retains that assumption.
And this one has it
negated down there.
And this one has this
assumption negated down there.
That line is just
doing the logic we did for
the alcohol in Scotland.
We get two new rules that
have not seen them
out of one rule,
but didn't have the
knots at the meta level.
Can anyone find this from
whatever the adjacent rules?
I think that one's done by
during the bottom line,
just a contra position there.
Can we find something
that corresponds to
swapping these two
and negating them?
Which we know should be that
if we got a complete set and
the answer is the one next to it.