Good morning. Made this later.
Going to start by reviewing
very briefly some of the
material on syllogisms.
The important point is to
get across the idea of
a proposition because
that's what we
generalize to make a sequence.
So we start from
Aristotle's propositions
and move on to sequence,
which were introduced by Jensen.
But we start very simply,
we have a universe of
things and we have
some collections of things
with particular properties.
So here are the
collection of things
that satisfy the property
a for any thing in the
universe, let's say x.
Then this is the set of things
such that a holds of X.
We represent a as a function.
So a of x is a Boolean
value, true or false.
And this is the set of things
such that a of X is true.
Set of X, such that
a holes of x is what I've
drawn a diagram off here.
And we're interested
in the relationship
between different predicates.
So for example,
here's a predicate.
Another one, be than I've
drawn the set of things such that
b holds of X name this diagram.
Everything that's in a is in B.
And I'm going to write that
in a symbolic notation.
As a satisfies B,
which I say as all a are B.
We then take another example,
and this time, Let's say
this is a, this is b.
And here is the case
that no a, a, B,
every a is contained in
the complement of B,
every a is not v. And we
use this symbol for naught.
If I take something in a and it
doesn't satisfy B for every x in
a b if x is false, now, a hobby.
Now look at that. This
is completely symmetric.
So this tells us our
first logical rule.
If every a is NOT B,
then it's the same
as every B is not a.