To formalize Aristotle's theory
of syllogisms,
reintroduced propositions.
With this notation,
a satisfies B,
which means in an
Euler diagram is
the universe and a
is contained in B.
And if we wanted to say
that a does not satisfy B,
we must provide a
counter-example.
And a counterexample is
an x in the universe such
that a holes of X and B doesn't.
That is, it's an x
for which a of x
is true and B of X is false.
And here we're
mixing notation from
Haskell with
mathematical notation.
But you should learn
to translate between
those two against and sequence or
a simple but very
powerful generalization
of this sequent
looks very similar.
It's talking about something and
says gamma satisfies delta.
But whereas a and B are
predicates of type
U, arrows goo here,
gamma and delta of finite
sets of predicates,
which we'll represent
in Haskell as
lists of things from you to boom.
And the easiest way to
explain what we mean by
gamma satisfies delta is to
say what we mean by
a counterexample.
So we will say that
gamma does not
satisfy delta if we
have a counterexample,
which will be an x of type u
such that for all G in gamma,
because of course, gamma
is a list of predicates.
So for all predicates in
gamma g of x equals true,
and for all the delta
d of x equals false.
So a counterexample is
given by exhibiting
an x such that it satisfies
every G and gamma,
and it satisfies no d in delta.