We finished last time
looking at this.
If we know that in Scotland,
one is between
10:00 AM, 10:00 PM.
You can legally buy alcohol
than if we know
we're in Scotland,
but we cannot
legally buy alcohol.
We know it's not like time.
And if we know it is
between those times and
become legally buy alcohol,
we can infer that
were not in Scotland.
It's true that there might be
other countries with similar
regulations that make me,
we're not in those countries
if we know something
else about the world,
but from these two
things and that rule,
we can only infer that
were not in Scotland.
We can't, for instance,
say We're not in Saudi Arabia,
even if you can't legally
buy alcohol in Saudi Arabia.
So it's only the
things that logically
follow that we're interested in.
What I left you with. With this.
Say, we take that pattern,
but we apply it to
our first syllogism.
The one that everybody
knows is true.
The one that says
everything that satisfies
a satisfies P and everything
satisfies P satisfies c,
then everything
satisfies a satisfy
C. Now how do we read
the other one is suppose
that everything that's in B
satisfy c. Looking appear
on the right hand side.
Everything resumed.
P satisfies c. Two,
what is this saying?
It's not true that everything
that's in a satisfies S0.
That means that there must
be something in a way that
does not satisfy C.
Or put the other way,
something in a pair satisfies
not C. So let's go and
look at these rules.
What can we deduce?
We can deduce by
swapping these two from
where they were before.
In the thing above, we swap
them and negated them both.
What we're seeing here is
the different level of argument
from the one we looked at before.
Earlier. Contraposition with
swapping things and changing
whether they've been negated or
not on either side
of the turnstile.
Now we're swapping things
above and below the
influence line.
This is a good
place to talk about
two different levels of
talking that we do when
we're studying logic.
We say that when we do
contraposition here,
we're working in the
logic statements
in logic and we're manipulating,
then this statement
is equivalent to
that statement when
Tommy contraposition.
When we do what we're doing now,
this is an argument at
the national level.
It's an argument about
rules, about propositions.
Rules about propositions.
Propositions,
there's something at
a higher level will
come back to that.
But this is your first
example of really
seeing an object level thing,
country contraposition on
either side of the turnstile.
And the mezzo level thing,
contraposition on either
side of the influence line.
Now you should hope the video,
take a break, do the
exercise, and then come back.