So these are Aristotle's
categorical propositions
as the all ISP,
where we say there
is nothing that is
a and not p grave
it is not really.
So there's nothing like that.
In other words, all a is b.
Here. We say there's nothing
that's both a and B.
That means no a is B,
which is the same as
every egg is not b.
This is the negation of that.
Because saying there's
nothing in here to say that's
not true is to say there
is something in here.
This is the negation of this to
say there's nothing in
here and there's
something in here.
So these are some a is b and
this is sum a is not re,
just by the way, we made them.
The things diagonally opposite
our contradictions of each other.
So this is every area
is B and this is
that does not hold.
It's not the case that every ISP,
this is every eye is not B,
and this is that does
not hold some ISP.
Could you find a way of saying
each of those in your language?
But it's not ambiguous.
It's actually quite
hard in English
to find something that says
these simply and precisely
without people saying,
well, what does that really mean?
And if you put it inside
another sentence,
It might be taken differently.
Try doing that in your language.
You say you've got it straight.