And now we're going to
look at how we can use
the Venn Diagrams to
show some syllogisms,
but include these
things his a syllogism.
We're going to try and prove.
We're going to try
and prove this one.
Here. This is every baby
is not C. So that means
here's b and c up here.
And to say, every day is not c,
is to say there are now obese RC.
So no B and C means
that bit is empty.
Every city is not a is false.
That means that some say is a.
So that means this
one is inhabited.
If I put those together,
then I put the green in here,
those two, but now I
put the gray in here.
Now why have I drawn
it that way rather
than leaving that
middle bit green?
Why have I chosen Detroit
where trust in Detroit.
We know two facts.
We know that this pits empty.
And we know that this
bit's got something in it.
If we know that
something's empty,
and we divided into two parts,
we know both parts are empty.
But now we're going to
think about what happens if
we know that this pit
empty and that bit's
got something any,
what's it? Tell us?
The thing that's in
here can't be in the
top half of here,
so it must be in the bottom half.
If you think about
it and you were
doing it with apples and
oranges or something,
it will be perfectly obvious.
But by the time you've taken
a new turn it into
symbols plus c,
what we now do is to
say this is inhabited.
What I'm trying to show is
that this plate is inhabited,
which you see this
works completely
differently from being empty.
If we say something is empty
and every part of it is empty.
If we want to show that
something is inhabited,
it's sufficient to show
that one piece of it is
inhabited because that means
there is something in here.
We don't know where it
is, but it's in here.
So this is a valid syllogism.
Syllogisms don't have to
correspond with the world.
First of all, as a supposition,
no mathematician is infallible.
Some programmers
and mathematicians,
so some programmers are fallible,
fallible and infallible are
negations of each other.
So in natural language we
don't always have the not.
So that's what you get for
being a mathematician.
You, you get the fallibility
of mathematicians.
But of course, from being
a mathematician and a programmer,
you also get some good things
like you can make little proofs
like this and they'll
actually help you write
correct programs.
Now here's an example
for you to look
at all plants, fungi,
some flowers and plants,
therefore, some
flowers or not fungi.
The question for you is,
is this a valid argument?
But I want you to do is
give it as a syllogism.
Then use Venn diagrams
to either show it's
valid or produce
a counterexample.
So first of all,
I would like you
to use for plants,
fungi, and see for flowers.
And then try and do this and
see whether it is a
correct argument.
Now you should hope the video,
take a break, do the
exercise, and then come back.