It's often helpful in situations
like an exam setting
where you can't just
pointed the Board appointed
the region to use
these codes to talk about
regions of the Venn diagram.
These correspond to
the binary codes
we get by putting a, B, C,
a 0 or one,
and taking this as a
three-digit binary number,
or three bit binary number.
So 0 is 000 where
no things are true.
Seven is 111 where
everything is true.
And one for instance,
is 001, where c is true.
For is 1-0-0, where a is true,
you can work out the rest
of them for yourself.
Now we're going to use
these. Another example.
Here's our example.
B, C sum C is a.
Therefore, some a is not be no B,
C. What does that mean?
No, VC every B is not.
See, here's the brown one.
Every day he's not say.
So 37 are empty.
Everyone agree? Right? Some CSA.
Sum C is a,
so something in the blue is in a,
at least one of several m5
is inhabited, but we
don't know which one.
Here. We want to show that
the conclusion is valid.
So we've got both 37 are empty.
At least one of 75 is inhabited.
One of 75 is inhabited.
37 are empty.
What can we deduce from that?
Five is inhabited.
And five is inhabited
means that at least
145 is inhabited,
which is what we need
for the conclusion.
When we look at one
of these rules,
what we're trying to
do is to work out,
does it apply in every universe?
So if I give an argument
like this that says,
I know that 37 are empty,
I know that one of
75 is inhabited,
but because seven is empty,
that means five is inhabited.
That tells me that at
least 1045 is inhabited.
That argument shows
that the rule is sized.
Rule is sound if in every model,
when its premises are valid
and its conclusion is valid.
So if we want to
show it's not sound,
we find a model in which
the premises are valid,
but the conclusion isn't valid.
And if you want to find
those counterexamples,
what we just did is
a good way to do it.
You try and make the proof
and then you find now it
doesn't work because I
can put things here,
here and here.
The mean, the proof doesn't work.
Now, I am going to leave
you with the task of using
that method to give a
proof that this example,
which we looked at
earlier is not sound.