Boolean operations.
This tells us how
the operations work.
So we have truth tables
for how the operations
work on the Booleans.
And I just want to say something
about what happens in Haskell.
When we'd look at
the documentation,
it says infix x3 and infix to.
Or what that means is that when I
write false and true or true,
it means one of these
two computations.
Either it means I take
these truths and do the OH,
and then at the end.
Or I take these two due the end,
an entity or in other words,
we either put brackets
here or brackets here.
There are a lot of ideas here
which we will come back to.
The most important idea
is that when I write
something like false
and true or true,
you should never think of it
as just a string of symbols.
You should think of it
as a tree like this
that tells you what to
do with these values,
to put them together,
what to do with this,
and how to put them together.
So that diagram is
what we really want
to think about when we
think about an expression.
And the other thing is, That's
actually a very simple
form of computation.
This is a different
computation from that one.
This one comes out false,
that one comes out true.
So we can use Haskell to
tell us what's going on.
And we can try doing this
without the brackets.
We get true doing it
with the brackets.
One way we get false doing it
with brackets the
other way we get true.
So this is the way that it's red.
I'm going to leave you there.
Thanks very much indeed,
and I will see you tomorrow
at a slightly later era.