Somebody end of the session
yesterday came out
and said, okay,
so that's what you do if
you've got a Venn diagram with
three things and we
understand the syllogisms
there and what's going on.
But what would you
do if you have more?
And the answer is not quite
that you do something
completely different.
That's an important idea
that we're going to keep.
Which is the idea that this
relationship between a and b,
that every a is b
is very important.
But we'll talk about it in ways
that Aristotle didn't manage.
So let's just see what
we've done so far.
Yesterday we got to
these syllogisms.
Here's a nice way
of organizing them.
These ones down the left.
This one comes because we
just look at it and see that it's
true and we check it on
the Venn diagram or
even the Euler diagram.
This is the substitution.
These are the various
contra, positions down here.
So we get this column
very easily just by
making those contract positions.
In this layout, what I've
done to go from here to
here is exactly the
same as I did to go
from here to here.
Remember we went from here to
here by swapping these two,
negating them compared with that.
And by swapping these two
negating them
compared with there.
I've done the same on each line.
So this time it's more
organized because if
you go down on the left,
we know what we're doing.
We're doing those local
control positions.
And if you come across
column by column,
we're doing exactly the
same in each column,
so it's easier to remember.
And in fact, what you'll
see now is that the names,
these are the traditional
medieval names.
They line up all the ones
beginning with C. Are there,
all the ones beginning with F,
eta, all the ones
beginning with you there.
That's because their names helped
them to remember where
these things came from.
They also use the
code for each of
the four different forms of
categorical proposition.
This is the four forms we've got.
They labeled them
a, E, I, O minds.
We'll label them with something.
They labeled them with
the letters a, E, I, O.
And what Barbara tells us,
because there's three a's.
It means that we've got
three of these in it.
123 A's.
Morocco tells me I have one.
A, that's that 12 of
these, what are they?
They are this 00
fascinating piece
of history as to
how people organize
this kind of stuff
when they didn't have
the kind of algebraic
notation that we're using.
Here are the same syllogisms.
Is time, the variables to change,
to label them with
a standard names.
We have S for the subject and
p for the predicate
of the conclusion,
and N for the middle
variable that
is eliminated from
the assumptions.
So I relabeled the variables
from the previous diagram,
and that is basically the
way they will present them.
They're not in the notation
that they would use.
That was where Aristotle got to.
Basically, it was
where things stayed
until the late 18 hundreds para,
a 150 years ago.
Aristotle certainly
knew about these rules.
He knew about these
forms of deduction.
But he didn't think they were
important to write about
because he was only focused
on the difficult ones.
These everybody knows
if every a is NOT B,
then every p is not a.
He would use it, but he didn't
think he was an important
part of the system.
It was just a fact you
used to prove things
about the system
or even more so he
never bothered saying
this because why would we
say it on no premises?
I can always deduce that
every ASA as the phrase goes,
it goes without saying.
But one of the things you'll
learn in this course,
which is not specific to logic,
is that it's often worth writing
down the things that
go without saying.
So it's worth considering
what do I mean when
I say every ISP,
when there are now a,
what do I mean when
I say sum a is B?
What do I mean when I say
one of these things is true,
or every one of these
things is true.
What happens if
there's nothing there?
So we need to think about
those things because it makes
the rules more general
and easier to use.
We were able to get
these very easy rules
when you do the tutorial.
Next week, you will see
that Aristotle also had
this existence assumption
that lead to further rules.
We can still get those,
but they make the system
more complicated.
There's a simplicity in doing
it where you do it cleanly.
So that's what we're
always trying to do.