Here we have a and not a.
And they look quite
different on the diagram.
But really, when we
do it algebraically,
not a is just
another proposition.
How can we picture it?
So that we take
away the fact that
the diagram makes it
look as though there's
something special
about naught a and a.
And the idea is, if
we do it on a plane,
we put a here and then
there's everything else.
Where could we do it where
that wouldn't happen?
Just think of the
surface of a sphere.
If we say a is in
the northern hemisphere and
not a is in the
Southern Hemisphere.
There's nothing special
about North and South.
We can look at it both ways and
it looks exactly the same.
If we take a circle,
not a great circle just to
circle around the globe is b.
So we're saying the thing is that
this side of that circle P is
true and the things that
this side of that
circle P is false.
This circle, the things that
this side of that
circle a is true,
things this side is false.
So what happens if
we now look at this?
Here's a picture.
Or I'm asking you,
is every AB or is every B a?
Here we have the circle
for a and things on
this side a true.
Here we have the circle for B.
And the things on
this side, b is true.
Every B is a. But just
by the same token.
If we looked at it the other way.
Now you see that
every not a is not b.
Just by looking the other way.
Sometimes it's helpful
to have pictures like
that enable you to see
relationships between things.
And say that actually
there is no difference
between saying every BSA
or every not a is not
v. It just depends
how we've chosen to
name those predicates.
One of them's called
the pathway and one of
them is called the miners.
But there's no real difference
between them is predicates.
Before we get onto something new.
Aristotle thought that
was very different
because the words he
used to say this,
every B is Nazi or no,
b is c. C said no BC.
He didn't mention Nazi.
And it didn't feel
like it was about
the predicate Nazi
being a different one
from the one above.
He thought he was saying
something different.
So it's good to look
for patterns and
algebra helps us
see those patterns.