Now I want you to
draw in your minds or a piece
of paper in front of you.
One of these tiny Venn diagrams
that just has two predicates,
a and b, and it's a Venn
diagram so they overlap,
they know inside each
other just a and b.
And I want you to think
about what we might
say about a and B.
You can fill in a and b on
a Venn diagram, can't you?
So think of the relationship.
Everything in C. So draw a,
C such that everything
in C is in a and B.
So you've got your IMB.
You're going to introduce
see somewhere such that.
And now it's going to
be an Euler diagram,
not a Venn diagram because
this new one comes in somewhere.
And I want it to be
such that everything in
C is in both a and
B. I hope you've drawn a
diagram, something like that.
So here we have a at the bottom.
As a, there's B.
And I asked you to draw something
that was contained in a and B.
So I hope you drew
something like that.
I should have done this without
putting a picture in the video.
Because I want not only to
train you to draw these pictures,
but also to conjure
up in your mind.
So you think of things like this.
When you are trying to
think about problems,
you actually bring the
pictures in your mind.
And for those of you
who find pictures,
not the best way
of seeing things,
then probably the algebra
works better for you.
So you do the algebra, let's see,
everything in C is in a and b.
It's exactly the same
as saying two things.
Everything in C is in a
and everything in C is NB.
Everyone agree, this
is a good rule for,
and so you see what the game is.
The game is to try and describe
these things with rules.
And if we now do what we did for,
not do it for,
and then we have
this function and
goes from Booleans to booleans
and gives you a Boolean.
Let's truth table is up in
the top left hand corner there.
This is just a description
of what Haskell
does when you take the
and of two booleans.
If it's false, false,
it gives you false.
If it's false, true,
If it's false, true the other
way it gives you false.
But if it's true, true,
it gives you true.
We extend that to a corresponding
function on predicates,
which you know as the function
you see on venn diagrams.
By saying that a and we
introduce another name for
end because it's a function
of a different type.
And we already have
this e1 is of type bool
arrow is Polaris bu.
We want something
that goes from the
predicate on you to
a predicate on you.
So we have to say a
and in this funny way,
be applied to x
because we want to say
what the predicate is,
is I applied to x
and p applied 2x.
When we are talking about the
operations on predicates,
we're always going back to
operations on booleans.
We have a rule, we have a way of
writing it down in Haskell.
We don't need much more.
What I want you to
do now is to take
a couple of minutes to do the
corresponding rule for all,
most of it is that easy?
We can take the o function now we
can define a function that
we'll call Funny or here,
and we'll use the old
function that, that's fine.
But how do we draw
the diagram for all
where with the blue,
red, blue circle P,
Start with a Venn diagram.
And then you will turn it into
an Euler diagram by
adding the circle.
And what's the rule look like,
which is even more interesting.
So we'll do the same again,
start with the same Venn
Diagram that we started with.
But now may the Euler diagram
where you say something
about the relationship between
your new thing and a or B.
And I have 0B is of
course the union.
And try and write down a rule.
Because what we will see over
the next few lectures
is that once we get
these rolls right,
we really understood everything
about these operations.
So your task now is to draw
a C such that everything in a or
B is contained in C. And use that
to write a rule for
all will give the answer
in the next video.