We're going to change
the subject now to do
something that's no longer
back in Aristotle's time.
But that it is due to blow,
who lived in the 19th
century of an American PS,
who's very little known in
the UK because he's American,
but actually did an
awful lot to sort out
those ideas and make them
much clearer and
easier to deal with.
Then Jensen, who worked on
the rules that we will
be looking at today.
Jensen, change the way
we write these rules.
We started with the idea
every a is B just means
a is contained in B.
Sometimes we wrote
a comma b satisfy
C. And that means if
a and B then C here,
let's look at a little inference.
C satisfies IOP, then no,
AOB satisfies Nazi,
that's contraposition.
Then if we know de Morgan,
we say, this is the same as that.
But then that's the same
as having these two
separately because the comma
on the left just
counts as an end.
Because we interpret
this as saying,
if this is true and this
is true, then that's true.
If I have this.
And for a moment, I
changed the rules and say,
instead of doing
a contraposition,
that just lets me move one thing
across and one thing back.
I'll move both of these
across and change their sign.
And I'll move this one
back and change its sign.
That I get two
things on the right.
And what do those two
things on the right mean?
Well, if we look here,
it means a calmer on the
right corresponds to an OR.
It's the game we'll play will
make sequence they're called,
which are just like our
normal satisfaction,
except we can have
a finite number
of things on the left and
a finite number of things on
the right and on the left.
When we write the calmer,
you think of it as end.
And on the right
you think of it is,
or what the sequence says is,
if all the things on
the left are true,
then at least one of the
things on the right is true.