Let's look at the
rules we've got.
We're going to take these
rules and make use of them.
We have those roles
that we had here,
which are just the rules
we've already played with.
But now we're going to
play a different game.
We're going to say we have a
sequent, which is satisfied.
If whenever everything
on the left is true,
then something on
the right is true.
Okay? So we're thinking still
of predicates that are
about individuals.
And if any individual has
all of these properties,
that it has at least one
of these properties.
And that's a picture of Gensler.
Again, since a very sad case,
he joined the Nazis at
the end of the war.
He was in a prisoner camp.
I'm with maltreated
enough so that he
died of starvation,
which is a pity.
I mean, it's a pretty
joined the Nazis.
It's pretty terrible
story sequence.
Or whenever every
antecedent holds,
some succeed and holes.
If we want to write
that in Haskell,
and we will at some stage,
we have to do it like this.
I'm not going to go through this
now I leave you to
ponder over that.
It says for every thing,
so that's and X from things.
If everything gamma G is true,
so that's the end Over
the Gs from gamma.
Then something in delta is true.
That's an or of the D's in delta.
Gamma corresponds to
the capital G in Greek,
and that's a delta
corresponding to a
D. And it's just
traditional to use
those for these things.
Writing it in symbols that
satisfaction is defined in
terms of one with
just one predicate.
I can take the end of
all the things in gamma.
That's a single predicate as
sets, that's just intersection.
And this is the or of
all the things delta.
That's again a predicate,
which is the union as the
sets we started with,
All a is B,
which means that the gray part of
that Venn diagram is empty.
What does it mean?
If I say G comma a satisfies B.
And instead of drawing
another circle,
which would divide University
to provide it with
a straight line.
The places where G is true
above that green line,
and the places where G is
false below that green line,
we're reaching j
comma a is G and a.
But I want you to
think we've done
slightly differently if
I take any universe.
So I've got a
collection of things
and I have some
properties on them.
And then I throw some
of the things away.
I've still got the properties on
the things that I
haven't thrown away.
So I can always take a
sub universe and that's
a perfectly good Universe
to be working in.
So what happens here is that
this is valid in
this whole universe.
If this is valid in the parts of
the universe that satisfies
g. In other words,
this area which is G
and a colored grey.
And we don't care what
happens out here.
Once we have this G here,
we're only interested in
what goes on in here.
So we can interpret this
as just saying, oh, well,
it really means this is valid
in a smaller universe.
Namely that one.
The same happens if we
take lots of things.
I can replace gamma.
By the end of all
the things in gamma.
I made the diagram look the same.
Of course, if there's more
things that you might
have got smaller, you
couldn't have got bigger.
This is the things that
satisfy everything in gamma.
Gamma comma a satisfies
B is valid in you.
That's this big universe.
If this thing we originally
started with Aristotle.
If every a is b inside
the collection of things
that satisfy everything in gamma,
this is the universe
of those things which
every G in gamma is true.
So actually when we
write the chromosomal f,
instead of thinking It
says this and this,
we can always think of it in
some small universe where
these things are true,
focused on one thing
we're working on the a.
So we can think in a
smaller universe where
all of these are
true. I satisfies B.