Now we have these rules,
and these rules are
valid in any universe.
Fluid, in some universe,
I add gammas and deltas,
basically everywhere, the
same gamma everywhere on
the left and the same delta
everywhere on the right.
If I put a gamma here,
gamma here, a delta there,
and a delta there,
that I'm saying that that
rule that is only there in
black is valid in the universe
where everything in
gamma is true and
everything in delta is false,
that's another universe.
And this rule is valid
in all universes.
So that's certainly the case.
So if I have any one of
my rules that we've
already written
down and I decorate it
with these extra
gammas and deltas.
I'm really not saying
anything different.
I'm just saying in
these particular
places that rule holds.
So these roles are valid
because now this is saying
that if this holds
in that universe,
of that part of the
universe where every gamma
is true and everything
and delta is false,
then this happens in that
part of the universe.
So I put the gammas
and deltas here.
If we write the rules without
the gammas and deltas,
provided they sound, we can add
the gammas and deltas
and they still sound.
So we add them. This is
the form in which you
will normally see
these rules learned to love
them to the end or all
rules which are here.
I've added one which
is the immediate rule.
I normally draw that with
a single line on top.
That doesn't mean it
doesn't go both ways.
It just means that actually you
don't need anything
on top to come down.
This rule says, it is
always the case if a
occurs on both sides.
Remember, the sequence is valid.
If when I make
everything here true,
then I make something here true.
If I make everything here true,
I make a true and a is here.
So I've made something
that troops.
So that's, that's
trivially it's immediate.
That's the eye. It's
an immediate rule.
We just write it down.
And if we ever want to know why
that's true or say,
why is that true?
We put a line with nothing
above it to say it's
true because from
nothing I can get that.
Whereas these rules, if I
have this valid somewhere,
then I have this and vice versa.
That's what the
double line means.
We never need to use this one
backward because it would say,
if I know the I satisfies a,
then I would know that true.
Well, that's a bit useless.
Whereas here it says,
if I know that gamma
satisfies a and B or Delta,
and think of that
cameras and all.
Then I know that,
and I know this,
and I know that.
So these rules say
if everything above
the line is valid
in some universe than
in the same universe,
the thing below
the line is valid.
The other thing is, these
are formerly finite sets.
So really, I should write this as
the set delta together with
the singleton a and B.
But if we get too many
brackets all over
the place and it's
much easier just to
know that assets in our head.
So it doesn't matter what order
we write things in and it
doesn't matter how many
times I duplicate something,
but I'll write them
just as lists.
Commerce, I got a negation
rule down the bottom.
The assumption says, if
everything gamma is true,
then either a is
true or something
adultery is true
because something
in this list altogether,
this is set on the right
altogether is true.
So either it's a or it's
something that's in delta.
This says, if I've made a
false and I know gamma,
then I know something
intelligible.
If I've made a false
and I know gamma,
then it can't be a, That's true.
So it must be something in delta.
That's how that rule works.