In this video, we're
going to continue looking
at syllogisms using
Venn diagrams.
At the end of the last video,
we introduced two Venn diagrams.
And I left you with
the following problem.
These Venn diagrams represent
statements about the universe.
So this one represents
the statement that there
are no things of this
type in this gray area.
That is, that every a is b.
In other words, anything
that's in a cannot be here,
so must be in B.
Then for every a is b,
this diagram represents
the fact that there are
no things that both
a and c. That is,
everything that is in a cannot
be in C. Every EI is not.
See. What I asked you
to do last time was
to convert those
into Euler diagrams.
Here are the Venn diagrams again,
every ISP and no a is c. Here.
We translate this by saying
that a is contained in B.
But apart from that, the
relationship between C and
the others is not specified here.
We've missed out here to
regions of the Venn diagram
which are not inhabited.
There are eight
regions altogether.
So we should find six
regions represented here,
and we'll just do this
as a sanity check.
There's 123456 regions
down here. Every ISP.
And this represented
here, though,
actually the Euler diagram
doesn't really represent
all the possibilities.
Because the Euler diagram
means that there is
something in here and there
is something in here,
and there is something
in here, and so on.
So it says that in our universe
there are at least six
things that are different.
Whereas the Venn
Diagram we interpret
as saying there may be
something in here or not.
We don't know. There may be
We don't know, and so on.
We do know that there's nothing
in either of these areas.
So the Venn diagram,
let's us say less,
which is important because then
there are more things we can say.
We can say this much
without committing
ourselves to the
fact that therefore
there must be something
in each of these.
Whereas with the Euler diagram,
you make that commitment.
If we do the same thing with
the other diagram here,
then we're missing out these two.
Again, we should
find six regions,
and if we count them, it's
easy to make a mistake.
Humans I, one.
2345, there are five regions,
but if you counted
carefully, you get 123456.
If you are doing
an Euler diagram,
you represent all
the possibilities.
But as I say, if we interpret
this strictly is
an Euler diagram,
then it saying that
there are six things,
one in each of these regions.
And that's not what we want
to say with a Venn diagram.
Now I want you to try
an exercise in the
opposite direction.
Given an Euler diagram,
can you derive a Venn diagram?
So what is the venn
diagram like for this?
And what is the venn
And all the Euler
diagrams are going
to show that there are
1234 things that are inhabited,
If you consider is annoy diagram,
I want you to mount the
ones that are empty.
The Venn diagram that we then get
will tell us at least
the ones that are
empty and leave us flexibility
about whether there's
anything in the four
regions represented here.
Again, here we have 1234 regions.
So there are four regions which
should be possibly inhabited.
In your Venn diagram.
Pause the video while
you try doing that.
You should get
something like this.
In each of these examples,
we have four regions
that will be inhabited.
So we should have four regions
which will not be inhabited.
And then we can check that
we have the right ones.
This is things in here are in
a and in B and C. So there,
there things in here are
in B and C, but not in a.
So they are in B and
C, but not in a.
Things here are a and C,
but not in a and B.
So that's this region.
And finally, things out
here are in none of them.
That's this region here.
You can do the same
exercise here.
Here are things
that are in a new,
neither being nor
C. So that's here.
Here are things that are
not in any of them here.
Things that are in C,
but not in B or a and C,
but not in B or a.
And things that are in B and C,
but not in a. And that's here.
These Venn diagrams correspond
to these Euler diagrams.
And although for simple
cases like this,
which corresponded to
the Barbera syllogism,
It's easy to see what's going
on when you draw
an Euler diagram.
The Venn diagrams are more
flexible because
they don't commit
us to having these
regions inhabited.
They let us say this
one's not inhabited,
but this May 1 or
may not be later,
we will introduce a notation
to say maybe that some of
these regions of the Venn
diagram are inhabited.
And then we'll be able
to say things that we
can't say with an oil diagram.
We want to say some
things are inhabited,
some things are empty,
and other things.
We leave the question open.
We're going to talk quite
a lot about Venn diagrams.
As we'll see later, that
can get very complicated.
So we're only going to talk
about simple Venn diagrams.
This is the simplest one
with two predicates.
Let's say a is appetizing
and B is beautiful.
Or you could say a is
amber and B is blue.
We can label the areas
by saying this is
the place where a is
true and B is false,
a and not B.
This is something that's
appetizing but not beautiful.
appetizing and beautiful.
This is something that's not
appetizing and it is beautiful.
This is something that is not
appetizing and it's
not beautiful.
So we use these
symbols, negation,
fanout and friend and of
rho will also use
another notation for describing
the regions of a Venn diagram.
We'll often use this for
three predicate Venn diagram.
If we think of the
predicates as a, B,
and C, Then to tweet region,
we associate a binary number.
If it's a region where
all three are false,
then we associate the
number 000 in this region.
And the decimal value of
that, of course, is 0.
If we're in a region
where only a is true,
so true, false, false, 1-0-0.
That's 100 in binary,
which is decimal for.
So I filled in each region
here and you can check those.
Each region corresponds to one of
the eight binary codes
from 0 to seven.
And we will often label
these regions, 0123, 4567.
That's just a useful notation
if we want to refer to things
when we are writing
and we don't have the
opportunity to point.
Venn diagrams get very
complicated very quickly here
our Venn diagrams for
five predicates and
seven predicates.
These ones are very
pretty strange fact,
a Venn diagram that you
can rotate and it falls on
itself so it hasn't rotational
symmetry is possible.
The n predicates if and
only if n is prime.
So there's something quite
deep going on there,
but we're not going
to explore that.
What we're going to do is
to stick with the
somewhat you should
get from this particular video.
Is this coding used to refer
to the regions of the three
predicate Venn diagram.
And these two examples,
every ASB and variations on them,
you should be able to work out
how to color in a Venn diagram.
So every CSP or every B, a,
C. And now ASE.
Similarly, you should
be able to say,
now C is a,
nd actually has the same diagram.
You should be able to say no PUC
and now ASB and things like that.
We use these notations
that says every a is b.
And now we come to a subtle,
nah, not really subtle, a simple.
Now we come to a simple
but important point.
We've introduced the notation a
satisfies B to say
that every a is b.
And now here we introduce
some different statement which is
no a is c. That
says that every a is not c. So
this notation shows us
a similarity or relationship
between these two.
That's not so obvious here.
All we've done is to talk
about not saying in
a place of pain.
And that's very powerful to have
the algebraic
notation that lets us
say this is actually a statement
that is very similar to
this statement here.
It just is talking about
a different predicate
instead of talking about
it, talking about Nazi.
That's all for this video,
you should make
sure that you can.
If you want to try
an exercise to test
your understanding
of the shadings,
maybe you could try shading in
a few examples on the five
predicate Venn diagram,
but we won't be doing that.
We'll be sticking entirely to
Venn diagrams with 23 predicates.
And what we want to go for
predicates will introduce
yet another notation,
which is simpler than
the Venn diagrams and
has advantages over
them in the same way,
the Venn diagrams have
an advantage of the
Euler diagrams.