In this video, we start on
the main preoccupation
of logic deduction.
The ways in which we
can derive console.
We can derive consequences
from assumptions.
We assume that some
things are true.
And then by logical reasoning,
we derive conclusions.
This goes back to Aristotle,
and we're going to
start this course with
a Valley quake introduction
to Aristotelian syllogisms.
We'll use them to
introduce some of
the notation that we'll use
in a broader setting
of modern logic.
And the basic ideas of
the relationship between
models and reality will
start using simple diagrams,
known as Euler diagrams.
But surely diagram is like this,
were drawn long
before Euler error.
A couple of Euler diagrams.
This one shows a
universe of things.
And then three collections
or subsets of things.
Didn't that? And in
this first example,
a is contained in B,
is contained in C. A
very simple arrangement.
We think of these subsets is
corresponding to properties.
So the things inside this circle,
other things with the property a,
is inside this circle with
the property P and
this circle with
the property C. And when
we say a property a,
we mean that for each
individual in the universe,
we can tell whether it has
the property a or not.
So we say a hold of that
individual is true,
or a hold of that
individual is false.
Here's a different configuration
of properties in a universe.
In this case, a,
having the property a means you
don't have the
properties brilliancy.
It's still the case that
the bees are contained
in the seas.
What Aristotle did was
to codify these kinds of
relationships and will count
some rules of inference
between them.
That's the introduction
of deduction.
And the very first example,
which is probably familiar to you
already is this syllogism.
Socrates is a man.
All men are mortal.
Therefore Socrates is mortal.
That corresponds to this pattern.
If we say a is the property
of being Socrates,
B is the property of being a man,
and C is the property
of being mortal.
Socrates is a man,
represents the statement
that a is contained in B.
All men are mortal is
the statement that v
is contained in C,
and obviously a is contained
in C. Socrates is mortal.
You may want to think about
what kinds of properties are
represented here
and what kinds of
deductions you might
make between them.
We're going to introduce
some mathematical notation for
talking about these things.
Because doing it in
natural language
becomes quite involved.
We want to make it much easier.
And using modern
mathematical notations and
some algebra will
allow us to do things.
Easily that were quite
hard even for Aristotle.
First of all, we have
this mathematical notation for
subsets of the individuals.
So this is the set of x
such that x is Socrates.
That represents the things
with the property being Socrates.
This is the set of x
such that x is a man.
The set of man is a subset
of our universe of objects.
This set is contained
in this set.
The set of things which a man is
contained in the set of
things which are motile.
And we conclude, because this
set is contained in this,
this is contained in this,
and it's a property of sets
that containment is transitive.
That means the set of things that
Socrates is contained in,
the set of things
that are mortal.
We're going to try and
represent everything uniformly.
So this says the set of x
such that x equals Socrates.
That says the set of x such
that is a man is true of x.
We want to be able to put
everything in this form
where these things are
called predicates.
Predicates are functions that
given an element of the universe,
gave us a truth
value, true or false.
So rather than writing
this as x equals Socrates,
we want to write it as,
is Socrates x.
Where is Socrates?
Is the property of
an x that is true
if x happens to be
Socrates and is false.
Otherwise. When we come
to do things in Haskell,
it will be very important
to do this kind of
trick to make everything
of the same type.
So these predicates,
these functions from
things to Booleans,
will be our basic way of
representing
properties in Haskell.
If we now look at this
pattern of inference,
we have everything that
is Socrates is a man.
Everything that is
a man is immortal.
Therefore, everything that
is Socrates is mortal.
And we abstract from
that and say for
any properties a, B, and C,
which have this form, that is,
every a is b and every B
is C, satisfy this role.
That then every ASE.
And that's again just
this containment and
that obvious fact that
we're trying to unpick.
So we can generalize to
other forms of argument.
We're not going to use
Euler diagrams when we
generalize to other examples,
it's easier to use Venn diagrams.
The Venn diagram looks
quite like an oil.
A diagram with an
important difference.
This Venn diagram represents
three properties.
Let's call them a, B,
and C. And all
possible relations between
them in the sense of terror.
Eight regions here.
And each region represents
a combination of
those properties.
The things out here satisfy
No, the properties.
These things satisfy
only a, these only B,
and these only see these a and B,
B and C and a and C. And
they satisfy all three,
a and B and C. And
rather than represent
the world by not drawing
regions which are empty,
we're going to use
Venn diagrams and use
this shading to indicate
that the region is empty.
So in this Venn diagram,
I've said that this region,
the places where a is true,
but B is not true.
This region is empty.
That says there are no things
where a is true
and B is not true.
Which is the same as saying
everything which
does have a is here.
Which means everything
in a is in B.
So this is another way of
representing our every ASP.
If we look at this example, here,
we've colored the region where
a is true and C is true.
So there's nothing
such that both a
and c. That means the,
as soon as we know
something's in a,
we know it's not in c,
because if it were, it
would lie in this region.
And we've decided that is empty.
So this represents nothing in a,
is in C, no AC.
And we now go back to
our universe of
disks and triangles.
We looked at these statements.
And you recall, when we looked at
every red triangle is small.
We decided that that was true
because this region is empty.
And what we're going to
do is to use this in
the context of general
Venn diagrams.
In order to reason
about syllogisms.
Will take these Venn
diagrams and think of
the individuals are sitting
in the various regions.
This is every a is b,
and this is no a is B.
You can write the
corresponding Euler diagrams
for these two Venn diagrams.
Pause the video, take
a moment to work out
the Euler diagrams
that correspond to
these two Venn
diagrams. Unthinkable.