Now we're ready to work
through our first example of
a syllogism using Venn diagrams.
Socrates is a man.
All men are mortal.
Therefore Socrates is mortal.
That's just an instance
of this general pattern.
If all ILP and all
PAC than all IRC,
we're going to use Venn
diagrams to represent that.
The first thing is to
understand what it means on
a Venn Diagram to say
that all a are B.
Where we've seen this too
predicate Venn diagram before.
If every a is b,
and we use this notation
to say that every ASB,
so all ARP is a turnstile B.
If every a is b,
it's the same as saying,
no a is not B.
That's the same as saying
that the region in
the Venn diagram
where I would put anything
which is a but not B is empty.
No individual is a and not B.
This region of the
Venn diagram is empty.
If we now want to show that
our syllogism is sound,
we assume that in the
diagram for a and b,
this region is empty.
In the diagram for B and C,
This region is empty.
We have to argue that
if that's empty and
that's empty than in the
diagram for a and C,
This region is empty.
In order to do that, we'll
rearrange our diagrams
a little bit.
We want to take the information
here and the information here,
combine it to conclude
that that is empty.
So this is empty, this is empty.
We want to combine
those two facts
to show that this is empty.
What we do is to take
the two binary Venn
diagrams and overlay them.
Now I'm making use of the codes
that I had before to label
the eight regions of this
three element Venn diagram.
In a three element Venn diagram,
we have 0 to seven is
eight possibilities.
And the venn diagram
represents the mole.
The hypothesis that this
region is empty says
the regions 45 of the three
predicate diagram or empty.
The hypothesis that this region
is empty tells us that
regions 26 are empty.
So we know that 45 are
empty and 26 are empty.
But this region
corresponds to 46.
So four is empty because this one
was six is empty
because this one was,
the union of 46 is empty.
That's our first syllogism.
Its name is Barbara,
and the reason for the
name will come to later.
We say this rule is sound.
What does it mean to
say a rule is sound?
It says for any predicates a, b,
and c in any universe.
If the premises are
valid in that universe,
then the conclusion is
valid in that universe.
To recap, we represent
the fact that
every ASB by saying that
this region x is empty,
every B is C tells us
this region why is empty.
And then basically we infer
that zed is empty because
z is contained in the
union of X and Y.
Our syllogism in
Barbara is sound.