We're going to look at
other forms of syllogism,
other forms of proposition.
For instance, the syllogism,
all snakes are reptiles.
No reptile has, therefore
no snake has for isn't.
In the Barbara form.
We'll formalize it
and we will see
later that this is
how it will look.
But before we can do that,
we've got to understand how do we
say no snake has for what does
that proposition look
like and how does it
relate to propositions
like every ASB?
All of Aristotle's propositions
relate to predicates.
The simplest kind
which you've already
seen is called
universal affirmation.
A corresponds to every
a is B, or all a are B.
And the examples we've seen
are all men are mortal.
Socrates is a man where
we created a predicate,
which was being Socrates,
to allow us to put
that in the form of
a proposition, a
universal affirmation.
We introduce this symbol.
And we introduced
the representation
of this in the Venn
diagram by saying
that the area that will be
inhabited by things that
are a and not B is empty.
The proposition all a is B
is valid in whatever
universe we're looking at.
If there's no counterexample,
this region is empty,
we use this notation.
A satisfies B and it
corresponds to saying
the set of x such
that a of x is contained
in the set of x such that p of x.
We're now going to look at
another region and say
that this is empty.
So the proposition here
says that no a is B.
A counter-example
to that would be
an example where some a is B.
So if this region,
things that are both a and
B is empty, then no ASB.
That's the same as saying
that every a is not b.
So in our notation,
we say every a is NOT B
in English is more natural
sometimes to say no a is B.
We now have two forms
of proposition.
We have the original
universal affirmation.
Every a is b,
which says that this region
of the Venn diagram is
empty and we have
universal denial.
Every a is not B or no ASB,
which says that this
region is empty.