No a is B is exactly the same
as no B is a on an Euler diagram,
no a is B is represented
by two disjoint circles.
And of course, whether we look at
a first Toby First is
destroyed that disjoint.
We're going to look
at more examples
of that kind of relationship now.
So we're looking at
negation of predicates.
And if we look at some Venn
diagrams on this top row,
various regions being empty.
And then look at the mirror image
of each of those diagrams.
So here we have a on the
left and be on the right.
But here we have B on the
left and a on the right.
So if we swap a and b here,
we arrive at a diagram that looks
exactly the same
as we had before.
This tells us that
if every a is not b,
it's the same as saying
every B is not a or
no a is b is the same
as saying no B is a.
This example is a little
more difficult to translate.
But if we swap these,
then we put a over here.
We have a here,
we move it to the other side.
Then this says all
A's BY every a is B.
So that says if I
have something in a,
it must be in B because
this bit is empty,
it can't be that.
This says if we
start with p here,
if I have something and
not be in other words,
outside B, then it can't be here.
I have something not
in B, which is this.
And it's definitely not in a.
So every not b is not a.
So no not b is a.
Here I have the third possibility
of a kind of region
that can be excluded.
We exclude these.
It says anything that's
not in a must be in be.
It can't be outside be.
That's exactly the same as
saying everything that's not in
B is in a or not a is b is
the same as all not b is a.
If we look at each
of these examples,
we can swap the sides of the two.
And as we swap the sides,
we add an negation
or take one away.
Taking negation away really
is the same as adding one.
Because if I take a
and then negate it,
and then negate it again,
I get back to way.
So in these relationships we
can say when we swap them,
we add an negation.
And if that gives us
a double negation,
not, not is something
we can ignore.
This is the first rule
of Boolean algebra.
Here we have an
operation not a and not,
not a equals a, just
like arithmetic,
where we have an operation minus,
which takes the negative
of a number and
minus minus a is equal to a.
So negation behaves in the
same way as the minus sign for
number is the first rule
of Boolean algebra,
but it's really the second
rule of Boolean logic.
The first rule of Boolean logic
is our syllogism Barbara.
We've written a to these roles
with the double horizontal line.
That means that the rules were
purged from top to bottom.
If every a is B,
then every not b is not a.
But they also work
from bottom to top.
If every not b is not a,
then every a is B.
Because if we just
had this single rule,
then once we know that not,
not a is the same as any,
we can get the data rule.
We can say apply
the single rule to
every ISP to get not
b is not a fine.
But if I now apply the
single rule again,
then I get every not,
not a is not not B,
but then I replace
these double negations.
Nothing. So I can go from
here to here using
the double negation.
So from this one rule we
can derive both ways.
Are algebraic. Notation
makes it much easier for us
to do some of these things
than it was for Aristotle.
Aristotle just talking
about negation,
not says to every
affirmation neck
corresponds exactly
one denial such that,
that denial denies exactly
what the affirmation of firms.
It's getting quite convoluted.
And thinking these
things through without
the algebraic notation
can be quite difficult.
And we'll see you in
our next syllogism
that the algebra really
does give us for
free somethings that
perplexed logicians over
millennia between the times of
Aristotle and van to recap,
where are we now?
We have predicates a and B.
Predicates are functions,
but they can also
be viewed as sets.
And when we draw
the Venn diagrams,
we're representing them
as pictures of sets.
We have this relation,
every a satisfies B,
which is a relation
between predicates.
We've introduced negation.
A predicates a function.
I can take a predicate
a and apply it to x
to get a truth value.
I can say not of
that truth value,
not false is true or
not of true is false.
So the negation of a as a
predicate when applied to x,
takes the truth value
of a applied to
X and then negates that
applies not to it.
And not, not a is the same as a.
We have our rule,
Barbara, which is like this.
And just a slight look ahead.
That means we have
a rule like this
because if for every predicate,
we have a predicate
which is called Not a,
then if this rule works
for any predicate,
it works not only for
C But for not see.
The other thing we have is
these contour positions.
Anywhere where I have a satisfies
not B. I can replace it
by b satisfies not a
without changing the
validity of the proposition.
Similarly, wherever I
have a satisfies B,
I have not B satisfies
no day wherever I
have nodejs satisfies
B, I have not.
B satisfies a.
So this is contraposition.