In an earlier video,
we ended with the remark that
this syllogism is really
just an instance of Barbara,
where I put Nazi instead
of the sea in Barbara.
But since Barbara works
for any predicate,
it works for the predicate Nazi,
just as well as for
the predicate si.
Here's an example
of that syllogism.
All snakes are reptiles.
No reptile has for no snake has.
We've taken our
syllogism Barbara,
since it works for
any predicates ABC,
it works for a, b,
and not c. So this rule
must also be sound.
If I look at it on
an oil a diagram.
Then this says that
if a is contained in
B and B is disjoint from C,
then a is disjoint
from C. We can see
that intuitively obvious with
our geometric intuition,
but it looks like quite
a different observation
than the one about
a contained in B,
contained in C. It's a
different kind of thought.
When we represent it
with the Venn diagrams,
the derivation is very
similar to the one
we gave for Barbara.
If every a is b and
every B is Nazi,
than every a is Nazi.
Rephrasing that we
have if every a is
b and no BSC and no ASE.
And the example, all
snakes are reptiles,
no reptiles have
no snakes heifer.
In terms of the Euler diagrams,
all a's b looks like this.
This region in the
Venn diagram is empty,
and no a is B, looks like this.
And this region in the
Venn diagram is empty.
If we now try and
prove this by putting
those together in the
way we did for Barbara.
We take this Venn
diagram for all a's b.
This Venn diagram for no BSC,
with these regions x
and y being empty,
we can put them together in
a three predicate Venn diagram
to know that all of
these parts are empty.
And we wanted to
show that no a is c,
that simply to show that
this region Zed is empty,
but just as we did before,
Zed is contained in X union Y,
Zed is contained
here in X union Y.
So we can give that kind of
derivation problem,
the Euler diagram.
It's much harder to see.
So far we've seen two syllogisms.
The first one Barbara,
and the second one,
an instance of Barbara.
We saw that we could justify
back inference independently.
We're going to derive many
more syllogisms from Barbara.
From Barbara.
We derive this
syllogism simply by
substituting Nazi for c in here.
Here we're going to see
that with no more work,
we can get three more syllogisms.
We know that no B is C is
equivalent to know CSP.
So we can replace,
in this syllogism,
we replace the no
b is c by no CSB.
That is, we apply contraposition
to this proposition.
That gives us a new syllogism,
which has this swapped over.
We can now swap this over to
give a new syllogism here.
And we can swap
this back again to
give yet another
new syllogism here.
So from this one,
we have derived for
others and we don't
need to check them
with Venn diagrams.
You could as an exercise,
check them with Venn diagrams,
but we don't need to.
Because we've seen that
this is equivalent to this,
and this is equivalent to this.
All of these three syllogisms are
sound simply because this one is,
and this one is simply
because it's an
instance of this one.
Logic is just common
sense in symbolic form.
But it's quite hard to do
these transformations
without symbolic form.
You have to be Aristotle
to have thought of this
in the first place.
But with the algebra
notation we now have,
You can all do at
least as well as
Aristotle in understanding
the syllogisms.
To see what we've achieved.
Take a look at these examples
of our five syllogisms.
If you had to just justify
these arguments without having
done this work at
the symbolic level.
I think you'll find it
much more difficult.