We have a universe
with predicate.
There could be
anything in the world.
They can be as big
as we like today.
We got to realize that
because we have a
restricted language,
we really don't need to talk
about everything in the world.
And in fact, when we have a
propositional logic and we use
some number of
propositional letters
to talk about things.
You know, we have
predicates a, B,
and C, which we could
interpret in the world.
There's one model which
covers everything.
So we actually can
look at one universe,
what goes on in that universe.
And once we understand that,
we understand every other one,
there's a universe which I
showed you at the end of
last time with just
four predicates.
And the only possibilities
for things in this language,
the only things we can talk
about is the differences in
whether they have the
property Ohio town,
whether they have the property
P or don't, and so on.
Which means that there are
only 16 possibilities.
And if we take this principle
saying if things
can't be distinguish,
them will treat them as equal.
Then basically the only
difference between universes for
this language with four letters
is do they have
something of this kind?
Let's say that I have
something that is
a and not B and Nazi and not the,
or do they not have
anything like that?
Instead of considering
all possible universes,
we can just consider universes
that are sub universes
of this one that has
16 different things.
Because if I had any
other universe I
could map it onto
here by saying, well,
I'll just clump all
the things that are a,
not B, not C and D
clump those together.
Interesting, yes,
there is one of them,
or in some other instances
maybe there isn't.
So how many sub universes are
there of that
particular universe?
64. You think?
How many different things we got?
16. So how do we
calculate the answer?
There were 16 things here.
If I take a sub universe,
each one could either
be there or not there.
So how many sub
universes are that?
There are a huge number,
two to the 60 is 64 thousand.
And we're going to focus
mainly on this example.
The ways we deal with it will
generalize to much
bigger examples.
But already here we've
got 64 thousand,
and that's a binary thousand,
which is 10 to four.
So 64 kbps bit or KB Things.
There are 256 universities
that we have three things,
but it goes up to the 64 K
when we have four things.
And as you say, it's
65,536 to be precise,
what we're going to
say is that if we
take this one or
this one and this is
the one we'll look at.
If you're given any one of
the 65 thousand
anode patterns here,
you will be able to write
down a formula that
corresponds to that pattern
and as over 64 thousand.
And yet you'll be
able to do all of
them here just for fun,
are 256 Venn diagrams
with three things.
They just randomly generated.
They do repeat a bit
which ones are missing?
It's really odd already
when you've got three,
I wouldn't even try and
draw the picture of
the 64 thousand
because if we did,
it will be so small
you wouldn't see it.