If we have a language that's
talking about four
different predicates,
then we can make a special model
which is a universal
model for that. Each region
in here corresponds to a
pattern like that which shows
us which of the four things
are true and which are false.
But if we're being
a bit more formal,
we can think of it as a
state which says a not b,
not c and d. Where is this
true in this universe?
How many places is it true?
One. So if I write
a state like this,
then it corresponds to
exactly one of these
and in this case, it's this one.
We'll also think of these
states as valuations,
that is functions.
If we have a function
saying a is true,
b is false, c is
false, d is true.
So that one model and
these two ideas of how
we may represent the regions
here will be very important.
So in this model, if I look at
the state that
satisfies a, not b, not c,
and d. And for those of you
who remember yesterday,
gamma on the left
here is just a set with
four things in it and
they're very simple. And when we
say gamma satisfies p,
what it means is p is satisfied
in the sub-thing of this,
the sub universe in which gamma,
everything in gamma is
true. That sub universe in
this case is the universe
that only has this one thing.
This satisfies p if
and only if p holds
of that one thing.
So we've taken this
general idea we had
before and were able just to say:
oh, we work out p on this one,
and that tells me
whether this is true.
To tell whether this is,
whether it's valid on this one,
we just substitute different
things here and work it out.
But what I want to do now
is to introduce the ways of
taking patterns on these 16
things and identifying them.
Here's a state picture
of the same thing.
Here we're thinking of
something which has a state
represented by four
lights. And they're amber,
green, red, blue. Amber is the name
of the yellow of a
traffic light in Britain.
So if you don't
know what amber is,
go out and look at one
of the traffic lights.
The yellow color on the
traffic light is not yellow,
it's amber. Look in the highway code.
So we're going to treat states
as lights. In this diagram,
it's a perfectly good Venn
diagram in that each region is
represented and no region
is represented twice.
But it's not a very nice diagram
because things aren't
very different.
Like this one is not very
different from this one.
It only differs by one light:
whether the amber
light is on or off.
They're far apart. From this state,
the red and amber: to
switch off amber
we have to go a long way.
Another pattern, a Karnaugh map,
puts things in a different order.
This is a bit of magic.
Now, to change one light,
you just have to move
one square. If you
go from one thing to the next,
we only change one light.
Here, the amber light goes on.
And here the amber light goes on.
The amber light goes on.
Here, the green light goes off.
The green light goes off.
Green light goes off.
What happens if we come down here?
The blue light comes on.
Red light comes on.
Blue light goes off.
Red light goes off. What happens
when the amber light goes off?
When the amber light goes
off, you go from here,
you have to come back here.
So we'll come back to that
and see that picture again.
We won't need it
for a little while.
Here, we've got 'a' as a nice block.
That's places where the
amber light is on.
We've got g as a nice block.
This word 'block' is actually
going to be a technical word.
A 'block' on one of
these diagrams is
one of the rectangles I am
going to be showing you.
And I want you to think about
what's special about these
rectangles we're seeing.
So we'll see a variety of
them and we will come
to the definition,
but I'd like you to
think about what's
special about the
rectangles we're showing
and we haven't shown
sufficient variety
yet for me to ask
you the question.
The reds and the blues are there.
So if we know where amber,
green, red, blue are,
we can work out where not b is.
Not b is the things outside here.
You know, it's a bit like
a Venn diagram except
instead of having the
thing with everything off
sitting out in the cold,
it's rather the same
as everything else:
it's just another
thing in our diagram.
Another way of looking at this
is to take exactly the
diagram we had before,
but now for amber and
green, I'm saying 00,
meaning amber and green are all
off down in this column.
01 means amber is
off and green is on.
Check it in this column.
Here, amber and green are both on. And here,
amber is on but green is off.
Notice the order: I don't go
00-01-10-11 counting in
binary, I go 00-01-11-10.
And that's called a Huffman code.
So it only changes by
one bit when you go from
one place to the next.
And you can do those
with any number of bits.
So if you have a 5-bit number,
You can write something
that does this.
And when we come here,
if we go back to the beginning,
we still only change one bit.
So we use the same
code going down here.
And again, if we come
back to the beginning,
we only change one bit.
But this time, here we're saying
that red and blue are off. Here
we're saying that red is off,
blue is on. Here
we're saying they're both on.
And here we're saying red is
on, but blue is off.
So that does all the possibilities.
Now what we want to do is do
a little bit of logic.