Now we're going to do a little
bit of logic. We're ready.
We call pictures that aside to
remind us what swear
it actually help.
Instead of looking here and
trying to get through
the encoding,
it just helps to
think employers on,
that's what's there.
That means blue zone.
If I say green and blue,
it's the intersection
of these two.
So green and blue eyed ones in
here where green is
true and blue is true.
Here's another block, there's
a block of ones showing me the
green and blue are true
for each of these letters.
This is a block of ones
showing that a is true.
This is a block of peace,
showing that P is true.
Block, block green.
We'd have a block for naught.
A will have a block for Nora.
And we'd have to
think about blocks
for not green and not blue.
We'll come back to
that. If I try.
Not a and B again
get a similar kind of block.
Does everyone get that?
Does everyone see
node a and b naught
a is this side and b,
so we intersect them.
So we get that block,
not a and not r.
So not a is this left hand
side now is this topic.
So not a and not a is
the not B and not.
We see another blow.
Anyone i, any idea what's
special about blocks now?
G and no TAA.
Where we get to this place
where if we're going
to make sense of this,
we've got to think of those
as being next to each other.
For doing that, let's
make a picture.
Here. I've taken
our 16 states and
out here I've got copies
of that same thing.
But we can put them
together like this.
Now, you can't see the edges.
What I've done is to take
multiple copies and just put
them next to each other.
So the rules how along this row,
we've just got reds down here.
What we got, we've
got neither this nor
that down any row
along any column.
We've got something
that's constant.
Namely the, here're
two things around
changing and the
other two can change.
And every time I go
from one to another,
I changed one thing.
So I can change this
nothing to amber or red,
or green or blue.
You can see why you do this in
two dimensions for
four variables.
But if you wanted
to six variables,
you have to go into
three dimensions.
And it's much harder
to see when you've got
a solid cube that's
colored, you go through it.
So some people can do that,
but I'm not gonna do that
with you in this course.