We now have this. Let's
try a few examples.
What I want you to
do is to tell me,
now, here's a block.
What's special about that block?
In other words, can we
describe that block?
Not by describing a state,
but remember which state
we said the values
of all of the predicates.
Now I'm asking you to tell me
what values are common
across these four.
Amber and green for that one.
Yup, Amber and green.
What about this one?
How many things you Usain?
Red and blue and green.
Here we have four
things in the block.
How many things do we expect
them to have in common?
Too good?
And what are the two for days?
Now? Green and red.
So you do this, you
should check that you
can do the same for the
other block shown here.
We'll put the solutions
online. What's a block?
What makes something a block?
What do these have in common?
What happens if I draw this?
What do they have in common?
They know all the
things that are not
read has to be a power of two.
Let's just think about it.
We've got our 16
different states.
When I say read,
I cut the number in half.
If I say not read,
Suppose I say red
and then I say blue.
I not only cut the
number of things
I'm considering in
half by saying blue,
I'm cutting the number of
red things in half as well
because these properties
are independent,
there is no connection
between the properties.
So when you say blue,
for any other thing,
you've counted all the things
that are red and not
green or something,
and you've got them there.
Half of them will be blue
and half of them won't,
because we've represented
everything here.
So every time you
add one of these,
we call them literals.
That is one of
your basic lattice or the
negation of a basic letter,
then you cut the
number of states into.
So we start from 16.
If we say one thing,
either red or not red
or amber or not Amber,
Just one thing carried
down to eight.
If we say two things,
we got it down to four
and we carry it down
to three things.
We cut it down to two.
And actually we have
seen examples already.
We carry it down to four things.
We got a single state.
And that's just
represented by saying
what's true and what's
false in that state.
If we go back to our example,
we were looking at
just this picture
and we were looking
at these being one
and these being one.
And basically if I put the thing
together, this is a block.
It's repeated again because
everything's repeated.
This count says, if you
do that repetition,
if we just fold
everything up, well,
it's difficult to physically,
but you can imagine doing it
physically in one direction.
You just roll it up into a tube,
into a cylinder
that maps around on
itself to wrap it around
the other way you need
something better than paper.
Because if you're going
to make that match up,
you can't do the
cylinder trick again.
Geometry doesn't work like that,
so you have to make it
into a torus this way,
the cylinders being
done that way to make
a row and then it's been
wrapped around into a torus.
So you can put these
things on there.
If you go to Wikipedia,
you will see that that's where
this picture comes from.
This one counts as a block.
And a Kansas not G,
not or a block is
a rectangle of these
things on the torus.
A rectangle whose sides
are some power of two.
So it can be one which
is two to the 0,
or it can be two
or it can be for,
because we don't have
any more room on,
on this thing. That's
what they are.
There's a slightly more tricky
example of the same thing.
If we consider these
four corner things,
which is where we're
not green and blue.
So not green means wherein
these columns not blue
means we're in these rows.
So we end up with these
four corner things.
And that again forms a block
if it's wrapped round.