So far we've been
looking at logs of ones.
What happens if we have
two blocks of ones?
If we have two blocks of 1's,
then if not a and
not our way here.
And if a, and then we're here.
So we have two blocks of 1s,
then we can make
the expression an
expression that represents
exactly this collection of
states by not a anatta
or a and r. Okay?
That's called a disjunctive
because there's a disjunction,
their normal form,
it's a disjunction of
conjunctions of these
things called literals,
which are A's or nowadays as
not as letters or
their negations.
Disjunctive Normal Form,
disjunction of
conjunctions, of literals.
We take a pattern,
here's a pattern.
We find some blocks.
Can anyone see
other blocks that I
haven't labeled blocks of ones?
We could do a
horizontal block here,
and we can do a
horizontal plot there.
Notice that we're keeping
as a power of two,
so it can only be two things,
but there are two
more two-piece blocks
that we could add when we,
when we made the normal form,
each block we've got here will
correspond to are putting,
this says what does this say?
Can anyone work out
what's in common there?
In here, we are in this column,
so we're not a and not
G. And we're on one
of these two rows.
They have in common
the zeros there.
You see? So or not.
So it will be not a,
not g, and not r,
or what would this one be?
Not b, not a and G and B.
Not a and G and B,
because B is the second one of
these and it's true on those two.
And this one a and r,
because we got once
here and once the a
and R. So this is written
them in another order.
And which is that one?
Pay not AIG.
Which one is that? It's this one.
And not a naught R naught
G, because the first one.