So far we've been
looking at logs of ones.
What happens if we
have a block of zeros?
What does that mean?
This, if it were ones,
would be blue and
green cells saying it.
Zara was saying we're not there,
we're outside the places
where Hulu and greener.
So what's not blue and
green by De Morgan?
It's not blue or not green.
Not grain is out here.
Not blue is out there.
And we make these true
if either of those,
that's what the O means.
All the things here and
all the things there.
Instead of intersecting as
we did when we had an end here.
Now we've got an all
the ones go together.
We've already looked at getting
Disjunctive Normal Forms
from blocks, ones.
I'm afraid it's much more
useful to play with the zeros.
So once more you have to get
negation in your head working,
you're getting quite a lot of
practice thinking backwards.
Hopefully, it's getting easier.
If we now focus on the zeros.
Then for this one, the expression
that we're thinking of is
if we're not in here
than either way in here,
which is not nowhere in here,
which is a not ROA.
If we're not in here than
either, we're in this pit,
which is not a over in this pit,
which is R naught a OR a.
Now, if we say
we're outside here,
which means we're either they're
all there and we're outside here,
which means with
arrow that we and
those together to say we're
outside both of them.
And that means that the ones
are represented by this.
This is called a conjunctive
normal form because it is
a conjunction of
disjunction literals.
If we take any pattern
of zeros and ones in
here and then identify
the blocks of zeros.
We can do something like this.
Represent each block of
zeros as a disjunction,
then conjoin all
of those and we'll
have written down something
equivalent to that pattern.
You've already seen
a Disjunctive Normal
Form for this example.
Now we're going to take it,
produce a conjunctive
normal form.
The disjunctive normal form is
easier to think about
and easier to read off.
But the conjunctive normal
form is more useful.
If you think about the
disjunctive normal form,
it says, we've got
some things like this.
And we've got some
things like this.
It just tells you
there are things of
this form because we're saying
this and this and this,
or this and this and this. O, ok.
So in general, you
probably have to
get very deep descriptions
of lots of things
to say that there.
Whereas the conjunctive
normal form says,
we don't have things
like something.
It says we're away from here.
And when we're writing
specifications of programs,
for instance, we don't
say this can happen,
all this can happen
or this can happen.
Typically, we say this will never
happen when you say a small thing
that should never happen,
another small thing that
should never happen.
Things arise more often.
And that our natural way
of describing problem,
but we're going to
talk about Sudoku as
an example of a problem
that we can code in logic.
And now's a good time to
talk about it a little bit.
If we think of a Sudoku
board and you start
filling it in and
suddenly you see that.
Now I'd have to put a nine
here and I've already
got a nine in that row.
I can't do it because you can't
have two nines in the same row.
Ok, so we are saying
that can't happen.
Then we'd say, Oh, you can't
have two weights in the same row.
We want to have the same
things in the same row.
There are lots of little
things that will say.
And what we're trying to do
is to then solve the problem.
Finding something that satisfies
all those requirements
that doesn't
make a 99 in the same row,
so we're not allowed
to do things.
And that's common
in many problems.
We're saying you're not
allowed to do this.
And that means that the
conjunctive normal form
is easier because we're
saying we're not
allowed to do this.
Otherwise, you produce
things other than this,
and you've got to do
things other than that.
And you exclude all
sorts of possibilities.
And then you try and find
something that satisfies
all those constraints.
That's why cnf is more important.