So far we've been
looking at logs of ones.
What happens if we
have a block of zeros?
What does that mean?
This, if it were ones,
would be blue and
green cells saying it.
Zara was saying we're not there,
we're outside the places
where Hulu and greener.
So what's not blue and
green by De Morgan?
It's not blue or green.
Not green is out here.
Not blue is out there.
And we make these true
if either of those,
that's what the O means.
All the things here and
all the things there.
Instead of intersecting as
we did when we had an end here,
now we've got an ore,
so the ones go together.
You've already seen
a Disjunctive Normal
Form for this example.
Now we're going to take it and
produce a conjunctive
normal form.
The disjunctive normal form is
easier to think about
and easier to read off.
Cnf is more important.
So for CNF, we could do
identify blocks of zeros.
People find different
ways of doing this.
The way I normally do it
is I think what would it
be to say that if
I had ones here,
which would be that
I have not a not g
and not a not G
gives me that column and
puts me in these two rows.
And then I need to negate that.
So I say a orgy,
I change the ends to
know a or G or not.
So you have to change
the zeros to positive.
So I say a or G,
That means we are
somewhere in this pit.
Or, and I change
those and it's not us away
somewhere in this pit.
So I've excluded all
of that by my a or
G and all of that by
my half from here.
So I'm saying I'm outside here.
I'm either here or I'm here.
That's the O and M will deal with
the other bits will
say we're not in here.
So what these two got in common,
they certainly both Not a and G,
and they're certainly both not b.
But now we've got to do
our thinking backwards to
our standing on our head.
How would you like to think
about it and say what we say?
We say either a holds
or gee doesn't hold,
or b holds. Try the last one.
Try writing it down for
yourselves and then we'll
see whether you get it
right on the next slide.
Now, there are various notations.
Some paper will have seen things
like this in Engineering before.
So instead of writing
things as we normally write
them in this
mathematical notation,
or we sometimes write
them in Haskell.
Some people use things like this.
They may put bars over
the things domain negations
rather than primes.
There are lots of
ways of doing it.
If you use a different
notation, that's fine,
as long as you are
very clear what
you use and you get it right,
we should be able to
give it mounts for it.
I will normally be
using this notation.
What was this last one?
If we're not in here,
then we're either in
or we're in not a, does
everyone get that?
Given any packing,
you can now do this.
What happens if I
get an isolated?
had a 0 right there?
What would I hadn't
I describe this is
something which is amber,
not green, red, no, blue.
If I want to say I'm not there,
I have to say at least
one of those must fail.
So I'd say not amber or
green or not red or blue.
A block widow, an element
is still a block.
It's a power of two,
and the power of two is
the zeroeth power of two.
You may have many
blocks of size one.
Then if you're doing,
if you're doing clocks of 1s,
than you would have
many disjunct in
your DNF because you'd be
saying either way
here, over here,
over here, or you'd have
a remaining conjuncts in your
cnf if these were zeros,
Let's say we are not here
and not here and not here.
We could do things by
taking very small blocks.
We could always focus down
on single elements and say,
those are the blocks
we're thinking about.
For we get much more writing
down because we'd say,
let's do the disjunctive
when we'd say way here,
over here, over here,
we'd write down lots of
descriptions of State since I,
one of those holes were looking
for compact descriptions.
So we're always looking for
bigger blocks rather
than smaller blocks.
But I do have to be
passive to self.
There are three things in a row,
then you need two blocks up to,
to cover those three things.