So the upshot of this is
we have these stages,
we eliminate that and
eliminate these to get here.
And push in the
negation to get here,
then to this, to get there.
So this is r if and only if
a and g. You've already
seen this slide,
it's easier to get
the same result using a
Karnaugh map. What's more?
The Karnaugh map is a more
general way of doing it,
but you should be
able to do both.
So this is doing the
same for Karnaugh map.
And how have we done this?
So if we're trying to get
an expression like that,
R if and only if something.
And let's say there's some
things in two variables.
I am using a and b.
So if I say a and B,
then that says b is true.
So I mean these two
rows and a is true,
so I mean those two columns.
So this is a and B.
Our divides the world
into two halves.
The hub where R is
false and a half where
R is true in half
where R is true,
then R if and only if a
and b if and only
if a and B is true.
So in the bottom
half of the world,
we just take that piece.
And in the top half of the
world where R is false,
then r is the same as a and G
if and only if we have a 0.
So these ones come there.
What's above the line is
the complement of
what's below the line.
So it's actually
very easy to fill in
these Karnaugh maps for this
particular kind of problem.
And luckily, this particular kind
of problem is
particularly useful.
And we'll see why in a moment.