Here's a DNA. I've
written it in two ways.
I've written it first of all,
without any parentheses because
the and binds more
closely than the or,
it actually means the same as
the expression below that
has the parentheses.
If I take that and
make it into a CNF,
how many clauses will I have
before we had a plus B,
C plus D. We multiply them.
We got four. If we put
two more, we got eight.
How many did we get now?
64. So you can see that,
that gets big very quickly.
Suppose we now do
this circuit trick.
Can anyone tell me
or at least give
an estimate of how many
clauses we need to
describe this circuit
that R if and only if
a and B corresponds to
one of these and gates.
It says, if I take a and b here,
then the signal here is
the end of the signals
here provided.
And then we had, how
many clauses do we have?
We have one clause with
three literals and two
clauses with two literal,
three clauses that describe this.
And actually, you'll
see in a moment that
the OR gate also
takes three clauses.
How many gates we got.
This is a matter of
simple counting.
I'm talking my
instances of gates,
not different kinds of gate,
but how many actual gates on
this circuit everyone
understands, I hope,
the link between the circuit
and the expression we take a
and B that is computed by
that first AND gate here.
And then we all it with
the sandy that's computed
by the second AND gate,
these things associate
to the left.
So this really is a picture
of what the computation
looks like.
It's, take these to
all of them together.
Take this one or this one,
or it will take this
one or this one.
Or if that's exactly what
this expression means,
if you parenthesize it fully.
How many clauses?
Three for each game?
How many clauses? 33.
Yes, that was hard.
This is called the
SAT in procedure.
It doesn't give an
equivalent formula
because it gives a formula which
has more variables in it,
but it's aqueous, satisfiable.
What that means is if I have
a satisfying valuation
for the original formula,
then I have a
satisfying valuation
for the new formula
and vice versa.
And it's easiest
to see that here.
If I have evaluation
that satisfies this.
If I have any inputs here,
I know that because
I have an AND gate,
I get determined outputs here.
When we look forward at the cnf,
will see that the CNF has
a particular form such
that if I set one of
the inputs or if I set
enough of the inputs,
then it determines the output.
And we'll see that that
links into what goes on
in our DP ALL when we
have unit clauses,
any values on the inputs
determine the values on
these internal wires.
Therefore determine the values
on these internal wires,
and therefore
determine the output.
So really, the extra variables
don't give us more choice.
Because once I know
what the inputs are,
the extra variables are
absolutely determined.
And the only question is,
is the output we get at the
end here true? And if it is.
The whole thing is satisfiable.
If it's not, it's not.
So as well as putting
together the causes for this,
causes for this closest,
closest to this, to describe
the behaviour of the circuit,
we also have to say,
and the output is true.
We'll do a simple
example to show you.
But the point is on
simple examples,
this is more complicated
than just doing the
Boolean algebra,
but on any realistically
sized example,
doing the Boolean algebra
leads to this
exponential blow up.
Whereas doing it with
Satan is linear.
There are three
clauses for each gate.
We just take three times
the number of gates,
say the output is true
and that's done it in
a way that's linear.
And the number of gates
that we started with,
which is the number of
connectives in the
expression we started with.
So we start from the expression.
We draw an equivalent
circuit wire for
each subexpression logic gate for
each operator and input
for each variable.
And then we describe
that circuit.
So here we have,
for instance, if and
only if a and b,
which is what we saw before,
and derived both by
Boolean algebra and
by a Karnaugh map.
And if we do if and only if AOB,
it's very similar
except that it's
not everywhere or other,
it's negated everything.
Well, that's just two, Morgan,
you would expect this when
we translate it to all,
to turn to this with
everything negative with
respect to that one,
that basically the same fact
can work them out separately.
So we have those two.
And then I'm going to
say, first of all,
given equation for
this, that's that,
then given equation for
this, that's this one,
x if and only if a and B,
I've got R if and
only if a and b,
I want x if and only
if a and b I just
put x instead of r.
That's very easy.
Substitution there now
will do the other side.
And we'll say, we've
got this one over here.
We got, here, we got OK if and
only if a OP, which is that.
And we formalise this
one as R if and only if
X or C. So the r
stays the same this time
we'll substitute opera,
but we've got a substitute
x for a and C for B.
So if we do that, we'll
get X where we had an
a and see where we had a P
and the r stays the same.
So if I now take this bottom
line and can join those two,
so I have three
clauses for the first,
three clauses for the second guy,
and also say R is true.
So what I'm going to do is
to say what happens if I
take these and I make are true.
It doesn't add an extra clause.
It actually simplifies
these and you know how
to simplify clauses
when you make are true.
That's exactly what we did
when we were writing the PLL.
We simplify the set of clauses
by making some literal true.
This is just using
that knowledge.
Again, if I make are true,
what do I do here?
I just erase the Ya,
so I've got x or c.
If I make are true,
this one is true,
it adds nothing.
This one is true, so
I don't say them.
So this one comes down
here and these two vanish.
That really is exactly the thing
we were doing before
when we were looking at
examples of clauses in
the PLL and saying I
have these clauses,
what happens if I make are true?
If I make are true,
then I can't make not our true.
So I have to make a or C True.
And if I've made are
true, then these
don't say anything
so I can drop them.
So this cnf is satisfiable.
A and B or C went to
gates are connected.
Cns share a variable
when they share a wire,
that variable gives
you the relationship
between this clause
and this clause.
So you see the x occurs
both in, in this part,
which corresponds
to the AND gate,
and in this part which
corresponds to the OR gate,
the wires are just
doing those linkings.
If we now think of doing
the PLL with something
that involves this
and we make a false,
then we make a false here.
That means that not x
becomes a unit clause which
says that I must make X
false and that propagates
through the circuit.
So that's unit clauses
that come up in
the DP ALL serve to propagate
values through the circuit.