Just to go back to
these Karnaugh maps,
this is the one for o.
And just as we did last time,
we can look at the orange
where it's true that
this is where the
ore is true here.
And then they are at
the top and the bottom.
And then we can say,
for the bottom half,
we just copy this and for the
top half we just negated.
So it's very easy
to draw these for
these particular
formulae we want to
use to describe logic gates.
So sorry, this
should be two to the
six and this is 11
times three is 33.
Then we will look at cnf problems
where each clause has
at most two literals.
And for those, you will be
able to buy Han solve them.
So it's something we
can let you practise in
the exam so we'll learn about
that tomorrow. Thank you.