What I want to do
now is to get down
to a piece of nitty-gritty.
Once we have these
formal languages
as things we can
handle and manipulate.
And the best way to understand
what I mean by that
is things we can
encode in Haskell,
then we can write algorithms
to work on the languages.
And that's what
you've been doing.
We're going to show
how we can take
any expression in this
language has and,
or if and only if,
if then or not and variables
and turn it into a CNF,
which is something where
the only negations
are in literals.
In other words,
they're always way
down there at the bottom,
then the literals
are contained in
disjunctions and we have
a conjunction of those.
In fact, it's something we could
translate into our
language of forms,
but we can do, leave it in
this language for the moment.
And the way we're going to
do that is in three stages.
Now I've seen some discussion on
Piazza saying you could
just do these together.
You probably can, but
you're more likely
to make mistakes.
It's much easier to separate
out the different parts
of what's going on.
Make sure they're eat right,
and then put them
together to make
some complicated thing that
depends on some reasoning of,
well, if I do this, then this,
those kinds of arguments.
You don't want to
make complicated
arguments about your code,
certainly not the first
time you write it.
If you then find that it
runs slowly and to
make it faster,
you have to do
something that needs
a complicated argument, fine.
First of all, get it running
properly with simple arguments.
And I believe that if you do
the experiment between doing
this cnf transformation with
a complicated single
pass and doing it with
what looks like three
simpler passes,
you will find that Haskell
actually makes them almost
indistinguishable
in terms of what
actually happens
inside the machine.
We're going to take
this simple example and
see how this procedure were.
The first thing we want to
do is to eliminate if and
only ifs and implies
where we've only
got one if and only if here.
And this is the step
of replacing if
and only if by a implies
b and b implies a.
And then replacing a
implies B by not IOP,
which means we would
replace b implies a bike
not b or I will do that.
That's what we've done
here. We've taken this,
we've made it into that.
If I look down here,
then this line here says,
if I want to eliminate
implications from a p,
if and only if q, I then have to
eliminate them from P implies Q,
and then end it with
eliminating them
from q implies p.
So that's exactly what
I've written here.
If I now go stage further,
can we use this line of code?
Eliminate the P implies Q,
we replace it by
not the elimination
from P or the
inflammation from q.
Everything else.
We just go down and
eliminate the bits,
but rebuild with the
same connective.
Go down, eliminate the pieces
rebuilt with the same connective.
So if we do that,
we've now finished, there's no
more implications left here.
The next stage is to
make sure that there are
no negations except
right at the inside.
So here we've got a negation
that is not at the inside.
What we do in this
example is very simple.
We just apply what's effectively
DeMorgan's law here
to replace this not
a and G by not a or
not G. Here we have
the code which says,
when we're pushing knots in,
if we push and not in pass,
true, we get false.
In other words, not true
is the same as false.
If we push it past
faults, we get true.
What's important
about these equations
is that are not
changing the meaning.
What's on the left here should
always be equivalent to
what's on the right.
Because then we're going
to push the negations in.
But if at every step we
don't change the meaning,
we have an equivalent formula.
Then when we've
done all the steps,
will still have an
equivalent formula here.
Not, not, we just take the
two knots away, not P and Q.
We do the De Morgan
to push it in,
not p or q,
we do the De Morgan
to push it in.
Then the others, we just
push in and rebuild.
And these are very
common patterns of
recursion for these
kinds of data type.
And you'll be using lots
of such data types,
not just for languages.
In general. They stated type is
an example of a tree data type.
It's a rather special one
cuz it's got some constants.
It's got away of forming
leaves, our variables.
It's got various ways of forming
trees out of other ones which are
labelled with and's
and or's and implies,
but it's still a tree.
And algorithms on trees will be
very important in
the next few weeks.
So that as taking it to this
stage and the next stage
is to push o's inside the ends.
If you look at this example,
this is an orange side already.
There's an and. So
what we need to do is
push this or inside that.
And, and I hope that
you will know how
to do that because we've
done the distributivity.
Think of the or as
a times I know it really
behaves like a plus.
But if you want to think
about this distributive law,
it's easier if you think of
this is not r times a plus g,
What would you write down?
You write not r times
a plus not a times g. So
you use that rule though,
in this case, we're interpreting
times as the awe and,
and as the plus.
I've done that there
and we finished.
Unfortunately,
if you think about it a little
bit and think what if there
were other places where things
were disjunctions and they
were outside each other,
how would we how would we
make sure we've done all of them?
It's not easy.
Try making some bigger
examples and thinking.
Not only how do I do this
example, you can all do that.
You'll just work until you've
got it pushed into the middle.
How can I tell a machine
to do this example?
Turns out to be slightly taxing.
So the secret of
this recursion is that
you start at the bottom.
So you say, I'm going to
make the lowest level.
Cnf will allow US labour law that
just literals are constants.
And now we'll express
those as cnf,
and then we'll say
how to build them up.
So we've taken away our
implies an if and only if.
So, I've only got ands
and nots and all the not.
So right at the bottom.
And we've got some
ores and that's fine.
So we make the walls
into little lists,
civil wars, and if we
add them, that's fine.
So we then got a cnf.
But if, if I then find,
I've got to cnf here and
I've got a C and F here,
and I've got to all those to CNS.
Then what happens if
I take one cnf and,
AND it with another? That's fine.
Maybe in thinking of this code,
thinking of how would you,
or two forms together is a
good way of thinking of it.
The point is to go back to
something we did look
at along time ago.
What does a plus B in brackets
times C plus d. If you,
how many terms for
you cross multiply
the different pairs.
So you'd say all four terms.
If I had a plus B,
C plus D, and E plus F,
how many terms would I get?
I get eight because you
take the selections.
So that's what's going on here.
It says, Take a close
from the left one,
take a clause from the right
one and put them
together and then now
counted as all together.
That's just like saying,
take a c times and take
a d times and take B,
C and times and take bd times.
Then that says, Take
one from one side,
take one from the other side,
and then put them together
because these are
two clause is being put
together an altogether,
if there are ten clauses in
this cnf and ten
clauses in this cnf,
how many paths do we get?
A 100. So this piece of code
hides quite a lot
of stuff going on.
Luckily, if you're doing
something on paper
to make it small enough so
that you can do it on the paper.
But it's good to understand what
the issues are once
you've done that.
So we've now got this in the
form of a list of lists.
Tend to take that list of
lists and then put it back.
We just simply say if it's
a now lists of lists,
then it means true if,
and this is a library function.
If any now x is, then it's false.
Any now x is a library
function that is
exactly equivalent to the
function we've called some.
X is null. So flip
any is our sum.
Ok, the thing that we say,
something from this
list has this property.
That's what it says,
except it takes
the property first and then
it takes the list second.
That's what any
girls, in terms of
translating logic into Haskell.
It seems much better to
have some, and every,
the way we've done it,
because it looks more like
a mathematical notation
for the same things.
Otherwise, this fold
L1 is just a trick.
What it says is,
if I get that far,
I know it's not the empty
list or with the inner one.
I know that is not
the empty list.
So I can just take the,
and of all the things
in the list or the,
or of all the things in the
list fold one just says you
don't need to give me
initial thing because
I'm working on a non empty list.
So i will just
apply this thing to
the first thing in the list and
then fold them altogether.
So that's what that code is.
So the upshot of this is
we have these stages,
we eliminate that and
eliminate these to get
here and push in the
negation to get here,
then to this, to get there.
So this is r if and
only if a and g.