Stage when we're
starting to bring
various different ways of
looking at logic together.
And in fact, today and tomorrow,
we'll finish off
the logic section.
We'll come back to it before
the exam for a revision period,
but we'll start next week
on looking at machines.
So we got quite a lot to
to pull together over
the next couple of days.
Hopefully, every one of
these pictures makes
some sense to you.
So at the bottom we have the,
the rules of Boolean
algebra that you have
actually in tutorial derived
or at least tried to derive.
And then in the tutorial seen
how you could have done it.
On the, on the right here
we have a Venn diagram.
Anyone know what that
Venn diagram is for which
which particular operation
is that band diagram for?
That's a puzzle for you,
which I'll leave you with.
On the left, we've
got a Karnaugh maps
and you know how to use a
Karnaugh map to make a cnf.
And at the top we've got
the circuits that I talked
about briefly at the
end of last week.
Now I want to return to a slide,
essentially we've shown before.
But to show you a little
bit more about it,
this was about languages,
and I gave the example of
arithmetic expressions
in algebra.
Here we have the tree that's
associated with this statement.
On the left we have an
expression x times y plus z.
On the right we have
an expression x
times y plus x times z.
And this is a formal statement.
Now last time I said
we can put numbers
in place at the variables
and then evaluate.
So we can put these numbers in,
in place of the
variables and evaluate.
And that's what's done here.
And if we do those
sums three times five
plus seven is three times
five plus three times seven.
If you were just given
that very quickly,
you'd have to think a
moment to work out.
They rearrange, but they do,
and they both come to 36.
Now one thing that's
puzzled Some of
you recently with the
tutorial you are doing.
Php at the moment is when we do,
when we don't use parentheses.
Here, you're very
familiar with saying
three times five plus
seven in brackets,
equals three times five
plus three times seven.
And you don't put any parentheses
in because you know that
the time spines more
closely than the plus.
So that's told to
Haskell by saying times
has a higher precedence
than plus up here.
Anyone, any idea what's
going on up here?
No, it's not Boolean algebra.
There were twos and
zeros and ones.
You've been doing this algebra,
you've done a lot of it.
This is linear algebra,
is a two by two matrices.
And I am substituting
matrices in here and saying
this time this plus this
equals this times this,
plus this times this.
So if you do the
matrix algebra and
I'll let you look at
it in your own time.
But I think I've got it right.
Do you find that either way?
You get the, the,
the resultant matrix is
2153 independent of
which way you do this.
This brings out the
difference between
the algebra where we have
these formal expressions
and the arithmetic,
because I've got the same
piece of algebra being
interpreted as in one
case about integers.
And the other case about
two-by-two matrices,
we could interpret about n by
n matrices if we wanted to.
In Haskell, we can not
only make you enumerated
types we started off with,
or even the label
types like or of
a list and end of a list that
we use in our language a forms,
but we can make them recursive.
So this datatype says OAuth
is either a variable,
that's what that v stands for.
A variable which is an atom
a or a constant T or a
constant f or not
of some wolf you've
already constructed,
or the, or of
some woofs you've already
constructed or the end of them,
or the implies or
the if and only if.
Along with that, to
explain the Haskell
how to both paths
expressions like that,
that words read them
when we write them and
how to express them
when it prints them,
we tell it these
rules about fixity.
And again, the end
behaves like the times
in ordinary algebra.
It finds more closely,
just as we did with the algebra,
interpreting it in terms of
both integers and matrices.
So it is useful to
interpret the Boolean
algebra in different terms.
So here's a piece
of Boolean algebra.
Here we're putting not
equals but satisfies.
But we've got essentially
the same equation.
But this time instead
of plus and times,
we've got or an end.
So we can interpret
that in the Booleans
where the or is this all
and the end is this end.
We have these in fixes
that we remember.
But we can also interpreted
what's going on here.
Where are we interpreting
it that way back,
we defined these operations.
What are the operations on?
Those were operations
on predicate.
So we can interpret
our Boolean algebra by writer
substituting Boolean values in
o predicates in the code looks
complicated until you look
at it about three times.
Once you've looked at
it about three times,
you notice that my gosh,
this is a pattern.
This was the way we
declared this type.
I put at the end,
I supposed to make it just
like the way we declared it.
I could have put the top,
but I put it at the
end in order to
write a function
that takes a wolf,
then I have to say what
it does with any Wolf.
So I say what it does
for each of the patents,
true and false for the constants,
what it does for the variables,
what it does for not p,
what it does, EOQ,
what he does for p and
q, what is the p-n?
I just list those out.
Go back to algebra.
That's rather like
saying, if I have,
if I have any set of things with
two operations which I'll
call plus and times.
It could be matrices,
could be integers,
it could be reals.
We can even add and
multiply functions if we
say f times g of x is
f of x times g of x.
If we say things like
that, we can interpret and
functions to substitute
for variables.
We simply substituted
the variables at
the bottom and then rebuild
it with the same operation
to evaluate if I take
something where I've
already put booleans
instead of the variables.
So I've taken the variables
and I've substituted
Booleans just as we did
in that little example.
Then I can evaluate that by using
the operations on pools
to do the evaluation.
And the pattern of the
function definition
is exactly the same as before.
Here we were saying to substitute
f of a for the
variable a of the SMA.
I will put those
in at the bottom.
That's what that says. And
then rebuild by saying, well,
what happens if I want to
look at P if and only if
Q I substituted in P and
I substitute to enqueue,
and I put them
together the same way.
So we just rebuild it.
Here we're evaluating,
can evaluate using
anything which has
the write operations,
these ones to match those ones.
And we can also use
a similar pattern to interpret
woofs as predicates.
A map from woofs where I've
substituted predicates for
the variables to predicates.
And this is really just
the same as before.
We interpret true as the
predicate that's always true,
false as the predicate
that's always false.
Not P is the Negev,
the interpretation,
the predicate.
Similarly, we use
these operations
on predicates over here.
This isn't only for ordinary
algebra or Boolean algebra.
It's much, much more than that.
When you start doing programming
languages and compilers,
you'll be doing the
same kinds of things.
You'll be saying.
Here's a compiler,
here's what it means to
do such and such with it.
And you'll have the
same kinds of things
going on in a more
complicated setting.
So it's worth sitting down with
these and try and
get your head round.
First of all, what's going
with the ordinary algebra,
then understanding how
that really is the
same as what we're doing
with the Boolean algebra.
And then we're
ready for next year
when you have to look at
it in more general things.