Order orderings are very
important in computer science.
You may have seen
these orderings.
So this is 0, is less than one,
false is less than true.
These are the subsets
of a singleton set.
These are the subsets of
a set with two elements.
These are the subsets of a
set with three elements.
And these are the subsets of
a set with four elements.
When you're looking
at Karnaugh maps,
you're looking at
subsets of 16 things.
And if you try and even draw
the next hypercube above
these upsets a four things.
It just gets so messy.
You can't see it's a
hypercube anymore.
Orderings very important in
computing the question
of information.
We've, we have more
information coming in.
We can have more
information going out.
You will see those ideas
a lot as you go
through the course.
Here we're just going to
look at the ordering as
it regards our current topics.
The ordering a less
than or equal to b,
which we were looking at when
we looked at satisfaction,
it corresponds to a
implies B being true.
If we look at two variables,
this one can be false or true.
That's a, this one could be
false or true, that's B.
Then when this one a is less
than or equal to this one,
that is in these three cases than
the implication is true.
Otherwise it's not.
If we look again at
that hypercube of
the subsets of four things,
then here we have four things,
any one of which may be
either in or not in.
So I put the ones that are in
as green and the ones
that are not in as red.
Okay, so we've got it's whatever
predicate is false down here.
Of all four things
in our universe.
This is true of all four
things in our universe,
and these are the other
possible predicates
on a universe of four things.
We can identify some of these
if we think of the predicate a as
being true on the bottom row
and falls on the top row.
And the predicate be as being
false here and true there,
then I think that will
correspond to what I have here.
This is not a or not b.
So not a is this top row,
not b is that first column.
This of course is
just everywhere true.
This is not a or b.
So we can write down
an expression for
every single one of
these things is not a.
This one here is the
exclusive OR of a and B.
One of them is true,
but not both of them are true.
And if we look at this
diagram now we can see
these arrows correspond
to implications.
So it's true that if a x or b,
then a or not b is true, right?
So this arrow corresponds to
the truth of an implication.
All of these arrows do.
In the original cube.
I didn't have arrows,
but now the ordering
is making a difference
because set is the empty set
is smaller than this set,
which is a singleton.
In fact, we have for singletons,
this one, this one,
this one, and this one.
And the empty set is
less than all of them.
But these two are less than
this one which is doubled.
And there are two states
that are in there.
This implication is just the
containment relation that
we started off with when we
were looking at syllogisms,
we get these cube sitting
inside the hypercube.
And the hypercube is
basically made up
of a number of those
cubes locking together.
And not B implies a x obey and
IX OP implies A0 not flow.
If I take things out
of the hypercube,
imagine we're now sitting inside
a much bigger hypercube with
as many variables as we like,
but we can only look
at little bits of it.
So if I have a proposition,
x and I have a proposition,
why think of them as
subsets of a set X or
Y will be bigger
than both x and y,
and x and y will be
smaller than both x and y.
And in fact, this is
the smallest thing that is
bigger than both of these.
And this is the biggest thing
that is smaller
than both of those.
Suppose I interpret
some propositions,
then if these propositions set
like this with this
arrow going up,
then it's true that this
one implies this one,
this one implies that one,
this one implies
that one, and so on.
Now, we're going to look at
the very simplest
cases of satisfaction.
That is, satisfaction for
conjunctions of clauses,
where each clause has
at most two literals.
So what's a clause with two
literals are like, well,
it's either a or b,
not b, not a or not
B or not a or B.
If I just take two atoms,
a and B, I make
notes for Clausius.
What's that got to
do with arrows?
Here? I'm just going to
look at two things with
arrows, a implies b.
So if I manage to
interpret those things in
a universe so that a
implies b is true,
then it means that B contains
more things than aid us.
Every state that's in a is
in B allowed states that are
neither in a NOR NB were
allowed states that are
neither in a or in B,
in B but not in a.
And in both of them, if a
implies b is true and I'm in
a state where a is true
and I must be in a
state where p is true.
So if I've made a true
than anything above,
it must be true.
Because if this
implication is true
than the set where a is true
is contained in the set,
whether things above it true.
So this ordering tells me
what valuations I can have.
I can't have the valuation
that makes a true and b false.
These lines I've drawn
a meant to be pictures.
I've drawn the line
between true and
false. What does that mean?
Drawing the line
between true and we
go back to this diagram,
then I consider the states
that make this true,
and then they certainly make that
true because this is
contained in that.
So I can draw a
line here and say,
I'm only thinking of states
where all three of
these are true.
Or draw a line here and say,
I can make all of
these things is true,
but not anything below.
I can make all of
these things true.
Because if I make these two true,
then I make that true and
that true and not true,
and I make nothing below true.
Thinking of particular
valuations allows me to say,
if I make this thing true,
I make all things above it true.
That means I can draw
a line across saying,
how do I separate the
things above which a
true from the things
below which are false.
So this is a line
that says everything
below here is false,
and everything
above here is true.
That's what the green
is meant to symbolise.
I can make this arrow
valid if I draw
a line here and make
everything above their
true and everything
below their false.
I can also make it valid.
If I make everything above here
true and everything
below their false,
because I make a false and
b true and that's okay.
Or I can make everything
above here true,
everything below here false.
That says I make them all false.
And again, a implies b is true.
So just three ways of doing it.
We can pick them up
from the diagram.