That's a bit boring because
we could already draw that.
We're going to look
at problems which are
formed from such
binary constraints.
So here's an example.
Universities have very
weird regulation.
Sometimes you may not take
both archaeology
and cameras three,
not a or not see.
You can't take both of them.
That's how we say
you can't get both.
You say not one or the other.
And that came up in the exercise
that we're doing
for your tutorial.
If you take biology,
you must K chemistries
that biology Implies
chemistry or not.
B or c, you must take
biology or archaeology.
And B or a. If you
take chemistry, your
mistake, divinity.
And you may not take both
divinity and biology.
So again, it's not the
or not be question.
What combinations of
course is can you take?
So we have a, B,
C, D, four different courses.
So there are 16 possible
combinations of cost is
that we could take and which of
those combinations
satisfy these rules?
It's not immediately obvious,
but what we're going to do is
say a method that
makes it obvious,
we can translate this,
not BOC Back to the b implies
c that it originally had.
We can translate this
to a implies Nazi,
we can translate this
to not B implies a,
and this one to C implies D,
And this one to
the implies not B.
So we can translate each
of those conditions into
an implication by saying that
this o corresponds
to r implies not a.
They saw corresponds
to not a implies
that this corresponds
to not r implies a,
and this corresponds
to north of this,
which is our implies B.
You can do that two ways,
as well as saying the Nada
or a means r implies not a.
It also means the
contrapositive that
a implies not r. And
similarly with this one,
vitals meaning not
a implies not g,
It also means g implies a.
Each time we have a
clause with two literals,
then it corresponds to
two equivalent implications
that both equivalent.
So all three things
here were equivalent.
Sometimes with the method
that we're going to look at,
you need to use only
one of these forms and
sometimes you'll have to
actually both of those.
That's just showing
how that comes.
Because of course this
disjunction is symmetric.
Not r or not a is the
same as not a or not are.
If I have clauses
with two literals,
they correspond to implications.
In fact, each one because
of contraposition,
corresponds to two implications.
So we can think of them
in terms of implication.
But that means that
we can try drawing
diagram rather like that one
just for a implies b that I had.
And think about how truth
values might work for them.
Remember, a implies b is true.
If a is less than or equal to
b and we're giving things value,
we're giving them Boolean values,
making something's true
and something's false.
And if there is an arrow
going from a to b,
then if we make a true,
we have to make be true.
That means that the head
of the arrow either
must be on the same side as a.
So we've got a arrow
b, b's at the head.
If a is false,
the head can be anywhere it can
be true, or it can be below.
The value of a has to be
less than or equal
to the value of B.
If I separate them,
ones above, that's fine.
If I put them both above,
that's fine because there's
two less than or equal.
But if I try and go
the other way round,
I'm not giving them values
that are less than or equal.
So I can cut here,
and that makes these two true.
I can cut here, and that makes
this one true. And
that one's false.
And cut here, and that
makes both of them false.
That's the rule for
a single arrow.
And if you've got a rule
for a single arrow,
then you really got this
because all you have
to do then is to
make sure that for however
many arrows you've
got on your diagram,
for each of them, you follow
the rule for a single arrow.
The rule is if an arrow
crosses the line
between true and false,
then it must point upwards where
it crosses, not downwards.
Evaluation make
some literals true.
Of course the negation is false.
So we can always
draw a picture of
evaluation by saying these
are the ones that are true.
And we'll put them
above the line,
and this one's false and we'll
put them below the line.
Now suppose I have that
valuation and I say,
does that valuation make
a arrow is be true?
Does that valuation
make arrows be true?
The answer is, you just
draw the arrow from a to
b and you cheque that where it
crosses the line,
it goes upwards.
Does this valuation
make D arrows a true?
No, because if I draw the
line from here to here,
then it's a bad line,
it goes the wrong way.
If we have the evaluation
here and you asked question,
is this arrow satisfied or not,
then you can easily
Aren't. You draw them.
And if you find an error, you
have to cross out like that,
then you haven't satisfied
all the conditions.
Are we going to do is
to use that backwards.
We're going to say,
suppose I have the arrows,
but I don't yet
have the valuation.
Can I use the diagram
with the arrows to draw
a line that makes evaluation
that satisfies the rules.
So this was, we have
evaluation, we draw a line.
What we're going to do
next is we have a diagram.
We draw a line and that
gives us evaluation.
The line we draw has to be such.
It doesn't break
any of these rules.