What happens if some
of them are negated?
So suppose I have some of
these that have a NOT on them.
But what does that
valuation mean?
It makes S true.
It makes Q false.
What does it do to our,
makes not our true.
So it makes our false.
Similarly, it makes not P false.
So it makes Pete True.
Everyone understand how
we read the valuation
of the literals that we're
making true and they're above,
and the literals that we're
making false when they're below.
So if it's a negated literal,
then it makes an
atom the opposite.
What happens if I
repeat something?
So here I've got not p
and p. Now as well
as the rule says,
you must always cross an arrow
going upwards, or sorry,
crystalline, an arrow must
always cross the
line going upwards.
We've also got the rule,
when I have a valuation,
I've gotta put not something on
the other side from our
something's whereby put a true,
there has to be false.
I make a false that
nasa has to be true.
So if they both occur,
and there I've got
a p and a not pay,
any legal line has to go
between p and not pay
for this problem.
Instead of having all
five of the lines
that we had before
for the earlier
problem that look the
same but didn't have
the p repeated.
We have to go between
the p and not
p. This is a consequence
of something
called ps is r2 NOT P
implies P of I have an
arrow from NOT P to P,
then I have to draw the
line between these two.
Therefore, p must be true.
What happens now
here's an example.
R implies Q and R
implies S. So I draw
the diagram and I can
certainly make this true
by drawing this line.
If I make all of
our Q and S false,
then because the
implications are true
when both their
arguments are false,
this lines perfectly fine.
How many other lines can we draw?
The lines don't have to be
horizontal, latent be wiggly.
They've just got to cut
the arrows the right way.
So each line has a,
a red side and the
green side that
we don't normally draw
them in red and green.
We don't have red
and green pencils.
It just to make you think of
the two sides, draw the line.
And it's got a side
that's below it,
an aside that's above it.
And we've got to cross so that
the below side has the
tales of any arrows,
and the above side has
the heads of the arrows.
Where else can I draw a
line? I've drawn one?
Can you draw for more?
We can come here in here and
we can go straight across.
But we can also come in
here and go down there.
We can come in here and
go straight across.
But we can also come
in here and go there.
And we can also go across here.
Helpful sometimes.
When things get more
complicated to count,
how many ways are there of
coming from here towards there.
This is a different
kind of arrow.
This is, I'm coming from here,
coming from here. How
many ways there is?
One way I can get to
that line because I've
just started as one way
I get to that line.
But once I'm in here,
there are two ways I
could have gotten here.
So when I came out, there were
two ways I could get there.
In two ways I could get the
here, there's just one.
So down here I can
count two plus two
plus one is five altogether.
Sometimes helpful
just to keep tally.
This is just going through
those various valuations.
What do we do now?
So I want you to work out
how many ways there are of
drawing a line there that
satisfies the rules.
First cheque, do we have
any repeated atoms?
In other words, do we have, well,
either something repeated,
in which case they both,
if I have a and a has
gotta be the same,
same side of the line if
you've written it twice,
but I would advise
not doing that.
Link it together instead.
But do we have an a and not
a or an hour not on them.
So we can just go ahead
and count the lines.
We don't have to worry
about the second rule.
If we draw one's coming in there,
11111, what number
am I going to put?
What number am I
going to put here?
Last time we looked at
an example where there
were two ways of coming
in on this side.
So we put a two on those
because there were two ways
we could have got here,
but now there are three
ways of getting in.
So now we will put a three
here and three here,
and three here.
Now we just count the
ways we can get out
altogether one way
here, three there,
because they count
for the three ways
we could have come
in, going out there,
three here because they count
for the three ways
we could have come
in getting out there
and three here because
of the three ways.
So in total, how many do we have?
I've got one at the top,
one at the bottom, and
three times three.
So I've got 11, that's
the one at the top here,
the three, the 331 at the bottom.
We can come through here and just
make all of these literals true.
Or we can go through the top
and make all of them false,
or we split them up.
And there are three ways that
make you not P false and Q true.
There are three ways
that make Q false,
not are true, and there are
three ways that may not
have false and true.
So I put one on each of
these places I can
get into the diagram.
If I'm in this region,
I had three ways
of getting there.
Through here, through
here, through here.
So on the ways I get
out of that region,
I label them each with a three.
Because the number
of lines that get
to here could be that one,
that one, or that one.
And the number of
lines to get to here
could be that one, that one,
or that one number here
could be that one,
that one or that one.
So that's why I've got a
three on each of these.
I've still got the possibility of
this line which is
that one there,
and this line which
is that one there.
So these two accounted separately
and then we got three.
We got three plus three
plus three to give us 11.
You will get practise on this.
It can be very confusing
if you just try and draw
the lines that some
lines drawn on it.
Do we have 11123456?
I think we don't have 11.
Which one's missing?
It's much easier to do
the counting them to
dry and draw the lines.
The hint of what's missing is we
know that there should
be three ways of,
three ways of coming out here.
So we only have two,
so that one's missing and
that one's missing amino,
there should be three coming out
here, so that one's missing.
And I think then we've
got all the lines.
But the counting, except in
the simplest cases is easier.
The other way of
thinking about it
is the other way of
thinking about it.
The other way of thinking
about it is I have
three ways of getting in
here and three ways
of coming out here.
So I've got three times,
three ways of going
through here altogether.
Okay, that's also a way of
thinking about it which works.
But you want a single
block like this,
but we'll see examples soon
where that's more difficult.