Here's an example where
that's more difficult.
So if we just look at
that formula at the
top and say, okay,
we've got a Universe
with 256 individuals,
eight letters, 256 individuals.
I want to count how many of
those individuals
actually satisfy this.
That's what we're
trying to work out.
From a formula. You
can draw a diagram.
You have to think a little bit to
make it look moderately.
Any errors trying
to point upwards,
because it's helpful to do that.
The formulae will give you
to do this exercise with,
will be pretty easy to draw
the translation from
what's at the top.
Not B implies, not a implies ie.
Cheque it, but I'm
pretty sure I've got
the right formula
for this diagram.
And if I haven't worked with
the diagram rather than
the formula here again,
I've got something where we
don't have anything
with its negation.
First thing to note here is that
the formula only mentioned
seven of the letters.
So that means that
whatever answer I get,
I'll effectively have
to multiply it by two
because the letter H isn't used.
So whatever answers I get
that talk about the
letters from a to G,
b two possibilities
and we can make
H true or we can make H falls.
So we're now going to count
the number possibilities
for those seven atoms.
And we'll do it the
way we did before.
We can start from the left.
You could start from the
right if you really are one
of the people who wants to
read from right to left,
and that's better for you.
You could start
thinking coming in
here and putting the
numbers on that side,
but I'll do them
here to start with,
and then we'll cheque and see
if they give the same answer.
So one way of getting in there,
one way of getting in the way of
getting in the way
of getting in that,
one way of getting
in this region.
How many ways are there
of getting into it?
Three. And this region,
how many ways are there
of getting into it?
That three goes on
those two things.
So how many ways are
there of getting
into this region here?
77 ways of getting in.
How many ways of getting out 777?
So how many
evaluations do we get?
We can go across the
bottom here, that's one.
We can come through here somehow.
But there were seven
ways of getting in here.
And for each of those seven ways,
there are three ways
of getting out.
So we got those three
sevens plus one
is and let me do that.
44 of the 256,
it would not be fun to
try and do that with
the truth table,
where it's doing it like
this gets to be quite
fun because you suddenly realise,
gosh, I've mastered the universe.
So that's counting the ways of
threading a path
from left to right.
If you have a non planar graph,
what you should do
is try and simplify.
And one way we know
of simplifying
problems about logic
clauses is to say, well,
we can at least make it
simpler by considering
the cases where a is true and
the cases where a is false.
Typically if you
do that once on a,
on a non planar graph,
you get to planar graphs and
those two out and
add it together.
So it's the same sorts of
tools as we used before.
Same tools we use in the
PLL simplify the problem
into a simpler set of courses
because I take a true,
simpler set of clauses
because I take a
false and then add those
two results together.
I always find it
shocking that this works
both ways here we've
done this some we've
come up 22 times two.
If we work from right to left,
we label these ones with ones.
So there are three ways
of getting in here.
So we label those two, threes.
So there are six ways
of getting out here.
Three ways of getting
out here, one way here,
and it has to,
but it's a really weird fact,
is add up the same amount.
So this is a fact of geometry,
logic and arithmetic,
approaching a planar graph from
the left or the right
and doing this counting,
you get the same result.
Whichever way you
count gets good.
Fact, because if you didn't,
the universe would fall to
pieces as in 0 equals one.