Uh-huh. What's more complicated
about this example?
What do we do when
we see an example?
We first cheque whether
there's a repeated datum.
We got Bay and
that's the only one.
So what's the rule now,
any line we draw has to
go between not B and B.
And it will have to go,
even if not p was above NP
was beloved still
have to go between.
So it has to go between.
And that actually simplifies
the problem provided
you notice it,
because it means you put zeros on
the things that don't
go between the two BCE.
So this is like
what we did before,
except that we now have a 0 up
here and a 0 down here,
because they're not legal.
We count these three,
that uses two 3's here,
a one here, that gives
us the seven there,
but we only have
two ways of getting
out with seven, that's 14.
And then again, this problem
has two lattices missing.
So it's 14 times 2X squared.
There were two letters missing.
So instead of multiplying by two,
we multiply by two twice.
Here's another example
where we see that we get
the same result whichever
way we approach problems.
Let's go back just to
this learning. Take
a minute or two.
We have now our original problem.
We've got a mixture of B's,
not B's and A's and nowadays,
so we're going to
put everything and
we're going to draw
the whole thing.
So we'll do both the
B's and C's and B's.
And so I've John that diagram.
And frankly, this is
difficult to do with
pencil and paper.
It's actually easier
to do on the machine.
Cuz I can drag things
around and align,
stay together and you can play,
but we will draw the diagram.
This is more complicated than
I would expect you to do,
but it's fun to play
pulling things around a
bit from that diagram.
We get to this diagram.
By the time we've caused
it to this diagram,
you can work it out.
One consequence of the
arrow rules that I
haven't talked about is
that if we have a cycle,
then I can never draw a line
through that cycle
because if I did,
it would cut one error one
way and one arrow another ways.
You can never cut
through a cycle.
Either we gotta be
completely below that
or completely above it.
Similarly with this cycle,
we've also got the D.
We have to go between
d not d. So I can't
do a line down here.
If I come in here,
I have to go out above
D and I can't come out.
They're somehow because that
would make that would make
this one go the wrong way.
So we have to come out
above the, so in fact,
for this example is simply
that one and that one.
So there are only two
possibilities for the courses
you can take with those rules
that I mentioned
at the beginning.
Some ways that it's just a toy.
But it's, it's actually
a fact that problems,
that can be phrased
as 2-SAT problems
where every clause
is a binary clause,
can be solved in polynomial time.
Whereas the moment you get
to three SAT problems,
then that NP-complete there among
the hardest problems,
we know there,
as hard as all the
other hard problems,
satisfiability is
really a key point.
And the, if you look
at what happens with
unit propagation in
the, in the, the PLL,
what it's doing is when things
are down to two literals,
then it creating unit clauses
and propagating them.
And doing that efficiently.
So it's taking the,
the easy bits of the problem and
doing it efficiently
and then leaving
the heartbeats
isolated rather than
treating the easy bits in the
same way as the heartbeats.