What we're going to do
next is we have a diagram.
We draw a line and that
gives us evaluation.
The line we draw has to be such.
It doesn't break any of
these rules. We couldn't.
Here are some arrows.
The arrows either stay on
the same side of the line
or cross it upwards.
And then other valid,
This one here is not valid.
For a valid this one
isn't, as I've said there.
So the valuation
makes the implication
true unless the arrow
goes from true to false.
We can also, of course have
things like Not the arrows,
not a, but interestingly,
because the deer on
other sides of the line,
not the arrow is not a and
not a and a are on other
sides of the line.
Not D or not a actually
corresponds to also that arrow.
So if one of these
arrows is valid
for an implication
than the other one is,
this is exactly what
contraposition is about.
Contraposition puts each thing
on the other side of the line.
Because when you
negate something,
you move it from being
true to false and
being false to true.
So it doesn't matter which one
of these arrows we put in.
It has the same force.
But when we put things together,
you'll find that sometimes
you need to put both of them in.
It doesn't matter which way
we represent the fact that
not a or D nausea ODE
corresponds to a implies D,
but it also corresponds
to not the implies not a.
And the rule will be the same
no matter which way we drew them.
We can't have arrows
going from top to bottom.
And this is just showing how
the contraposition
works in various ways.
Contraposition works here in
the way that I just indicated.
But if I have something
up here than it is
contraposition down the bottom
is also completely
down the bottom.
So contraposition works
fine with this rule.
So this gives us three
possible valuations.
Suppose I extend this
diagram and I say,
not only does a
arrow B be arrows c,
c would be another stage
and true would have
to move further up.
We put false at the
bottom and true at
the top just to remind ourselves
which way the diagrams going.
Of course, we can
never make true false.
So we can't put
our line above the
true and we never
make false true.
So we never put our line below
the false airline has to
cut somewhere between
true and false.
Suppose I put an extra
arrow in here from B to C,
and then from C to true,
how many valuations could
I make that would make
both a implies b and
b implies c valid?
Draw the diagram or
in your mind's eye,
draw the diagram.
Let's try and draw it.
Let's pretend this is
a c true up there and
we'll put an arrow there.
How many more
valuations do I get?
This valuation makes a,
b, and c true.
So certainly a is
true and B is true.
So a implies b is true,
and B is true and C is true.
So be inside, c is true.
So this valuation slow works.
This one still works.
A is false, B is true,
and B and C are both true.
So it's fine that
valuation works.
The only evaluation we
didn't have this this one.
So there's one more valuation,
which is I can either
make c true or false.
If I make B true,
I have to make c true.
If I make a true, I have
to make B and C True.
But when I make the
other two false,
I can either may see
true or makes a false.
So we get for evaluation 1234,
there are 26 letters
in the alphabet.
Suppose I have a implies
B implies C, and so on.
All the way to X
implies Y implies said,
how many valuations make all
of those 25 arrows connecting
the 26 letters of the alphabet in
a line says 26 letters the
alphabet, there's 25 arrows.
How many cuts can I make?
There are two extra arrows.
One that comes from false to a,
and one that comes
from zed to true.
So that's 25, arrow
is plus two is 27.
If we have a chain of
implications like that,
we've now worked that out.
If you thought about
it for a little while,
you would've got to that answer.
If I have any chain of
implications going up,
then I can cut in any
one of these gaps.
Anyone of those cuts will work.
You've got 12345 for that
example, possible valuations.
So if we had this problem,
which is this problem,
we draw that diagram.
So we have a chain of N things.
We get n plus one valuations.