Back to basics. Every
small triangle is read.
We did that fine.
Everyone's into catch on to
what was going on there.
And we just translated those
things with and's and or's.
So every small triangles read,
some small triangle is red.
It looks to start with as
though this could get really
complicated because could
say lots of things here.
So we're going to try and
make things simple because we
have these operations
on predicates.
Instead of thinking, oh, this is
about three different predicates
and there might be one,
about four When I
add something else.
And finally, when I
get something else,
now I have one predicate here.
I'm, I'm predicate here.
So I've made it simpler just
by using those operations.
If I want you to explain,
every small triangle is red,
then I load in eateries plane,
but every something is red means.
And now we're going
to look at another
example because we're going to
make it slightly
more complicated.
Will start from this,
which is very simple.
We have a universe of
people and we have a
predicate is happy.
And we want to say,
everybody is happy.
Where body, body be,
the collection of all people.
Just the words look nice.
Ok. Everybody is happy,
is, and is happy.
X for the X is drawn from body.
That's even simpler than
what I just asked you about.
So I assume it's all right.
What I'm going to do now is to do
something that I assume
will not be o, right?
And you're welcome
to ask questions.
I can say, okay,
I want to say something
like everybody is happy.
Say every xs is p,
or every x in x,
this is p. Every x in
this list of xs has
property P. So I take the x
from the axis and
say it has be lipid.
Now, what I've done
now is to write
a function every,
what's its type?
It takes a list of things,
it takes a predicate on things,
and it gives me back a Boolean.
I can now write,
instead of writing
all this stuff when I
have to translate that,
I can literally write that
Haskell and it works.
That's the game we're gonna
play mainly today is trying
to get Haskell to look
more like language.
And it'll actually help us
explain what language
means by doing it.
We can say this.
We got every going
from a list of
the things we're talking
about, this predicate.
And then he just says, for
all the things you're
talking about, it's true.
The way we're going
to make things more
complicated is to move
from predicates like
is happy or is red,
or is big or small,
to relations like loves
person, loves person.
Any any resemblance to
person living or that is
totally coincidental.
Loud asthma, Mary,
what does loves?
Mary main, if I write it down?
Well, we normally design
these things so that we
can use them in infix.
I love this, Mah Meri
really means my loves Mary.
If I just write loves Mark,
what type would
novice monogamy law.
This is just one of
these predicates.
It does from person
to person taboo.
And as we know, we know
it's brackets in there.
There could be packets
there and it would
make no difference.
So when we gave a person to
Love's, we get a predicate.
What does that predicate me?
Which people is it true of?
Suppose we put an X
in here for Mary,
then we'd have labs of x.
And log of x would
mean MA loves egg.
So loves mock means ma loves.
So a true of the people
who are loved PyMOL.
Now we got our every so
we can say everybody
loves MA what does
everybody loves Mark mean,
we haven't got it written
the right way yet.
At the moment it's written
in a confusing way,
but it'll get better.
Lavas, Ma is true if
someone loves them.
So what's it mean
to say it's true
of everybody loves everybody.
That's how we normally put it.
But because we've put
this partial application
here and now is the infix
version. It's mixed up.
Loves Mary is the same as Mark.
Loves Mary.
What you have to keep in mind.
So everybody loves Mark
is and of loves my X,
where X comes from body.
That's just the way
we defined everybody.
We take this predicate,
we apply to the axis and we
say it works for all of them.
So it means Matlab's everybody.
Haskell does something
really nice for us.
Haskell has clever thing
is called sections A7.
I have something like loves,
which is a binary operator.
So here we've got
an infix binary.
Then if I write my loves
the parentheses around it,
it says, are you
thinking of this?
Man loves x, means mark Planet X.
Now, this function works
the way we'd like it to
work. Loves everybody.
We can also do some
just the same way
as we done every same type.
It takes the list of things,
takes a predicate,
gives you a Boolean.
Some axes have property
p0 means for P of X,
X Fmax is, again,
you should remember that
from a few weeks ago.
If you remember a few
weeks ago anymore,
some body loves Mary,
should be o of b, loves Mary.
P comes from body.
Somebody loves Mary.
The way we can write
somebody loves Mary is
simply to say some body
loves Mary in brackets.
You can do that section
on either side.
So let you fill in
either the right, left,
and make a function
out of the other path
until you learns about this,
you would have had to write a
function like this and say,
loves Mary is a function
from version to bool.
Love Mary of x is x loves Mary.
But because Haskell has this,
there is something
that is the function
which for an x gives you x
love Mary, it's this one.
The x is not even
mentioned in there.
It's the thing you'd put
in to complete this.
So those are sections.