This is Phil slide on sections.
It works for things like
greater than because they
are just functions from
two things to bool.
So it's just like the ones
we've been talking about.
This is the property of
being greater than 0.
This is the function
multiplied by two.
This is the function at one.
This is the function take
two to the power of me.
So it's the function of n,
gives you two to the power n. And
this is the function square
that we wrote earlier.
So these two are very different.
But in the two times o plus one,
we could have swapped those
around because there,
because they want, what's
the name of what they are?
Commutative operations.
Commutative, probably useful
to your sections in logic.
But now we want something
a little more flexible.
This is to show why
what we have so
far isn't quite flexible enough.
I want to now try
somebody loves everybody,
and everybody loves somebody
at least I'll try one of
them and leave you to
worry about the other one.
So if I say everybody,
Mary loves, that means
Mary loves everybody.
So 7x instead of Mary loves,
i do an x. I can say x loves
everybody, loves everybody.
X, if everybody loves,
right, I've just put
x in the set of Mary.
And then I say, somebody
loves everybody,
is, some body has the
property, loves everybody.
It's already with a
tiny simple example,
getting a bit unwieldy
and we're having to use
really long names to
explain to ourselves
what we're doing.
And it's not the way to do this.
The way to do this
is to use lambda.
You fill were here, he'd
be jumping sky high.
You'd be doing all
sorts of dances.
I don't quite down site feel
Lander is really important
and I'm so glad I get to
introduce it to you
before he does.
Lambda will introduce just with
some ordinary
mathematical kind of
examples and then
we'll take it back
to use it in the logic again,
the function square takes an
x and gives you x times x.
But I can also write
it whenever I have a function
definition like this,
function definition
has identifier
for the beginning a variable.
Let's just have a
variable and then
an expression with that variable.
So here I've got the identifier,
but I don't put variable
right after it.
I say this and the way I read
that backstroke is lambda.
That's because it looks like
the long bit of the lambda.
And since keyboards
don't have lambdas,
it was decided to use that
backstroke for lambda.
So this would be the
mathematical notation for this,
which had a, did introduce in
one of her talks to some of you.
I think this is the same
function as we defined here.
But instead of giving a
name to x on this side,
the name for X is bound up in
this expression and it's only
available within brackets.
If I used x again,
outside, it will
be a different x.
If I already had an x
being used outside,
this one would have
right in here,
x means this one.
Then I could write hypotenuse AB
is the square root of the square
of a plus the square root 2pi.
But I could also have
two parameters here,
lambda AB, square root,
square a, square b. That's fine.
So this enables us,
instead of creating
long functions
with very long names,
do what they do.
You can just make the function
without creating a name for it.
And it's much, much clearer.
Once you get used
to reading them.
So we know loves Mary
of x is x loves Mary.
So we use a lambda to write that.
Then loves Mary is just lambda x,
arrow x loves Mary.
So when I want to write,
somebody loves Mary, I
could say some body.
And then lambda x, x loves Mary,
because we know this
maids loves Mary.
And if I write it
in Maths than that,
there is something in
body which I'm thinking of
a sunset now not Lisbon,
such that x loves Mary.
Similarly, if I want to do
mock gloves, why? That's fine.
But we can also say mark loves
is lambda Y. Mark loves.
Why? When I say everybody loves,
i can say everybody lambda y, y.
This gets a bit easier to work
with because I can see the every,
every body, let's call it
y has the property that loves Y.
As we read this, somebody,
let's call it x has the
property that x loves Harry.
So now let's try.
Everybody loves
somebody, everybody,
let's call it x has the
property that somebody,
let's call it y. X loves y.
All of a sudden, we get
rid of all that
stuff on the other.
All these long things.
Just by saying this,
everybody call it x
and then we don't worry
about these properties,
um, how it looks after itself.
We've just written it down
and it actually works.
So this is for all
x there exists,
or there should be
a y here, sorry,
that should be y, the x.
For all x there is a
y such as x loves y.
For all x, there is a y, yes,
that should be a wider
what I would like you to
do is to try and work out
what these three main.
So I want you to translate them
back into your natural language,
your mother language,
because it's,
it's hard enough to
one's natural tongue,
let alone during in
a foreign language.
What does exercise to main?
Let's go back to 11 means.
If we just think of EU law
being the bodies
we're talking about,
then it would mean that
everyone here loves somebody
hearing copy themselves.
We haven't said It's
not themselves.
So it could be that
just love themselves.
So it might even be true,
everybody here loves somebody.
In example two, we take
somebody you have to do
is choose that body
before we go on.
So we choose that body,
then they have the property
that they love everybody.
There is somebody here who
loves everybody, has
very good of you.
Whoever you are. Example three,
there is somebody here.
What does this say? Who
is loved by everybody?
And the final one, every body.
This is we, what does it mean?
Everybody, you as someone
who loves them, the good.
Saying those for different
things in English is
actually quite difficult in
every natural language
I know anything about.
It's quite difficult to make
those four distinction step
very important distinctions
when you're doing mathematics,
when you're doing computing, and
also in your love life too.
But that's not the point.
So it's really useful
to have this unwinding
at the moment.
It may seem, my god,
you've taken something simple,
like everybody lost somebody and
made it into these horrible
lambdas and stuff.
But actually, you will find,
particularly if
you're thinking about
things in maths, arguments,
you find where they
save everything,
this integral, you get mixed up.
Try and analyze it in
these ways and these
mathematical notations,
the furrows and exists
if I got it right,
which that should be a y really
do help to make it clear.
This is why when you
read a paper and
increasingly when you read
your course notes
through your time here,
am I trying to say
something like this?
We will normally
put it into words,
will more likely put
it into a mixture of
words in mathematical symbols
because we can be more
precise that way.