I said at the beginning
that we will be
studying Language,
Truth, and Logic.
And we've been studying
truth and logic.
So we've been looking at worlds
where properties
hold and don't hold.
And the same symmetry
Nokia logic is.
We've looked at the Algebra
or those properties,
and we've reasoned about those
properties using algebra.
That certainly logic
that would have
been recognized as all
there was to logic until
early in the 20th century.
The logic now has
another important piece,
which we normally don't do in
an algebra with addition and
multiplication and numbers.
But some people do
the people who code
algebra in computers have
to do what I'm about
to talk about.
But we always do it in Logic
and have done for a century
that is not just to
use the language,
but to reason about
the language which is
necessary if we're going
to compute with it.
But it is also necessary to
get some of the results we
want to get to in logic.
So we want to have
a language where the
expressions in the language
can be objects sitting in
Haskell and the computer as yet,
you don't have all
the bits of Haskell.
We need to do that for
the language that
you would normally
learn for propositional logic,
you've got all the things we
need to do a very
simple language.
So we're going to do a very,
very simple language first.
And a simple language will be
related to the exercises
you've been doing
recently where we
take an expression or
a sequence and we
reduce it and we get
a load of disjunctions and
we can join them and say
This expression is equivalent to
a conjunction of
disjunction of literals.
And a literal is either a
positive a is true or
a negative a is false.
I will develop that language in
the next video and use it to
code up a Sudoku problem.
The number of variables we
have will be and nine cubed 279,
and the number of disjunctions
will be something
over 8 thousand.
So it won't be something
we can do by hand,
but it will be
something that we can
describe using what I've
just shown you today.
And it will be something we can
easily manipulate
in the computers.
I will then develop some
algorithms to do that.
And you will find that with
just a couple of
simple idea is simple,
but it took a while for
people to find them.
We can build a program that
takes something in
this simple language,
somewhat simple
about this language.
This language will only allow
you to either take an atom,
a basic thing and say
it's true or it's false.
Or to take a disjunction
of literals to
form a clause or to
take a conjunction.
Those clauses to form a form.
The only thing we will
count as a full sentence is
a conjunction of
disjunction of literals.
That conjunction
could be empty once
the anti conjunction
represent true, true, true.
So the antique
conjunction is true.
If we had those clauses
amongst those clauses,
then maybe clauses of
all sorts of sizes.
If we have an empty clause,
the empty clause is false.
So that means it has
an empty clause.
We can't satisfy all the clauses.
So the whole thing will be false.
But that we will have
to wait till tomorrow
because we're already
out of time for today.