The entailment gamma
satisfies delta,
where both gamma and
delta are empty,
is only valid in
the empty Universe.
But the empty set is
itself a predicate,
the sequent with this
predicate on either side
of the turnstile, It's
universally valid.
We'll start this
video by seeing how
Haskell type system
resolves this confusion.
Classical keeps track of
what we're talking about.
It tells us if we're
talking nonsense in
this kind of way,
there are other
kinds of nonsense we
could talk that it
couldn't recognize.
But when we make tie
Paris, it's pretty good.
If I try and do this in Haskell,
let's take one cons
the empty lists and say
that it's of type integer.
I have to say it's a type integer
because otherwise
it gets confused.
And when I get to
this stage, it says,
I don't really know
what type we're
talking about because
you haven't told me
whether its integer
or real or double,
I'd take the tail of it.
I get the empty list.
Once I've got the empty list,
you think I could
say false Kanzi,
empty list because it just
one empty lists in
Haskell. It's not.
By this time, this particular
instance of the empty list
that we're talking about is
specialized to be
an integer list,
even though it's got
nothing in here,
trying to put false and it says
an error because it
can't match in tuple.
Sometimes Haskell typing seems
like a pain, but
on the other hand,
there comes a point where most of
your errors get caught
as type errors.
And once you get it to compile
and pass the type checker,
you've actually got rid
of the silly errors
you made a forgetting to give
one argument of
getting that needs to
be converted to something
else before you used it.
So it's really worth sticking
with the type system.
It's also really worth having
a picture of what the types are.
And I see people writing
things on Piazza as saying,
when I give it to this and I
gather that you don't quite
know what they're giving
the type signature down.
If you write it down,
you're more light-year
not discover
your error in trying
to write down,
OK. Now I'm going to
go back a little bit
to look at what we did earlier
talking about predicate.
We're going to introduce
a couple of new ideas in
Haskell that will make it
easier to talk about quantifiers.
When we say for all or
some Hua math position,
say for every epsilon
there exists a delta. Some
of you would have done that.
And they'll say for all there
exists, that's quantifiers.
And we're going to
explain quantifiers
because that's part of logic.
We had various operations
on Booleans, such as end.
And we wanted to define a
function on predicates,
which are things
that go from usable.
So that if I go to subsets
of the universe or
other the characteristic
functions
of two subsets of the universe.
Then I can add them to get a
new subset of the universe.
Some of you wanted to write this.
And I0 is, and people didn't
like it because they said,
But wait, there are
three things here.
And this looks like it's only got
two argument. What's
happening here?
Well, actually these two
types of exactly the same.
It's just, I've put in
brackets that are redundant.
Means the same with or
without the brackets.
But I want to go further on that,
although it means
the same to Haskell,
I really want you to start
thinking of it in this way.
That this is a function of
two arguments that returns
one other thing which
happens to be a function
rather than this is a
function of three arguments.
When we use a, will normally
not be interested in
providing the final x,
will normally be interested in
computing with the functions.
One way of saying that is if I
introduce type abbreviation
for these things,
I'll say type predicate
of you is a URL bu,
That just means I
can write pred you
wherever I would normally
write URLs, bool.
So then I'm looking for a
function that goes from
a and B to a and B,
which again is a predicate.
Then if I write the
type signature down,
all vestige of the x disappears.
This really is this,
even now, I still write
the definition like that.
One of the things we're going
to do today is to introduce
a notation that makes
that a bit easier.
So you see how this is natural.
Whereas here it looks really
weird because whereas x,
i don't see x any y here,
we did lots more of those things.
We took all sorts of functions.
I've written them all here.
One thing we haven't done
yet is to properly introduce
these functions implies
if and only if x or,
I mean, you've done exercises
with them, we've done them,
but we haven't
discussed them and I'm
not gonna do that today.
But I do want to point
out to you that they will
exist in Haskell and
they exist as these.
And you might want to check
that truth table sometimes.
And then we can check that.
You can check it. And some of
those at least we've
translated like this.
And we could lift all
functions if we wanted to.
And we can again go between
this view when we're thinking
of them as functions.
And a slightly more
abstract view where we
say a predicate is a function,
but I'll forget about
the function b,
and then I'll just write
the signatures like this.
So if you look at it like this,
then we've replaced
boost with Friday,
but we've got the same kinds
of operations on them.
Going back to my and,
and using a lambda to
define it makes the
type seem more natural.
Now we can write this
operation on predicates as
a and B is
the function which given
x gives me a x and b x.
But I've wrapped that up.
So maybe now it looks
a bit more actual.