So far we've been looking
at truth and logic.
We've been talking
about predicates.
We've been doing some
algebra predicates.
When we started, I talked
about the book Language,
Truth and Logic, and said that's
really what we're going to
be doing in this course.
We haven't really
talked about language.
We've tried to match
some natural language with
things we do in Haskell,
there is some ideas about
language and the way
it's meaning could be
modeled in the way we've
translated phrases
like every ISP,
but we haven't done it
in any formal sense.
And certainly the language
we're using every axis,
why we haven't set
what you can and
can't say we've just
had some things in,
left the rest unsaid.
What we're going to do over
the next three lectures
also is develop the
idea of language.
But I just want to go back
to algebra for a moment.
Algebra or algebraic expressions.
Very simple example of
one of the ingredients
of language.
So we talk about things,
but sometimes we don't
say John or Mary.
We say Mary's father or
Shawn's brother or my parents.
What we do is we
have some functions.
We start from John and then
we have to find John's Brother.
In arithmetic, we start
from numbers and we
say three plus four
or minus three.
Three plus four is a bit
like saying linguistically,
the child of Mary and Mark,
you take two things and we get
a third thing that's related
to them in some way.
So we try and look
at that in terms of
algebraic expressions that
we take this expression,
X times Y plus Z,
X times Y plus X times Z.
We can structure the language as
a tree where these are
things that stand for,
things in the world.
These are things that
stand for operations.
And really this is a
description, little computation.
It's a description of a
computation that says take x,
then add y and z,
and then multiply them by X.
Whereas the other one
is a description of a
different computation.
That computation
says, take x and y,
multiply them
together, say x and z,
and multiply them together,
then add the results.
So there's a different
computations.
And when we say those Rico,
what we're doing is
comparing the results of
those computations and saying
that they are actually
the same thing.
It's saying something about
the results of
those computations.
It's rather like saying
Marxist resume result,
Marxist one computation, Mary's
ONE another computation.
They happen to be the same.
So when we're doing logic,
we're also doing
little computations,
but they computation's
about truth values.
So this is entirely analogous.
That's the same
equation with and,
and or instead of times and plus,
it's still a computation.
Computation about logic. It says,
if I take logical things a, b,
and c, I take the o of b and say,
I take the hand of that with a.
It's the same as taking
the end of a and B,
the end the vacancy,
and during those two together
and we get the same result.
These statements about
computations with logical values.
And I say logical values
because we've already
seen that is computation's
could work for Booleans,
but they could also
work for predicates.
So there are other
things that we might
see as logical values,
which aren't just the
Booleans themselves,
just the same way as if you
interpret the results of
an algebraic equation.
You can interpret them as
being about the integers,
reals, or complex numbers.
There were all sorts of
different things that
have the structure of you
can multiply, you can ahead.
So we can interpret as equations
and the distributive laws work.
It's the same with logic.
There were all sorts of
places where we can interpret
those operations and
various laws work.