When we started, I talked
about the book Language,
Truth and Logic, and said that's
really what we're going to
be doing in this course.
We haven't really talked
about language so far.
We've been looking
at truth and logic.
We've been talking
about predicates.
We've been doing some
algebra predicates.
We've tried to match
some natural language with
things we do in Haskell,
there is some ideas about
language and the way
it's meaning could be
modeled in the way we've
translated phrases
like every ISP,
but we haven't done it
in any formal sense.
And certainly the language
we're using every axis,
why we haven't set
what you can and
can't say we've just
had some things in,
left the rest unsaid.
What we're going to do over
the next three lectures
also is developed the
idea of language.
But I just want to go back
to algebra for a moment.
Algebra or algebraic expressions.
Very simple example of
one of the ingredients
of language.
So we talk about things,
but sometimes we don't
say John or Mary.
We say Mary's father or
Shawn's brother or my parents.
What we do is we
have some functions.
We start from John and then
we have to find John's Brother.
In arithmetic, we start
from numbers and we
say three plus four
or minus three.
Three plus four is a bit
like saying linguistically,
the child of Mary and Mark,
you take two things and we get
a third thing that's related
to them in some way.
So we try and look at that in
terms of algebraic expressions.
Then we take this expression,
X times Y plus Z,
X times Y plus X times Z.
We can structure the language as
a tree where these are
things that stand for,
things in the world.
These are things that
stand for operations.
And really this is a
description, little computation.
It's a description of a
computation that says take x,
then add y and z,
and then multiply them by X.
Whereas the other one
is a description of a
different computation.
That computation
says, take x and y,
multiply them
together, say x and z,
and multiply them together,
then add the results.
So there's a different
computations.
And when we say those Rico,
what we're doing is
comparing the results of
those computations and saying
that they are actually
the same thing.
It's saying something about
the results of
those computations.
It's rather like saying
Marxist resume result,
Marxist one computation, Mary's
ONE another computation.
They happen to be the same.
So when we're doing logic,
we're also doing
little computations,
but they computation's
about truth values.
So this is entirely analogous.
That's the same
equation with and,
and or instead of times and plus,
it's still a computation.
Computation about logic. It says,
if I take logical things a, b,
and c, I take the o of b and say,
I take the hand of that with a.
It's the same as taking
the end of a and B,
the end the vacancy,
and during those two together
and we get the same result.
These statements about
computations with logical values,
and I say logical values
because we've already seen.
That is, computation's
could work for Booleans,
but they could also
work for predicates.
So there are other
things that we might
see as logical values,
which aren't just the
Booleans themselves,
just the same way as if you
interpret the results of
an algebraic equation.
You can interpret them as
being about the integers,
reals, or complex numbers.
There are all sorts of
different things that
have the structure of you
can multiply, you can ahead.
So we can interpret as
equations and the
distributive laws work.
It's the same with logic.
There were all sorts of
places where we can interpret
those operations and
various laws work.
What we don't have
yet is the tools in
Haskell to model a language
like the one we were
just talking about.
Because this language, I can
make more and more
complex expressions.
I can make bigger
and bigger trees.
To do that, we need to do
something having a recursive
type for the moment,
we can think about a
much simpler language,
which is a language
where we take literals,
which are things which may
refer to logical values.
When we do it in arithmetic,
the X and the Y aren't
themselves numbers.
They're just things that
will stand for numbers.
So here, these are things which
will stand for logical values.
And we'll have something
that will stand for an idea,
a being true, or an
idea a being false.
In this case, it's
saying it's false.
This is saying it's true.
And then we'll think of
this as just being
the all of those things that
may be more than three,
I have to put three.
There could have
been five or one,
or, or even 0,
but we'll talk about that later.
We form clauses with
o and then we can,
can join them together to
make N. But in this language,
that's all you can do.
You only can take literals,
make closes, and then make forms.
Seems like a pretty
strain language.
But actually, what we've
done so far has shown
that we can express
any logical assertion in
terms of this language.
So if we take a reduction
of a sequent that ends up
with this thing is some branches
may have been closed
off by a major rules,
but we end up with these forms
of the simple formula arrived,
moved everything to
the right because
it's the form in which
you put them in here.
So this is the form
we use when we want
to use the reduction,
get a conjunctive normal form
equivalent to our
original sequence.
So the conjunctive normal
form is this and this,
and this and this,
where each of these is
interpreted as an or.
So. If we can do things
with this language,
do things with
anything in principle
because we know is reduce or
other logical language to
an expression in this
very simple form.
Even the case that once we've
got the recursive types
and we can do the other kinds of
language computationally.
It makes good sense.
First of all, to do
this reduction to cnf
and then to use this to
answer some other questions.