We consider a language that's
quite simple like this.
There are three levels.
There are other literals,
the clauses and the form
I will call the things.
The literals are made of atoms.
But we'll come to
that in a moment
because we reduce
any problem to this.
It's worth studying
these for their sake.
That's what we're going
to do. I'm putting that
aside for a moment. We'll
come back to the language.
I want to give a logical example
of something you are
quite familiar with.
You can use algebra to
describe a situation.
You can describe a
graph by doing Algebra.
Two can also describe some
constraints using algebra.
And then you solve
an equation to find
numbers that satisfy
those constraints.
What we're going to
do now is firstly,
to use Haskell to model
the idea of a correct
solution to a Sudoku problem.
Then we're going to move
that into the language and
say is a specification of a state
filling in at the Sudoku
board with any number of
numbers in any one of
the places will be a
state of the system.
So there's lots of states.
The solution to our specification
will be a solution to the Sudoku.
First thing is to
understand how we could
just express in Haskell
without introducing
a language whether
a particular way of filling in
the board satisfies
the Sudoku rules.
We're going to write
a function S IJK.
We consider the universe of
all possible ways of
filling in Sudoku.
Ijk range over the numbers one to
nine SIJ K is the predicate,
which is true of a solution in
which k is the value
in square i j.
So if I see S 44,
that means I am talking
about this square.
So if I see S 443,
it would mean there was
a three in that square.
Otherwise S4 43 is false.
So in this example with
this state of the board,
S 443 is false,
but S1 to seven, it's true.
So we haven't even describe
that right? The next ones right?
The first one's wrong
as 12 should be seven,
not three anymore mistakes.
S, 16 should be six.
S, 21 is nine.
S to a is for S2, nine S1,
S3, three is 836 is nine.
S3. As far as you can
understand what it is for
one of those to be correct.
Homologs to be false.
These are the 279 atoms
that I was talking about.
We got nine times,
nine times nine of these.
So you're not going to be
solving this equation by hand,
but we can certainly represent
the state of the board.
The first thing I want to
convince you that we
can say is I only
allowed one number in each square
and you must put some
number in every square.
Otherwise it is a solution.
If you say upon every
number in every square,
that's obviously no solution.
If you put numbers in some
square, sort of solutions,
how do we say we put
at least one number,
any square we say,
and for all squares,
for all i j.
So we take i from one to nine,
Jade one to nine,
and then we'll say
some number is in.
So all of these numbers,
this is in that narrow
square is filled
twice L. What you can't have
two different numbers
in the same square.
If I take any i and
any j and any K,
and any k prime,
really we could say here,
any k prime that's
not equal to k,
but it's a bit more efficient.
In fact, twice as fast,
if we say any k prime
is less than k. Is that
enough to say that whenever
k prime is less than k,
they can't both be true.
It is enough because that
covers the other case,
just some different time.
The other way, if you just put
N4 equals Uc average-case twice.
So this is little optimization.
And you say either,
it's now got a k in it.
It's not a, got a k prime.
It may have neither.
In fact, in most cases,
it will have neither.
All we need to say
is that if I pick
any 21 of them must be false
because if I then fill in
the square with something,
I can't fill him
with anything else.
Exercise for you to think
about right down the
other rules for Sudoku.
So the rules are
that in each row,
each number can only occur once.
In each column. Each number
can only occur once.
And in each one of
these small squares,
each number can only
be entered once.
There is a way of making
that slightly easier if you
say that in every realm of
each number must occur.
So nine must occur somewhere,
the height must occur
somewhere that do I
need to say either
ignored only occur once?
Do I need to say that?
Why do we need to say it?
Once I've said I can't
put two numbers on
the same square.
Then if I'm going to put
all nine numbers somewhere,
then I will have
failed everything in,
but I can't duplicate
any number because that
wouldn't leave room for
one of the numbers.
If I have nine numbers to
59 squares and I've got
to fill each square,
then I can't have any
duplicates because I will
have used up all nine squares
to get each one somewhere.
So there will be all conditions.
Try writing those they say
for each row and for each digit,
there is somewhere along
our macro that digits is entered.
And similarly for the
columns and the squares.