I'm not gonna go
into that right now.
What I want to do
is then talk about
the language and this language.
The moment you may think
that's not quite Haskell.
And if you don't make
the right definitions,
it is not yet Haskell,
but it actually is Haskell.
So this language is going
to appear here in Haskell.
So what we're going to do is
to solve a Sudoku puzzle.
We're going to write
some conditions
about the things which we
don't know the values of,
just as you would do
with algebra when
you write an equation and
say, let's solve for x,
and we'll translate
those things I had
before into something that
looks almost the same.
The only difference
is I've changed
the ands and ors too big.
And because there's
some other functions.
And where I said S IJK here,
I've got, I've got
something which is
an atom in my logic,
which is S, i, j, k.
It's just a letter,
it's s. Think of it
with subscripts i,
j, k, which could take
any logical value.
So what we're now
doing is putting
constraints on those
logical values might take,
we say that and this,
and of all of these,
just all the values we
would have had before.
But he's making Haskell,
write it out as a formula
rather than computed.
So that's the hydrogen,
right? Something like that.
And then have a way of solving it
that will allow us
to solve Sudoku.
What I've done is to
take from two slides ago
and on the bottom
from one slide to
go from two slides ago,
we were checking
from one side to go.
We were changing that
into will construct
an expression with variables
in translating this checker,
do a logical specification
that will give us a huge number,
8 thousand or more clauses
in an expression is a
form in this language,
and we'll come back to it.
But basically, we will
then have a number
of assertions like that that
we want to solve simultaneously.
So we want to find
a model in which all of
these are valid and will
develop the ideas working
with a tiny example
with four or five letters
and four clauses.
But the ideas will translate
into code that runs
efficiently on 300 letters
and 8 thousand clauses.