We will have a
number of assertions
like that that we want
to solve simultaneously.
So we want to find
a model in which all
of these are valid,
will develop the ideas
working with a tiny example
with four or five letters
and four clauses.
But the ideas will translate
into code that runs
efficiently on 300 letters
and 8 thousand clauses.
So we got this.
And really what we
want to do is to find
a state such that this
is universally valid.
What delta could
do this and this,
and this, and this.
Once we know that delta
will say something like
a is true and B is false
and something else.
And that's enough to
show this is happening.
Let's see what might happen.
But rather than try
every delta which says,
I misstate, I give a value
to every one of your
propositional letters.
That's what the state does.
States as this one's true,
this one's false, that's
when true, this one's false.
These valuations don't
have to say everything.
I can just say something
and leave the rest unsaid.
That won't give us a solution,
but it often gives us a way
of simplifying the problem.
So we're going to start by
adding one literal at a time.
So what would happen
if I put a here,
then I be looking for a
delta that works with these,
put a comma delta,
see what happens.
So I'm going to leave
the deltas out because
they get in the way.
But that's really a gel to
that where we might add more.
Can we simplify any of these
expressions using reduction?
How about this one?
How would you simplify
that using reduction?
It's immediate.
How will we simplify this
one using reduction?
There's only a No.
The only thing here
is what role will
be apply and what
would that give?
This is a set. So
what would that give?
This is a set where I have
2a is it's the same as 1A.
So I could take this a over to
the left and I only have
one a e. So I've got this,
I got this, and these
two have disappeared.
We've seen two cases here.
One is, if not a occurs
on the right here,
we choose to make a true
ten knots disappears,
but it is just one
of the rules we had.
If a occurs on the right and
we choose to make a true,
we no longer lead that rule.
There is a third case.
Finally, if a doesn't
occur at all and that
one is unchanged.
So if I decide to make a true,
then I can solve the
simpler problem of
finding a valuation
that makes this true.
But I've already gel with a,
so I don't have to
worry about that.
I just need to find values
of a, b, c, d, e, f,
g. The rest of the
letters make this true.
So in order to simplify
a set of clauses,
we can choose some literal,
choose to make it true,
and then reduce the problem
to one that doesn't
involve that literal.