Good morning. Today and tomorrow,
we're going to look
at an algorithm
that was developed just
before the Beatles.
In those days, computers were
roughly 30 thousand times
slower than they are today.
So when that algorithm
was developed,
it would take about 30
hours to do what we
can do in a couple of seconds
with the same algorithm today,
we'll see later on,
this algorithm will solve
a Sudoku problem in
just over two seconds.
There's a list of roughly 50
thousand Sudoku problems,
which it'll work through
in about 30 hours.
No supercomputers, just a
six year-old laptop
conduit in about 30 hours,
all 50 thousand back
in the sixties,
it would have taken
those 30 hours
to do one of those problems.
So when they develop this,
it was quite something.
Suddenly you had a
computer that could do
Sudoku problem almost as
fast as a very stupid human.
Nowadays, we have a
computer that can do so
GOP Sudoku problems much
faster than any human.
But before we get
onto that algorithm,
I just want to go back
and do a little recap
of where we're at now
because we're changing gear,
we're going from looking at
Logic is something out there
to locate logic as something
we really implement on computer.
Just to summarize
what we've done so
far, we introduce predicates.
Along with syllogisms, we
have a universe of things.
A predicate is something which
is true of some things
and false of others.
In other words, it's a function.
From things to Boolean.
We define what it means for every
a to satisfy B or every a is b.
And we had this whole
theory of Syllogisms,
which was really to do with
either negating the bee
that only gating the
satisfies relation.
And we got all of Aristotle's
theory of syllogisms.
But then we introduced
operations on predicate,
which if you think of the
predicate as a set of things,
the operations like
intersection and union.
But we express them as
operations on functions.
And now we have the
lambda notation.
We can express those
functions like this,
which may make it a
little less mysterious.
Why we have something with
two arguments that
returns one thing here,
because we put the x over that.
That's just a notation you didn't
have when we first
introduce those,
this was the theory
of syllogisms.
We found ways of saying
that this one is valid,
then that one's valid or this
one's valley going
from one to another.
That is the things you
should be able to do.
We found ways of showing,
if I present you with
something that's
invalidate the purports
to be a syllogism.
You can actually use
Venn diagrams to
create a counterexample and
show that it's invalid.
Then we extended that
definition by saying
instead of having one thing on
either side of the turnstile,
we can have a finite
set of thing,
But we defined what
this means for
finite sets in terms of
its meaning for a simple
predicate on either side,
we said if we take the
intersection of all of these,
satisfies the union
of all of those.
In other words, if every
one of these is true,
then at least one
of these is true,
then that was the relation
between finite
sets, a predicates.
And we also can define
these functions.
The end over a number
of predicates and the,
or our number of
predicate in Haskell.
Again, using lambda notation,
it might make it clearer once
you've got your head around
lambda notation than it was
when we put the x back here,
gamma satisfies delta if for
everything in the universe,
if every gamma we have this,
then one of the
deltas we have that.
Then for that relationship,
we have these rules.
And that's still a
bit of confusion
about these rules which
I'll try and get round.
So this gamma here is a set of
things that things I don't
particularly care what
they are at the moment.
Similarly, delta, I don't
care what they are.
I've chosen one thing on
the left which happens
to be a disjunction.
And then this rule
will apply to say that
this satisfaction relation
is equivalent to this one.
And this one, if I just say gamma
entails delta than
gammas are set here,
the things on the
left has to be a set
that we call gamma together
with one more member.
It's still a set on the left.
So you have to think gamma ray
sometimes standing for
everything on the left,
sometimes everything
on the right.
But if I write this,
it standing for
everything except the
things I talked about.
And there's been some confusion,
but the delta is everything,
but it's not always
everything here.
It's everything except the IOP
here it's everything
except the not
a on the right here it's
everything because I don't
mention anything else.
If you have problems with that,
bring it up your tutorial
and make sure you've
got that sorted out.
When we apply those rules,
we choose a main connective.
Here there's only one choice
because there's only one thing.
Its main connective is here.
When I apply a rule to this,
then there's nothing on the left.
So this matches the rule,
but with gamma being
the empty set,
with delta being the empty set.
And this just being
this, all this.
And it in fact matches
the rule or on the right,
when I go up here,
in this case, I match with
this gamma is then this
piece, just a singleton.
Delta is these two things.
And we apply the rule
when I do this one.
Gamma is to be the gamma
because these are sets.
The gamma doesn't have to be on
one particular side of
the thing you've chosen.
This is something I've chosen
and the rest is gamma.
here. The B is the gamma.
So when you're doing
those matchings,
the order in which the
B and the gamma come.
The B might be in the middle.
Nine gamma rays to
all the other things.
When you do the matching,
I think you're all
able to make these
inference trees now,
certainly all the tutorials
I was looking and I
looked in quite a few people
were managing to make those.
That's the important
thing provided you
can actually
operationally to this,
you are at least 80%
of the way there.
And if you're 80% of the
way there on everything,
you might get 80% in the exam.
And if you get more
than 80% in the exam,
then you are doing
extremely well anyway.
So don't worry if you're
only getting 80%.
Here. We had two examples.
We reduced a sequent to
something simpler. In the US.
One, we reduced it to saying,
nothing needs to be true in
order to make this true.
In other words, this
is universally valid.
Here, we reduce this
to saying this is
equivalent to this
and this being valid.
And just that simple
operation or procedure of
reducing a sequence to a
set of simple sequence,
where simple just means
there's no notes,
no one's, there was no bats.
We use that reduction to
Shell things a universally
valid if everything goes via
the immediate r2 to
provide counter-examples,
it not everything goes
by the immediate rule,
but also in the tutorial
you used to compute.
Left and right rules.
The other connectives,
you use them to derive
lots of equations between
Boolean expressions,
which I'll put up
on the next slide.
And you use them to convert
an expression to a
conjunctive normal form
suggests it's one
reduction process.
Lets you do all those
different things and
the rules of Boolean
algebra that you checked.
I think we gave all of these,
but if we didn't
give all of these,
you can check the others,
the Boolean operations AND,
and OR are associative.
We had these two distributive
laws. They're commutative.
That means that X or Y
is the same as y or x.
You know that we've shown that
it follows from the rules.
We have these what
are called unit,
the units XOR 0 is x,
x and one is x when you're
using things like AND,
and OR with fold,
then these units, which
are true and false,
are very useful things
because when you're
doing fold of an operation,
you often want a unit
for that operation.
Apply in the base
case, annihilation,
these ones annihilate what comes
0 and anything just
kills the neat
it's called annihilation
pick dramatic item
potent every ten x or x, it's x.
And if we take x and x is x,
and the compliments that x or
not x is true and x
and not x is false.
This one you probably
haven't seen
and it's sometimes useful and
it's worth looking at this.
If you take x or x and y,
where x and y gets
smaller than x,
if you take x again and OR it
with it, you get back to x.
So x or x and y as x.
And similarly x and x or y
is x going the other way.
So those are all things
you might ponder over.
We would expect you
to know most of them.
Use reduction, using
Jensen rules to do
all these things show
the universal validity,
provide counter-examples.
Compute DLR rules, convert to
CNF derived Boolean equations.
But there's one kind of
example I haven't shown you.
I want to give you the simplest
example of this example.
What happens if we reduce
this using the rules?
What rule applies?
There is only one
connective at the top here.
The end rule applies.
If I have a and B on the
right of the turnstile,
we split with I turnstile
a end-to-end style be
to show that a and B,
you show a and you Shelby,
that we need to show that.
And that. Now what
that tells me is,
it's easy to make
a counterexample.
To make a counterexample
either make
this one false or I
make this one false.
Either way, it's
a counterexample.
In fact, everything's
a counterexample that
it's impossible to
find an example.
We can't find something that
makes one of these true,
which means make this true
and makes one of these true.
So if we took
a much more complicated
thing on the bottom,
we would get to a cnf up the top.
And using that CNF,
we could have a counterexample to
the universal validity
of what we started from.
But we don't know that what
we started from his satisfiable.
This is the simplest example
to show that we don't,
we don't know it's satisfiable.
We may have these huge
cnf and we think,
yeah, if I make that one false,
I've got a counterexample
that's easy.
It's easy to make them false.
But how do we find
evaluation that makes all
of these things up the top true?
In other words, how
do we find evaluation
makes our initial thing true?
It might just be like this
one, a contradiction.
That's what the algorithm
we're going to look at.
Does. It says, When
you've reduced something
to cnf or maybe produced it
in the first place as a cnf.
Then how do you look for
a satisfying valuation?