As I've said before, going
to apply this to sudoku,
does this problem
have a solution?
Some ways of putting numbers in,
in a Sudoku board will
not have any solution.
You can't fill in
the other places
such you got a solution.
For instance, if I
put a four here,
you know that you can complete it
because you've already
breaking one of the rules.
The rules are the same.
Digit doesn't occur
twice in any row,
but it does occur once.
In other words, it occurs
exactly once in any row.
It occurs exactly
once in any column.
And it occurs exactly once in any
one of these big squares.
That's the rule.
And we using the digits
one to nine to fill it in,
satisfying those rules,
it's perfectly possible.
Put in a collection things that
amongst themselves
satisfy the rules.
They don't break the rules yet,
but such that there's no
way of solving the problem.
Because everywhere you try,
you just can't do it. Does this.
Sudoku problems have a solution?
We're going to do this.
We'll produce cnf.
It's called Sudoku, which
says and of Rs where Rs,
lots of clauses, constraints,
disjunctions all
mean the same thing.
A real list of clauses,
the end of them expresses
the rules of Sudoku.
And I showed you
a couple already.
If I want to say that every
square is filled, then I say,
and overall the squares
or over the ones,
the nines and overall squares
gives me some i's and j's.
I and j, both of them
coming from 0 to nine.
And then o, k,
one of the case is
in this position.
So we express the rules of
Sudoku by saying that
and other pieces.
And then we'll have a cnf saying,
this is the problem
that we'll just say
there's a seven in the squared
as an eight in the square,
there's a two in the square.
So that's very easy to translate.
So we've got the rules of
Sudoku and the problem.
And then we put together the end
of all the rules and all the
things that the problem.
And we say, can I solve that?
We're going to give a version
of this algorithm D PLL,
which dates to 1962,
back when solving Sudoku
with it would've
taken about 30 hours.
On modern hardware, it can solve
Sudoku problems with 10
thousand, by the way.
Only recently
learned about these.
But as a national does an
international standard
for powers of two to the ten.
So 100 into four is
a natural number.
It's a natural, natural number
to use often in computing.
Because if you have ten bits,
then you have 1024 possibilities.
So often when we say we've
got a megabyte of memory,
we don't mean we've got
a thousand bytes memory.
I sorry, a million
bytes of memory.
We may, we've got 1024 times
1024 times whatever
bytes of memory.
Okay? So we use those as sort of
like kilo and mega,
but they're binary.
So there's actually,
this is pronounced KB.
Apparently, KI means kilo,
but with 1024 now, 13 zeros.
Okay, anyway, that wasn't aside,
or Madonna or reddish can
solve a Sudoku problem very
easily in a couple of seconds,
modern SAT-solvers lift.
And this changed
about 20 years ago.
20 years ago, there was
suddenly a renewed interest
in SAT-solvers because
Intel built a chip,
had a mistake in it,
and it cost them billions
of pounds because it
costs an awful lot to
produce the masks for chip.
And then recall it might
the Mosque and it's,
it's really quite amazing
the amount of upfront
money you have to put
in to make chips that are very
cheap because you
make so many of them,
but you putting millions
of pounds to get setup,
Intel had a problem.
They really didn't
have any good way of
checking that design to check
that they wouldn't have
similar problems in the
future until people started
realizing that using kind
of algorithms we're
now talking about,
you could do it, but
then it became important
to make them faster
in the late nineties.
And until now there have been
huge improvements going back
to what was there in 1962.
So the general problem
is called SAT,
it's boolean
satisfiability problem.
If I give you a cnf,
is there a state
that satisfies that?
For the Intel example,
we want to make sure
nothing goes wrong.
We want to do it in
reasonable time.
Practical applications,
fabrication of
hardware, software,
finite state machines,
communication protocols,
also used in AI planning.
When you're trying to do a plan,
you're not an express
what you're trying to do
using logic and then
solve a SAT problem.
And even in things like genomics,
where you want to find
out what combinations of
genes go together to form
things called haplotypes,
which I don't really
understand, but sat helps.