To introduce the
algorithm will go back to
the simple example that we were
looking at at the end
of last time, we said,
suppose that we've started
from here and we've
arrived at cnf server
some places we had
the immediate rule,
but up here, here, here and here,
we actually get the everything on
the right version
of a simple rule.
In other words, you've just
moved everything over because it
shows us what the
disjunction looked like.
So that says this is valid if and
only if I can find something
that this or this,
or this and this, or this,
or this and this,
or this or this and
this or this or this.
So that reduces this problem
of finding something
that satisfies
this problem of
finding something that
satisfies the associated CNN.
And I have put up a little
bit of this before.
I'm going to, it's very hard to
describe algorithms in
words, it's possible,
but it's much easier
to describe them in
a language designed for
describing algorithms.
The language you're learning
right now is Haskell.
So we're going to
use that language to
describe and in fact to
implement the algorithm,
we want to make a cnf,
something we can
manipulate in Haskell.
So we want a data type
of things that a CNF,
so a clausal forms,
I use the word form.
So we have roles than
disjunctions of lists
of literals or closes,
and conjunctions of lists
of clauses or forms.
Because we got lots of
lists of things around.
And we've already seen
with the example of
the empty set a few lectures ago.
If we use the same
thing to represent what
a really two different
kinds of things we can
get into knots if
we confuse them.
So to stop ourselves
confusing these lists,
we could say, well,
these are lists of literals
and these are lists of clauses.
But it's helpful sometimes to,
to remind ourselves
that we think this
is an or and this is an end.
New type is just like
theta except when you're
only doing one constructor,
one argument, it's a bit
more efficient to do this.
There are other issues about it
that you probably
learn about later.
A literal is either an atom said
positively or an atom
said negatively.
Our atom are going
to be things like S,
i, j, k, where S i,
j and k for the Sudoku
problem may in square i j,
we have the entry k Am I
won't say it's true that
will write it positively.
When we want to say it's false
that will write it negatively.
And then there's a
negation von literals,
which says the negation
of saying something
positively is saying
it negatively,
and the negation of net saying
negatively, saying it positively.
Now for this little
example that I am doing,
instead of having all 729
propositional variables
that we'll have to sudoku,
we'll just have these eight
just to do these examples.
So now I'm taking these things as
an example of a conjunction
of disjunctions.
And actually there's
a point to make here.
Someone on Piazza asked a
very reasonable question.
Why is d count as a disjunction?
We don't write it
as a disjunction.
Maybe I should put
brackets round.
It's a disjunction of one thing.
When I say a disjunction
of literals,
one literal is a
disjunction of itself.
We also consider the
empty set of literals,
which will be very
important as we go on.
And then a valuation.
I'm not going to
decorate this one.
Evaluation is a list of literals.
What we're going to look for
a list of literals here,
which will say
something like a is
positive, v is negative,
c is positive, such
that if I make a true,
be false and C true,
then I make this thing.
In other words, we are
looking for a list of things.
When I say a in my evaluation,
it means i is true.
When I say not a
in my evaluation,
that means a is false in
terms of the sequence.
It means we put the
valuation on the left of
the turnstile and the thing
we're looking at on the right.
And if these things,
if this is true, this
is false, this is true.
Whatever makes this true
than we've satisfied it.
That's what satisfies means.