Searching for a consistent
set of literals such
that this set of literals
gamma makes this true,
makes this true, makes this
true, makes this true.
In other words, makes one
of these, one of these,
one of these, and one of these,
because they're on the right.
So what could you say?
There are 32 possibilities
which I don't want to go through.
But what if I say, let's
choose one literal.
Let's make a true.
What happens to these?
If I make a true,
what can we say?
The way we approach
that is to say,
let's replace gamma
that we had before,
which was something I
know nothing about with
a followed by some other things.
And it will list, you'd
say x followed by xs,
where we're looking at the exit,
the beginning, we're looking
at the a at the beginning.
We said there's a
at the beginning.
If I know there's an
a at the beginning,
what can I put up here
that is simpler than
what's down here?
And hopefully your memories
might go back to last Friday.
I already showed you this once.
We're going to have to
show you it three times.
So you remember, I
suppose if I do this,
what can I do with this?
Not a, what rule can I
apply to this node a?
I can not on the right,
which moves it over to the left.
If I move it to the
left and I've got,
it looks as though I've got 2A
is on the left. This is a set.
So actually when I move it to
the left, I just get that.
And I could just as
well cross it out.
Similarly here I can
cross this one out.
What about this rule?
What do I put above the line?
Nothing, right?
It's the immediate row.
Nothing above the line.
So this will be much
simpler above the line.
I've moved this eye across it got
absorbed that because two
ways it's the same as 1A.
I move this across.
It got absorbed
because two A's is the
same as 1A and these
two disappear.
All I need to do now is
to solve this problem.
Because solving this
problem is equivalent.
If I'm making a true to
solving the original problem,
did I make this step?
What's the argument to say?
Actually, all I need to
do is to find a gamma
that satisfies not PC and a
gamma that satisfies DRF.
I don't need to worry
about anymore. Why not?
Pi construction?
I've got rid of all the A's here,
so there aren't
always on the right.
So the value of a,
it doesn't make
any difference to whether
something's satisfies this.
So now I've reduced the
problem of finding a,
deciding that a should be
true and finding a gamma
that together with a
will make all of these
true to the problem of
finding a gamma that makes
these true and makes these true.
And then I put the a
back on the beginning.
We're trying to find,
we decide it will make a true.
We're trying to find a gamma that
together with they will work.
We've reduced it to just
finding a gamma here.
By now, the problem
is simple enough.
You should be able to
solve it in your heads.
How can I find a gamma that
satisfies both this and this?
I can see four ways of doing it.
How many ways can I find
them making this true?
Either I make be false or I
may see true in either case,
if I make not p true here,
then not B will be true that
if I make Nazi true here, sorry,
they make ZI true here and
see it'll be true that,
so in either case I can
finish it off just by
making either be false or true.
Similarly here I finish it off
by making de true or true.
And because I've got
two choices here,
two choices that there's four
ways of making this true.
So I could list all
four of those paths,
not BD, not PF, CD, CF.
And for each of the
micro put an a on
the beginning and we
would have discovered
the IRR precisely for
wages of making this
possible staff true.
When we choose to make a true,
we're also interested
in what might
happen if we made a false
naught a and gamma,
we've got the
immediate rho naught
a and gamma naught a and gamma,
we can absorb the eye.
So this is similar
to what I did last
time when I had the
a is underneath,
except that this time
these two things survive.
This time, how many ways we
have of making this true?
How many ways we have making
these two true as it three,
I think it's 21 is we make p
true once we might be
true, table's true.
And the other one is we
make a truancy false.
We don't need to
say anything about
P naught being true.
So I think it's 23.