And what we've done is to
say that if a happens,
then we take all of these things
and we reduce them to
the simpler thing.
If not a happens,
then we take all of
these things and we
reduce them to these two things.
That tells us that if
we take a less clauses,
then the models of these clauses,
this is just translating,
hopefully what we have
here, not a, not B,
C and a and VPC not a,
D, F and a PD PDF.
So negative a positivity
positive f, that's our form.
And the work we've
just done tells us
that if I say make a true
positive a together with the
models of these two clauses.
So that says the
models of these two,
those are the four models that
we talked about
three minutes ago.
Or put a false together with
a model that comes from.
And we already worked
out that there were
two models that we did
that in our heads.
But in software, we
do that recursively.
Say, if I have
something that takes
the models of a list of clauses
using some kind of atoms,
then the models
that we get can be
divided into the ones
that make a true,
and then models for the simpler
thing and the ones that
make a false and then models
for this simpler thing.
So in order to turn
that into an algorithm,
we need to write something,
a little program that
says what happens when I
take a set of clauses
here and make a false.
And then I want to
know what the things
I get up here are.
What set of clauses I get that,
and what happens if I make a
true? What happens up there?
In general, if I take a
literal and a set of clauses,
what happens, flat
set of clauses,
if I make this literal true,
it's either a positive
or a negative,
a, or positively or negatively.
I mean, all the literals count
will start on the implementation.
What I want you to
have in your heads
is I can take any set of clauses,
I can take any literal,
and I can make that
set of clauses
simpler by making
that literal true,
like make it simpler another
way by making that
literal false, if I,
first of all, we'll
make that literal true,
make it simpler and
solve that problem.
Then I find the valuations
that make those true.
And then I also take a
simplification, making it false,
take the solutions for that and
put a negative on the
beginning of those.
So we've divide and conquer.
We've made it simpler in one
way, simpler another way,
we've solved the two
simpler problems
and put the thing back together.
That's a hugely important
way of solving problems
in computing so many times you
will do a divide and
conquer algorithm.
And this is just a
good example of it.
You take a problem,
you find a way of making it
into two simpler problems.
Such that if you solve
the two simpler problems,
you have a way of putting
those solutions back
together to solve
the bigger problem?
Ask yourself again,
can you find a model
with a true say you go up the
top there and you say Yes,
I can find 1234 models on the top
that you should be able to find
four models that make this true.
Can you find a model that
make not a true here?
We can find two models
that make not a true.
So can you find all
models for the original?
Yes. You take these
four models and put
a on the beginning
because these four models
only tell you about
things other than a,
you take these two models
and put north I on the beginning.
So altogether we will get
six models for this thing.
What I'm asking you
here is to find them.
So list out six.