Are there any questions?
No. Okay. I'll a couple
of people came up
with really good
questions last time
that I'm sure would have
confused other people.
So I will remind you,
if you have a question,
do not save it till after class.
Ask it in class if you're
confused about something,
surely there are other people
confused about the same thing.
If you will help them and
help yourself and help
me if you ask questions and
somebody now has a question.
Okay, so the question
is how do you write
a Haskell program that
returns prime numbers?
So you can, to check if
a number n is prime,
you can just count
from two up to n minus
one and check whether any of
those things divide and evenly.
So you just check whether,
so for d drawn from two up to n,
is n div and mod d equal to 0.
If so, it's not prime.
So you could use and
to work that out.
And then, and then
you can just check each
number to see if it's prime.
That's not the most efficient
way, but that works.
There's also something called
the sieve of Aristophanes.
Aristophanes, which you can
write in Haskell in
a really cool way
because the SIV is about
taking the infinite list of
all numbers and then crossing
out all the ones
that aren't prime.
And I'll let you look
that went up online.
So sieve of Aristophanes is
your friend if you want
to do primes in Haskell.
Okay. Any other questions?
Yes. Can you use map,
filter and fold for?
So typically use a
lambda to provide
an argument to map
or filter or fold.
So are you asking in
the body of a lambda,
can you write map filter or fall?
Right in the body of a lambda?
You put a term.
I will now tell you something
that's worth jumping up and down
about anywhere you
can my DU term,
you can write head term.
In other words, there
are no restrictions,
so anything can go in there
including map, filter and fold.
But this idea that things are
uniform, that you don't say.
You can write some things here
and some other things here,
and some other things here.
And we have lots of
different special cases.
That's not what you do.
You are trained in
informatics and you
understand that uniformity
and simplicity are a virtue.
So use the same thing everywhere.
Wherever a term can appear,
a term can appear and you
don't have arbitrary
restrictions on.
Thanks. That's a really
important design principle.
So does that answer
your question?
Great.
Yes.
Okay. So you're
noting that the class exams,
the past ones that you've seen,
all begin with a paid saying.
Here are some library functions
you might want to use.
And your question is,
could I use some other
library function?
I wouldn't recommend it.
But I put there the stuff that I
think you should know about.
So you might know
about something else
and it might be legitimate
library function.
And they'll have to go,
what on earth is this?
And tried to mark things if you
want to stick to the stuff
that your markers will
know and understand,
stick to the given
library functions.
Yes. You know,
you can use map and
filter and especially for
the question that says use
map and filter to do this.
Okay? Other questions?
Yes. Is there a
simple explanation
for recursive data types?
So you didn't understand
the recursive definition
of the natural numbers.
Right? So the data type
list of a's defined in
terms of the data type
list of a, right?
You saw that way back,
not to us yesterday.
You also saw it yesterday.
But we we explained
that right back.
My first explained head and tail.
I said the tail of a list
of a is also a list of a.
So we'll see some recursive
data types today.
Let's see if that sort you out.
Okay, so the question is,
I'm confused about
recursive data types.
Let me just check
how many people feel
they've completely understand
recursive data types.
Okay, I'm not sure whether
I should raise my hand.
There are not. How
many people feel
that they are somewhat
confused about
recursive data types,
right? You have lots of company.
So let me give you
another example of
a recursive data type
and let me see if that
helps bring it home because
recursion is one of
the most important
ideas in the course.
So it is important that you
become familiar with it.
But I understand, right?
You have to see a few examples
before it gets driven home.
So let me give you
another example.
So that's the perfect
introduction to today's talk,
which is about expression trees,
which are an example of
a recursive data type.
Ok. So here's the data
to a very simple data
type of expression trees.
So we've got three things.
An expression is either a
literal which has
one thing inside it,
which is an int, or an ad,
which has two things inside it,
which are both
themselves expressions.
Or a multiply which has
two things inside it,
which are both
themselves expressions.
Okay. And notice, right,
this is an instance of the
principal I just described,
which is everywhere in
expression can appear and
expression can appear.
So an expression is one
of these three things.
And then two of them
are themselves built up
out of the exact same
expression type.
So that may seem strange,
but let me show you
some things you
can do with the expressions.
So the first thing is
you can evaluate it.
So if you evaluate an expression,
you get back x.
Actually, let me, let's
just have a look
at phase so that we
can see some examples.
Alright, so I've already loaded
up this definition, right?
It's the exact same definition.
So what are some
examples of expressions?
So somebody give me an
expression using this type.
Yep. Let, yeah, 0.
Good. Somebody else
give me an expression.
And what does that rep,
which expression does that
represent? The number 0.
Ok, somebody else give
me an expression.
Sorry. Let five, good.
Yep. Add let 0.
Lead to good. When more,
Yep. Negative one, good.
One more.
Yep. Mole. Let minus1.
Let negative too.
Good. Another one.
Really big one.
Yep.
So if is
a thing we've got in Haskell,
but it's not a thing we've got
in these expressions, right?
We've only got, LET
add mode for you.
What are you trying to write?
A Haskell turn that
returns an expression.
Ok, so what Haskell term
do you want to write?
If
let
something in something,
okay, let m
n
i in brackets.
Yeah. So what do
you want me to write
between the brackets?
If The function.
What? Email export.
No, we haven't talked
about yet you're not
allowed to use it.
Right? Just using
LET, ad and mol.
Let's write down a large term.
Mall.
Good, add, lit.
Forty-two, Good choice.
And let 0. Okay, good.
Now we've got two functions here.
One of these is this beginning
to become clear to people.
Right? So one of these takes
an expression and
returns its value,
is given an expression,
I can always get a
number out of it.
So if it's a literal
and that's easy,
just returned liberal n. If it's
an add of two
expressions, E and F,
then what we're
going to do one way,
if it's an add of two
expressions, E and F,
then what we're going to do
is recursively evaluate E,
recursively evaluate f, And
what shall I do with them?
Oh, it's called add.
Why don't I add them together?
And similarly for multiply,
we will recursively evaluate
the first one and
evaluate the second one.
And it's called multiply,
so we will multiply
them together.
Okay? Now there's other one,
converts an expression to a
string so we can look at it.
So LET event just shows n,
convert the number n to a string,
add E of f recursively showy.
Then put a plus sign
and recursively show f,
and put some parentheses
around the whole thing.
Multiplies the same.
Showy, then show at times symbol,
then show f, and
recursively put parentheses
around the whole thing.
So let's give some, let's see
some examples of how those work.
Whoops. Go back here.
So the thing that we last had,
Whoops, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Go over here, right? The thing
we last had is called yet.
So I'm just going to type it up.
No. It reloaded it.
Okay. That's okay. There we go.
Here's the last thing we had.
So that's just that.
But I could show
exp of, well, wait,
let's do escape P. And
then I write show XP
around that whole thing.
What am I going to get?
But find out? Let's see.
Is it I'm doing show.
Ok. So why do these three things?
Let DO is an ad is more
or less same as ad,
bc, mole add or
they use the same.
They might be, let's
see. Oh no, they're not.
No, not the same.
Okay. Mole and mole
are the those are the
same. They're the same.
It's this one. It's this one.
Ok. So e is going to be
the first thing after
the mole that's ad of
let phi and lit for,
okay, that e and f is going to
be add of LET 42 and let 0 could.
So now I'm gonna do par of
show extra B and then a times,
then show exp of F. Okay.
Well I got to work out
what your extra V as ok,
so e was add 54.
So let see.
So that'll let know, is it an ad?
It isn't that it is an AD.
So e is going to be five and
f is going to be let
for, oh, you know what?
Haha, ungraded cheat.
I'm just going to
ask the computer.
Right? So that gives five
plus four. Again, why?
Well, because first,
we look at which line it is
and it's the AD line again.
So what's E going
to be this time?
E will be lit five and
F will be lit for.
So we can just do
show exp of those.
So show XP, flip five,
does all the
parentheses are needed.
That's the string five.
Right? So it takes a number
to a string using show
because that's what
this line says to do.
And LET four, what's that
going to be? The string for?
And so now we show those, right?
Then it says it's that
plus that, plus that,
which is five plus four,
and then it's par of that,
which puts parentheses around it.
Okay? So this is why if we
look at the whole thing,
we get five plus four
and then two times,
and then 42 plus 0.
Everything in parentheses
is that clear to everybody?
And then similarly
we can evaluate it.
Escape. So now instead
of show What I'm
gonna do eval exp,
and what's that going to return.
So five plus four is what?
42 plus 0 is what?
And nine times 42 is.
Let's find out what
nine times 42 is.
It's 378. Ok. Is that
clear enough to people?
Do you understand how these
expressions are working?
Okay, and you were worried
about recursion before.
Do you understand it
a bit better now?
And notice we already learned
about recursive functions.
Notice recursive types and
recursive functions go together.
Right? So here the bits
of an ad are both
themselves expressions.
The bits of a mole are both
So when we're doing an ad,
right, e is going to
be an expression,
f is going to be expression.
Somehow. We need to turn this
expression into a number.
Oh wait, that's exactly
what eval exp is.
Four. So I can find e
val exp of add a, v,
and f in terms of
eval exp of the e and
e val exp of that.
And again, this works just
like with lists, right?
With lists, you always go
to the tail of the list.
Here we're always going either to
the left subtree or
the right sub tree.
So the tree we're acting
on always gets smaller.
And with lists, you
always eventually reach a
base case which is nil.
And here again, we eventually
reach a base case,
which is the lit case.
Okay? So here are two examples
that I've already run.
So IO is add of two to
multiply three with three.
And e one is multiply add of Lit
two and let three with three.
So that means if we show E 0,
we get open parenthesis two plus
open parentheses
three times three,
close parenthesis,
close parenthesis.
But if we do show y1,
right will get open paren,
open paren 2x plus three
close paren times
three close friends.
You see how E0 and E1 correspond
to these two strings.
Is that clear to everybody?
So some people are nodding
and most people are
going to occur.
So I've asked you to do want to
thank them to look
around the room.
And I want you to either
nod as in yes, I'm bored.
That's completely obvious.
Fill or I want you to raise
your hand and ask a question.
Ok? Do one of those two things.
If you don't know
what question to ask,
you may ask the
following question.
What question should I ask?
That's OK. And then we'll
go on to get somebody else
in the audience to help you
out formulating your question.
But I really want you to do
one of these two things, okay,
so either nod or raise your
hand and ask a question.
So let's startling here.
Are you bored yet?
All right. So far
everybody's normally that
but that guys just
looking at his phone.
Okay. You're just sitting
there with your hands crossed?
The one or the other?
Yes. You nod or raise
your hand or ask
the person next to you what
question you should ask.
Okay. Okay. I'll keep
going around the room up.
Question or question,
shouldn't you ask?
I've no idea. Okay. Let
me keep going round.
People are now look,
if I look at you, please either
not at me or raise your hand.
I'm serious. Good. Yes.
Oh, why did I use plus and times
the built-in ones rather than the
once I defined yesterday,
I could use either one, right?
But they'll work on
different types.
So that was a natural
type, I think I called it.
And these are integers.
So here I've just
decided I'm going to
work with integers, right?
We could do it over
again with like floats.
That would work too. So there's
several different
numeric types and we
get different ones depending
on which one we use.
So here I've decided
it's going to be ints.
And here I've decided
I want to get out and
int by could've
decided say on floats.
That's a good question. Good.
Yep. Why do order of operations?
So that was the point I think
that I want to make to you.
So look why both of these are
two and a plus and a
32 times into three.
But they're very
different, right?
This one means first
multiply three
by three and then add two to it.
But this one means add
two to three and then
multiply it by three.
It's not what you meant
by order of operations.
Here. What would happen if I
omitted all the parentheses?
So if I omitted all
the parentheses here,
school will say I
can't parse that.
I've no idea what
you're talking about.
But so you raised
the next point I wanted
to make, so thank you.
Right. Which is write these
in some sense look the same,
but they are very, very
different. Right? Adhere, right?
It's everything in the same order
with just a few
parentheses different.
But if you look here,
right, it's very different.
This says the top level
thing is an ad, right?
This is the top level thing.
This is the most important.
It's an ad. But this
one says no, no, no.
What we're doing is
multiplying things.
So it begins with a
mole. Do you see that?
Actually? Does anybody
have a sheet of paper?
I should. I can I can use
this to show you something,
but I didn't bring
a sheet of paper.
Yes. And does anybody have a ten?
Right. So it's very
health, right?
I called these things trees.
So why are they called trees?
Because the first one looks
like it's a plus on the top.
And then oh,
you want to actually see
what I'm doing as well?
Okay. There we go.
It's a plus on the top.
And then this is a
two and this is at
times, and this is 33.
And the other one is
at times on the top.
And then a plus here,
and then a two, and then a
three. And then a three.
So those are illustrations
of the first expression
and the second expression,
or the first expression
and the second one.
So this one is E 0.
And this one is He wants,
you can draw them as trees.
Now, notice, right, all this is,
we call this data
structure a tree,
and we draw it like that.
And you know, so that
what this means is you
should all now do a
head stand, right?
Because you need to
look at them like
that to understand
why it's a tree.
Are trees grow from the
top down rather than
every tree in real life which
grows from the ground up.
Okay. But these are called trees.
And does that visualization from
the tree help people write?
It helps me a lot.
And the important thing is,
you can then see
this one has plus at
its root and times in a sub tree,
this one has times at its root.
And plus in a sub tree,
is that clear to everybody?
Okay? So at this point,
you should understand
at least one example
of how recursion works.
And you might not be sure
that you can always make it work.
But you should have some idea
of what's going on here.
Notice, by the way,
when we do lists,
lists are also, they
can be drawn as a tree,
but it's very lopsided.
So here is the list one.
And then the tail of that
is going to have had too.
The tale of that is going to have
three and then the tail
of that is empty, right?
So this is one cons,
two cons, three
cons, empty, right?
Which we also write
as the list 123.
So Lists also are trees,
but they are very lopsided trees.
So now you see two examples of
a recursive data structure drawn
as a tree, lists and expressions.
Okay? And they must be
lossless, lop-sided.
Whereas these can, right,
you've got complete
freedom as to what goes in
either the left subtree
or the right sub tree.
Because the type
declarations are different.
For lists, we said it's a
cons of an a and a list of a.
So those are different types.
Here. It's add of an x and an x,
they are the same type.
Okay? And then indeed,
if we evaluate the first
of these IO, it gives 11.
But if evaluate the
other one, we get 15.
I've just written
these out as a bunch
of equals conjoined together.
But let's just check, right?
If I, oops, I say ten.
Thanks. If I say test XP,
whoops, test underbar XP.
True, right, so all four of
those statements are true.
And that's all there is to it.
Right? If you want to add,
subtract and divide,
you would now know
what to do, right?
Is that fairly clear to people?
Okay. So that's all
there is to at all
you need to know is a white I
defining a thing whose components
are the same sort of thing.
And that's a recursive
data definition.
And therefore I need a
recursive function definition
to act on that recursive data.
So they go hand in hand.
Whenever you have recursive data,
you should have a recursive
function to act on it.
Okay?
Oops, right, so
there's some examples,
but we've been through that.
Now. We can do Haskell's a bit
flexible so we could also write,
instead of writing the ADD
and the model at the front,
we can write them in
between two things.
Between tactics, because Haskell
allows that as an abbreviation.
If you write E back, tick,
add F, that just
stands for add a,
v and f, right?
Just two ways of
writing the same thing.
So here we've just
written the same
thing in a different way.
And so that's fairly
straightforward.
So behaves same way. And also
we can write symbols index.
So remember, this is
a constructor, right?
Add is a constructor,
so it begins with a
capital letter, right?
And even when it appears in fix,
it begins with a
capital letter, right?
Types begin with capital letters.
Constructors begin
with capital letters.
Function names begin
with small letters.
Variable names begin
And that's by the
way, how you can
tell if you're looking
at something like this,
which thing is the constructor,
in which thing is the variable?
Well, if it's a capital
letter, it's a constructor.
If it's a small letter,
it's a variable.
That's why we have
that convention.
But how do you begin
to assemble with
a capital letter? O dare?
So Haskell has this
very weird convention.
For symbols, the capital
letter is colon.
So if you begin with a colon,
You're a constructor and
otherwise you're not.
And the way you can remember this
is the cons is written as
a colon and Collins
is a constructor.
So if you begin with a colon,
You're a constructor and
otherwise you're not
columns by the way,
to say they know what
cons is short for.
Can you guess constructor, right?
Cons is just short
for constructor.
So now we can declare
this by saying x colon
plus xp and x colon times x.
We write cones before and
after to be symmetric.
That's the colon at the front,
that makes it into a constructor.
And then it looks just
like what we did before.
Everything else is the same.
So is that clear to people?
Question. Yep. What about the Oh,
could you write this one
without parentheses?
No. Cuz it well,
how do you tell it
which one binds
more tightly plus or times?
If you write it
without parentheses,
it will make something
up and do it.
But what I recommend is always
put in the parentheses,
so it's absolutely
clear what's going on.
So good question. Is
there another question?
By the way, the technical name
for that is not order
of application.
The technical name for
that is precedents.
Which of these two operators
binds more tightly?
So the answer for
Haskell is if I write,
if I write one,
sorry if I write yet 2x
plus three times three.
What's Haskell going
to return 11 or 15.
11. So in Haskell times binds
more tightly than plus.
Okay. Okay, so now
we're done, right?
And, and the same thing works.
So now when we
write these things,
we can almost read them, right?
This looks almost like
what's supposed to
be which is two plus
three times three.
And this one looks almost
like what's supposed to be,
which is two plus three in
parentheses times three.
So using symbol
infix notation makes
these things close to
something you can actually
read, which is very helpful.
And what we're actually
learning here is how to
define your own small
programming language
within Haskell.
And that's actually
one of the things that
functional programming
languages are best for,
which is often you want to define
your own small language to
express whatever problem
it is you're working with.
And because you can write
things out in this way,
functional languages
are really good for,
excuse me, functional
languages are really good for
writing down definitions
of other languages.
That's one of the
things they're best at.
A small language for a
particular application.
When word for an application
is a domain of application,
which just means a place
where you're doing stuff.
So programming languages for
special applications are called
domain-specific languages.
And the way I like
to explain this is
that functional languages are
domain-specific languages for
defining domain-specific
languages.
So here we can see it's
pretty easy to come up with
a language to
represent expressions.
Now you wouldn't want
just that because you've
already got expressions
in Haskell.
But for other purposes
that will turn out to
be really convenient idea.
So let's do another example.
Something near and
dear to your heart.
Let's write a Haskell program
that can do your CL homework.
Would you like to do that?
We're going to write a
Haskell program that can do
your CL homework for you.
So we're going to use
exactly the same trick.
Right? We're going to define
propositions and we're going
to have just a few kinds.
It's a variable which must
have a name and the name is
just going to be a string.
Or it's false, or it's true.
I've, I, I'm not
spelled these out
because false and true are
already defined for Booleans.
I need to use something else.
I've just used F and T.
Or it's a not of
another proposition.
Or it's an OR oven of
two other propositions,
or an AND of two
other propositions.
And then we've got two
abbreviations will
use names is just going to be
a list of names and we've
got an environment, right?
Because when you are
given a proposition,
if you want to know if
it's true or false,
you'll have to know
for each variable,
is that variable true or false?
So an environment tells
us for each name,
is it true or is it false?
So now, showing a
proposition is easy, right?
If it's variable x,
just write out x.
If it's f, write out F If it's t
right out t. If
it's not right out
until the if it's an or
right out a vertical bar.
And if it's an and write out
an ampersand and all the
rest of this you can see
looks pretty much
exactly like what we
did for numerical
expressions question.
All right, so I've said
here deriving eq and Ord.
So or just means you can do
less than between things.
So this lets you actually compare
these things to see if
one smaller than another.
But I don't, I can't honestly
remember why stuck that
in there. So don't
worry about it.
Iq means we can
compare them to see
if they're the same,
which is useful.
Yep. You can use
less than or equal four implies,
but I'm not doing that here,
so don't worry about that yet.
Yes. Of the particular way 4D
works is it looks at
the order you gave me.
So because I wrote f before t,
F will be less than t and
t will be less than not.
And not will be
less than and, or,
but honestly,
I don't want you to find
less than right now,
so let's not worry
about that one.
Okay? So this just turns
a prop into a string,
very similar to what
we showed before.
This. Now here's
something useful.
What are all the
names mentioned in
a given proposition will
want to make use of that.
So if it's a variable,
x obviously mentions the
name X, so that's easy.
That's f. There are no
names in it. That's easy.
T, there are no names
in it. That's easy.
If it's not p, it will be
whatever variables
appear in p, right?
So it'll be the names of p,
f is p or q.
Then we'll take all the
names and P and add,
append to the list
all the names and q.
Why it might be something
like var x or Var aX.
So that would give the
list that has x in
it twice. And so we apply nub.
Does anybody know what NEP does?
Nub removes repeated
elements from a list.
So I think we can test
this out. Let's try it.
So here we've got
some propositions.
So this is a and B,
or not var a, var b.
And this one is a and naught a.
And here's an
environment which says,
right, we'll look at the summit.
Let's see what happens when
a is false and B is false.
So if we show prop p 0, right?
Does everybody see
why we get that?
And then if we do
show prop of P1,
does everybody see
why we get that?
And then the names
of P are not ABAB,
which is, you might expect,
but just a and B because the knob
gets rid of duplicates, right?
Cuz if we say, actually,
let's write, if I
get rid of the nub,
I get rid of the two
instance of knob.
And then I take
right, which is that.
And I noticed that it
gives me that because
I've said deriving show,
I didn't have that
and the other side,
tell tell you what
we're gonna do here.
We get River or we
don't care about 4D.
We're just going
to deriving show.
We check that didn't
break anything
now that didn't break anything.
So that means I was
never using Ord.
So show is the built in Haskell
show function which
prints out something
exactly the same
way you type it in.
But we've also defined show prop.
So show prop of P is now
going to do it as a string,
which is much more readable.
And now if I do names of
PCR, I got rid of the nub.
So what am I going to get?
I will get a b, a b.
But notice if I take the nub,
well, so if I take the nub of
AB, what am I going to get?
Right? There are no duplicates.
If I take the nub of a, b,
a, b, then it gives me AB, okay?
Or if I take the nub of a,
b, b, a, what do we get?
Will also get AB. So it
goes from the beginning.
So the nub of ABA is ab.
So if you want a more
core rock group,
you should call it ab.
Let's put the nubs back.
And so now if we do names P 0,
right, we'll just get a and b.
And what do I, what will
we get if I do names P1?
So p1 is very and not var a.
And if I do show
prop P1, I get that.
And if I do names
P1, what will I get?
Don't all answer at once.
What will I get if I do names p1,
a, meaning the list
containing the string a.
Okay? So just one
name appears there.
Okay, everybody learn
how names works.
And then the
interesting thing is I
can evaluate a proposition,
but to evaluate it,
I need to know what to
do for each variable.
So the key thing is
if it's a variable,
I look it up in the environments.
And now E ranges not over
expressions but
over environments.
And an environment is
a list of AB pairs.
I give it an a, that's
going to return a b.
How is it going to do that?
It just looks down the list
until it finds one that matches.
So here I've done that
with a comprehension.
So we say form the XP.
Look, look at everything
in this list.
This list of AB pairs.
I'll call it x, y's.
So each thing it, it
is an x prime y pair.
I've already been given acts.
That's what I'm looking for.
So I filter out, I just
have the X Y pairs,
where x and x prime are the same.
I just return the y's
and there really should
be exactly one of them.
So I've got this
function v, right?
So this would be a list of
B. I say note that should
be a list of length one.
Just return that one
thing in the list.
So if I do, let's try this.
So let's let down
here, right? N 0.
N 0 is a list that pairs a
with false and b with false.
And then if I say,
look up a in n 0,
what is it going to return?
False? That's all.
That's very odd.
Yeah, that should work for
that again. Thank you.
Right. It returns
false. Thank you.
Why didn't give me a
type error for that?
I don't know. But there we go.
And if I look up b,
what am I going to get?
Not all at once. Also false.
F, I look up and see
what am I going to get?
It says there is
no c here, right?
Non-exhaustive patterns
in function v. V what?
Oh, wait, these the name
of the function, okay.
Right, so D has been
given here a list of
length 0 and then it gets upset.
So now we can use lookup
to evaluate something.
So if I look up,
right, if I evaluate p 0 and n 0,
what am I going to get?
Where we're going to
get? First, we're
gonna evaluate this
sub term a and
b. Ands that means
first we'll evaluate a and
that will evaluate t2.
We look it up.
False. Now evaluate
b and we look it up and
that gives us false and
false and false is false.
So this gives us false.
And now we'll do this one.
So if we look up our a again,
that is not a false is.
And here we do. We look
up b that's false,
not false is and we,
and true and true
together and we get,
and now we've got false here,
true here false or true
is false or true is true.
So if we try it,
email and 0, p 0,
yes, we get true.
Okay, it's the same thing.
It's just recursively looking
it up for each sub term.
Okay? And also you
could figure out
how to draw these as trees.
The way we drew these,
these as trees, if you want to.
So the last trick
here, we're at time.
But the last trick,
I will not show you in detail
because we're at time,
but you'll get more time
to look at this later.
You can actually generate a list
of all possible environments.
And then you can ask, is there
any environment where
this returns true?
And that's called satisfiability.
Or you can say in
every environment,
does this return true?
That's tautology.
So we'll look at more
detail how to do that.
But you've begun to
see how you can use
these techniques to do
your own homework.
Thank you very much.