Oops.
Okay. I need
to learn properties of functions.
Yes.
That's right, I didn't believe.
Okay. So last time we got
pho this time, right?
And some people said, well,
wait, there's more two-fold.
When that I looked in the book,
there's Fulbright hand foldLeft.
What is the difference?
So the difference is the
way the parentheses go.
So n-fold, right?
This is what we saw last time.
You've got x and then
f, And then folds.
So we put the element
on the left, right,
we take the beginning element,
we put it on the left,
and then we do a fold.
And you can see when
you're all done,
the parentheses
slant to the right.
The other way, what you do
instead is you change this thing,
which is the thing you return
when you reach the empty list.
So you add the CAD
onto the end, right?
Not the beginning, but on the end
of what you get when you
reach the empty list,
if you go through and you
see how that computes,
You see that gives you
the parentheses
slanted to the left.
So that's the reason
for the names fold
right and fold left,
which is one way the parentheses
slant to the right and
the other way they
slant to the left.
Okay. I'll leave you to
play stupid computer and
go through that and
convince yourself that
that's what the definition
of foldLeft does.
You all can do this voice, Yes.
Okay. Because you need that
for playing stupid computer.
Now, notice that
we've got you here.
And I had somebody
say, I shouldn't,
I make it be an error for
the empty list. Well, no.
So this is important.
I will not quite
jump up and down.
It's slam the desk important.
Pay attention to the empty case.
A great way to design
your programs to work
well is they should do the
right thing if given nothing.
So whenever you're given
a problem to solve,
do this thing with a
list, for instance,
sum up all the numbers in a list.
You should think to yourself,
what do I want to do
if I'm given nothing?
Okay? If your program
is given a list
of cost of food and sorry,
items that you might buy at
the store and how
much they all cost.
And you want to
find all the items
that cost less than
a certain amount
and then add that up.
What should it do if there are
no items less than that amount?
It should give you 0.
You want to think through
what's the right thing to do.
In the empty case,
people typically start with ONE.
They begin thinking at one.
Doped, begin thinking at 0.
This is what makes you
somebody who understands
informatics.
If you stunt understand
informatics,
you start thinking at
0 whenever you can.
That's a very important concept.
Make sure the empty
case works well.
Whenever you can.
However, sometimes you can't.
So let's say I give
you again a list
of food items and a
list of their prices.
And I say, give me the
smallest price in the list.
What do you do when it's empty?
Sorry. You stop.
No, there is a smallest
price for everything.
I said, I've got
this wrong, right?
So smith, smallest,
I got it wrong.
For smallest price.
Okay? There is a smallest
price which is 0.
So if you say give
me the largest thing
in the empty list, you
can just return 0.
But if I say give you
the smallest thing,
then you want the
identity for minimum.
And that's plus infinity, right?
What's the minimum of X
and infinity? It's x.
So minimum does not
have a unit unless
infinity as a number.
Maximum over natural
numbers does have a unit.
What's the maximum of x and 0?
It's x, because x
will always be greater
than or equal to 0.
But what if we have
negative numbers as well?
So if we're not looking
at the maximum of
a list of prices,
but a list of
amounts owed which could be
either positive or negative.
Then you need the
maximum of a list
of positive and negative numbers.
And maximum does not have
an identity over
positive and negative
numbers unless again,
you have minus
infinity as a number.
So the maximum of minus infinity
and x will always be Ax.
X is minus infinity.
No, that's okay.
The maximum of minus infinity is
minus infinity and that's x.
So it still works out.
So maximum if minus
infinities and number works.
But if we're looking
at a list of deaths
and you want to
find the largest one
who has the most debt.
And that's going to be
an integer because it might be
positive or negative, right?
You might owe the person
money or be owed money,
then there's no answer
to give unless you
add minus infinity and
plus infinity as numbers.
That's exactly why
people sometimes
do add minus infinity and
plus infinity if numbered.
So that maximum and minimum both
have an identity, a unit.
But in general, they don't.
So sometimes there is no good
answer for the empty list.
Sometimes the right answer
for the empty list is to say,
you should not have
asked me that question.
And generally the way we
do that in Haskell is
we just don't give an
equation defining it.
In which case, when
you run the program,
it says I couldn't
match that pattern.
There is no equation
that applied.
So it gives you an error message.
Or to actually explicitly
give an error message
using Haskell's error function.
But you should do one
of those two things.
So most common is you've got,
you want to have an answer
for the empty list.
It should be the identity of
whatever operation you're using.
But every now and then,
empty list doesn't
make any sense.
So in that case,
we use what's called fold
R1 for list of at
least length one.
And we stop at the list
of length one and we
never give an answer
for the empty list.
So this will then find
the maximum of list of
either positive or negative
numbers where there is
no sensible thing to give
us the unit and fold l,
that's the same thing.
And again, folder are
all the parentheses
go to the right,
fold l, all the parentheses
go to the left.
And again, you can play super
computer and trace those
out and see why they
work the way they do.
Okay, so pulled our parentheses
go to the right, fold l,
they go to the left
and add a one
if there's no sensible
answer for the empty list.
And only do that if you have to.
You will all be
informatics experts.
And that means you
will always consider
the empty case whenever
possible and go only
rule it out if there's
nothing sensible to
do in that case.
Ok. Is that clear
enough? Any questions?
Okay. So let me tell
you a little bit more
about append, right?
You've seen the definition
of append before.
And right here it is much
worse, absolutely, right?
So append of ABC, right?
Sticks the a on the front.
The tail is BC recursively.
Does BC sticks beyond the fret
recursively does see six.
This younger front
recursively does empty
and empty append something
has just the other thing,
so it gives you d. Now,
append has some properties.
So imagine you're at
a party and a mathematical
operator walks up to you.
And you need to make
small talk with
this mathematical
operator. What do you do?
Right? You can't say,
what's your major or what are you
studying because mathematical
operators don't do that.
Or maybe it's obvious,
it's mathematics.
So how do you make small talk
with a mathematical operator?
So mathematical operators
all have properties.
And when you bump
into a new operator,
you can get familiar with it
by asking at what
properties it has.
So we've already learned about
one important property, identity.
But some other properties
are associativity,
commutativity.
If you've got two operators,
you can ask about Distributivity.
You can ask normally doesn't
have an identity, but
does it have at 0?
And you can ask
about item potent.
So let me give quick examples.
These associativity means it
doesn't know which
way the branch,
which way the parentheses goes.
What's an example of an
associative operator?
Multiplication? What's the
identity for multiplication?
One. Is multiplication
commutative?
Yet doesn't matter which
way around you do it.
Is it distributive? It to,
it is it distributes over plus.
So this is a property
of two operators.
Times distributes over
plus. Does it have a 0?
So 0 means something that
behaves like 0 for
multiplication.
So multiplication, 123
times 0 is three million,
six hundred and four
times 0 is right.
It always gives you 0.
So that's called a 0.
It's also sometimes
called an absorber.
And then item potent is something
that if you give it two
arguments the same,
you get back the same thing.
So let's see, two
plus two is four.
No four is different than two.
So addition is not item potent.
Can you name me an operator
that is item potent?
Sorry. Minus two.
Minus two is 00 is not
the same as to well,
one times one gives you one,
but two times two gives you four.
So times is also not item potent.
What's true and true?
Maximum not some of
the great example by
maximum of 4343 is 43.
So maximum is item potent
logical AND is item potent
logical or is item potent?
Minimum? Is item potent.
And he may know
little set theory in
set theory union is item
potent and intersection
is item potent.
So there are several
things that are item
potent but not arithmetic.
So all of these are properties.
I'm not going to go through
them in detail now,
but they are all things that you
should know and
know the names of.
And it's of course not just for
making small talk at parties.
Why is this important?
You might be reading
somebody's documentation and
they introduce an operator.
The first things to ask about
this operator are,
is it associative?
Is it commutative?
Doesn't have an
identity and so on.
Most but not all things
are commutative.
What's an example of
something that some of
you know about that's
not commutative.
Sorry. The cross-product, right?
Cross-product, it no, cross
product is commutative,
but matrix multiplication
is not cross-product visit,
I thought, oh no,
that's different from
dot-product, isn't it?
Right. Cross-product
is an example.
And matrix multiplication
as an example,
matrix multiplication
is associative.
It has an identity,
but it is not commutative
for square matrixes.
So there are various things
that you bump into and
probably those of you that
alert not I know not all of
you know about matrices,
but those of you that do when
you're first taught
about matrices,
probably the first thing you were
taught is it's associative,
but it's not commutative.
If you know little bit
of algebra in groups.
It's the theory of
things that are
associative and half a
unit and have an inverse,
but are not commutative or
may not be commutative.
So, right,
you might want this when
reading somebody's documentation.
You might want it when writing
your own documentation.
These are the things you should
explain about what you're doing.
And you will want it when
reasoning about your programs.
What operators to these, that,
what properties do these
functions satisfy?
That tells you a
lot, for instance,
about what kind of
optimizations you can do.
And I'll talk a little
bit about that today.
So at various points people said,
how efficient is this today?
I'm going to tell
you for one thing,
how efficient it is.
And sometimes making
things more efficient
depends on knowing
its properties.
And I'll give you a hint, right?
Mathematics is a super power.
If you're not afraid to use
a tiny bit of mathematics,
just to say, is this associative?
Does it have an identity?
Does it distribute
over this other thing?
You have special vocabulary
that your colleagues
may not have.
You can see clearly
certain things that
your colleagues
won't know how to talk about.
Mathematics is a
language that let
you understand what's going on.
And there's a fellow
named or both not in,
I think the 15 or 16
hundreds who said,
if you can use mathematics
to understand something
and you don't,
it's as if you're
hunting for something in
the dark and somebody gives
you a candle and you
don't light it, right?
Mathematics is your
Candle in the Dark.
It's a special tool. These days.
With all the Marvel
and DC movies,
we would call it a superpower.
Okay, so,
and here I give some
important reasons
why you want to know if
something's associative.
It means you don't need to worry
about where the parentheses go.
And I'll show you
it actually let you write
some programs go much faster.
So when you do care about speed,
associativity can
be a key to that.
So let's check some properties.
Right? Append is associative,
so that means it doesn't matter
where the parentheses go.
We could run that and quick check
and it would confirm it for us.
Penn has an identity
which is the empty list.
And in fact, it's
both a white identity
and a left identity.
And also another property
is that append and
columns are related.
So if you append a unit list
onto the front of something,
that's exactly the
same as causing
it to the front of a list.
So those are three of the
many properties of append.
Append is not commutative, right?
Adding ABC to DEF gives you
ABCDEF by adding them
the other way around
would give you d abc.
So append is not commutative,
but it is associative.
And we always use infix
notation for append, right?
We write it like this.
And there's a reason
for that because then
when you write out the
associative property,
it looks like this.
It's just the same as defining
this function append,
right, which is prefix.
And look at what happens to this.
So up append xs to the list Ys
appended to zed becomes
append xs, append wise ads.
That's not too bad to read.
But look at what
happens when you put
the parentheses the
other way around.
So first we're taking x's and
y's and we're appending
them to each other.
And then we take the result
of that and append it to z.
So this is really easy to read.
This is much harder to
read even though saying
exactly the same thing.
Right? So associativity
is easy to see here.
Just move the parentheses,
quite hard to see here
the whole structure
appears to change.
This is sort of the reason why
infix notation is a good idea.
Any questions yet?
Not enough questions odor.
And now I'll actually
tell you something
about efficiency.
So right when we add abc
to the front of DE, right,
there's one step to
stick the a there,
one step to stick the B,
one step to six C. And
then finally we stopped.
So there's n plus one steps here.
And n recursive calls
will actually n
plus one recursive
calls counting the first.
So there n plus one
recursive calls
to deal with a list of length
n. Remember I said always
consider the empty case.
That's how I know it's n
plus one rather than n,
because say you call
append on the empty list,
it tills takes right,
there's one call, the call
of append to the empty list.
So in the empty
case there's still,
the answer is still one.
Right? And then here
we've got three,
and the answer is 1234.
So always think about
the empty case.
It can help you think clearly.
So even in the empty case,
there's one call to deal with.
But in general takes
about n steps.
Let's not worry about
n versus n plus one,
but it's about n steps.
We call that linear.
It means if the list
is twice as long,
it will take you about
twice as many steps.
If it's a 100 times as long,
it will take you a 100
times as many steps.
So we're going to
make use of something
like the sum of the
numbers from one to
n is n times n plus
one divided by two.
You can do that in quick chat.
So I can instantly tell
you what the sum of
the numbers from one
to ten is. It's 55.
Because that is ten times
11 divided by two is 55.
And you can actually add
them all up and check, yes,
the sum of the numbers
from one to ten is 55.
So remember we can
use Fold r or fold l,
which should we use?
So if we use fold l,
then we would take,
let's say we were to
pending for lists and
let's say their lengths
are N1 to N four.
So if we append them this way,
first we do this one.
So that would take n n1 steps.
The result of this has
length n n1 plus n2.
So when we append this to this,
it takes N1 plus N2 steps.
And then when we take these
three things upended,
their length is N1
plus N2 plus N3.
So it takes that many steps
to append to the fourth list.
So the number of steps
required is this.
But if we do it
associated to the right,
so first we append this one,
that's length N one,
so takes n steps,
then we append this one,
just this one, that
one's length N2.
So it takes N2 steps.
And then we just append this one,
that one's like three.
So it takes N3 steps.
So here it's the sum of
the lengths except for the
last one because you just
copy that one over which the
computer can do in one step.
Copying something like
exactly without changing it.
By here, it takes N1 plus
N1 plus N2 plus this.
And remember I showed you
the sum of the numbers from
one to n is n times n
plus one divided by two.
We're just gonna
do things roughly,
roughly that's n squared, right?
N times n. That's what's
going to dominate the cost there.
So doing it this way around.
If you've got enlist
your appending,
it takes m squared steps times
the length of each list if
they're all about
the same length.
But this way around,
it just takes n steps.
So if, if you're,
if you've got a 1000 lists
that we're
concatenating together.
This one is a thousand times
faster than the second.
Ok. So this ways it
1000 times slower.
This one's a 1000 times faster.
Yep. Oh, right.
So a quick check in
this case, right?
This doesn't make any
sense if n is negative,
so we're just checking it for
n greater than or equal to 0.
Some quick check,
you can write down
a property and then a
double arrow and it says,
only give me an answer
if this property holds.
And in fact, he counts the
number of tests it does.
So it does a 100 tests
where this property holds.
Okay. Good question.
Yep. Sorry.
Oh, so yeah, the type here as
property rather than bool,
because if you add this thing
and it's a property and
quick check knows how to deal
with things that are properties.
Was that your question?
Yeah. Yeah. So there's
a funny word here,
property rather than bool.
Right? So if n was
negative, right?
This wouldn't work because
if this was minus ten,
this would become the empty list.
But minus ten times minus
nine divided by two is non-zero.
So it only works for numbers
greater than or equal to 0.
Okay? So first step,
this is why we always
use Fold r rather
than full l for concatenate.
Ok, very important,
it's better in time.
Here's another cool example.
Let's say I'm summing up a list.
Okay? So here I'm using
fold l to sum a list of
length 84 numbers we often use.
For addition multiplication,
we often use
fold l rather than
fold R. Because again,
if you play stupid computer,
you see the stupid computer
can do one of them in
constant space and the other
one takes linear space.
So again, full Bell is
better than fold R.
But I won't go through
the details of
why that's true today.
But so if you do fold l,
curl the parentheses
piled up to the left.
And you can see first
we do this one,
then we do this one,
then we do this one.
So in general, if you've
got a list of numbers,
it takes about n steps.
But we could do it differently.
We can parenthesize
adjacent pairs
and you get what's called
a full binary tree.
So here's X1, here's X2,
here's x3, x4, and so on.
And then we can do it
not in eight steps,
but three steps, right?
Because here, just add x1 and x2.
That gets us there some at
X3 and X4 at the same time.
That gives us there's some
add x4 and x5 and x6 and x7.
So we do four additions in
parallel that gives
us four numbers.
And then again we do two
editions in parallel.
And then we do the final thing.
So if we talk about how
quickly we get the answer,
if we can do things in parallel,
then the answer is,
it's in this case.
But in general, this is
M and this is going
to be the log base
two of m. So if you
have n is 1000,
this one is a 100 times
slower than this one,
because log base two
of ten is about ten.
So you'd have a tree ten deep,
that gives you a 1000
different numbers
at the bottom, actually 1024.
So just ten steps.
You can do the edition if you
happen to have ten
computers on hand.
Whereas here, you'd
have to do it linearly.
In general white, this
is what's called an
embarrassingly parallel
problem, right?
It's really easy to do the
bits of it in parallel.
I'll get to your
question in a minute
and write an example, right?
Who in this room has a
computer in their pocket?
Right?
Who in this room has four
computers in their pocket?
Right? Most of you,
most phones these days
have quad processes.
So you could do things
not a 1000 times faster,
but four times faster by
exploiting the parallel others.
And for adding numbers,
that probably doesn't matter.
But if you're doing
something like doing
some processing on a photograph,
that really does matter.
And indeed your, your phones
will all have something
called a GPU,
GPU graphics processing unit,
which let you do very
simple steps in a
1000 or 10 thousand
times parallel
precisely to speed up things
like processing pictures.
So you had a question.
If you use one CPU,
doing it this way
will not be faster.
But what if you use,
what if used for CPUs?
If you do multiple threads
on a single processor,
then it will still take
the same time because it
must execute each
thing in each thread.
But if you have
four processors and
your threads get distributed
among the different processors,
then it will be
four times faster.
So the important thing
is you have to have
multiple computers and
actually use them.
Ok? Now an important example of
this kind of parallelism
is whenever you do a
search on your computer.
With Google or Bing
or what have you,
right when you do
that, what happens?
Your query goes to a warehouse,
and that warehouse is
full of computers.
And typically it might use
a 1000 computers to answer
your one query, right?
If you had to search
the whole web,
the web is pretty big.
If you had to search the
whole web one step at a time,
it would take a long time.
But few 1000 computers or
10 thousand computers.
You can do it 1000 times
faster or 10 thousand
times faster.
And Google came up
with a standard way
of structuring
these computations,
which is called MapReduce,
which works basically by
breaking up the problem.
So this is a simple thing.
I want to count how many times
each word appears in this text.
So you break it up into lines.
You count if how many
times each word
appears in each lines,
you accumulate everything,
and then you do this.
So MapReduce is actually
named after these two ideas
from functional programming.
Map which you've seen
and fold, right?
Why isn't it called map fold?
Well, there's another name for
full used in some
systems which is reduce.
It's just the same thing.
So MapReduce is exactly
this idea that you break
your computation down into
higher-order operators
like map and full.
And they have some other
ones that they use at
Google as well for doing
this kind of accumulation.
But it's basically
just this idea.
So I mentioned that the first
few years of computing,
people didn't really think in
terms of higher-order functions.
And then gradually
more and more people
began to think in terms of them.
So the development of MapReduce,
which is now I guess a
dozen years old or so,
is an example of people
beginning to think in
terms of higher-order functions.
If I've got something
that I'm using for map,
something I'm using for fold.
Can I do that
quickly in parallel?
Yes. That's exactly this idea.
And indeed, sometimes
what you're doing,
just counting up how
many of something there
is right at the top
it says of about
such and so many
answers that summing
is done using exactly this
technique I showed you.
So instead of taking for
zillions of webpages,
instead of taking
zillions of steps,
it only takes log base
two of a zillion steps
which is much smaller.
Okay. Are there any
questions about that?
Yes. Does Haskell or
will Haskell automatically
parallelize stuff?
No. But there are
libraries in Haskell that
help you to do stuff in parallel.
And example of this is the
one that I mentioned on
the first day that
Facebook uses for again,
filtering every single web post.
Again, they do that in parallel
so that it happens fast, right?
As you can imagine, if you
had to take one step for
every single post to
Facebook looking for the
fake ones from Russia,
it would take too long.
So they do it in
parallel and in fact,
they use a Haskell program
to do that. Good question.
Ok. That is, so yesterday
I finished beating off a
little bit of material.
I want to show you that material,
but that is the end
of lecture seven,
and I will show you the
end of lecture six.
You may applaud for the
end of lecture seven.
And then let me just show
you the end of lecture six,
which I didn't show
you last time too.
So right, we saw map,
we saw filter, we saw fold.
And the one thing
I didn't show you
is of course you can
put them altogether.
So we can do the sum of
the squares of the
positive numbers in
a list using library functions,
using comprehensions,
using recursion.
So right, check if x
is greater than 0,
square it and add it to
the recursive thing
for the remainder.
Otherwise, drop it out
and just recursively
sum up the remainder.
Or we can do it
with fold R plus of
0 and map of square and
filter of positive.
So any of those different
ways work and you could use
quick check to show that
they're all equivalent.
And somebody said, oh,
am I better off using
recursion or using comprehensions
when I write things?
And the answer is,
Haskell actually knows more about
compiling comprehensions.
If you've got one comprehension
that's acting over
a list formed by
another comprehension.
So say squares here was
defined using comprehensions,
and say positives was defined
using a comprehension.
Haskell actually knows
if you write this,
it will turn it into this.
And I believe it knows
about Folder and maps.
So if you write this, it
will turned it into this.
But if you write this by hand and
then you use another
comprehension,
degenerate the input to this one.
It won't know how to
combine those things.
But if you write it
this way, it will.
So it's actually faster
to use comprehensions and
higher-order functions in Haskell
than it is to use recursion.
You might think, oh, recursion,
let me combine all these things.
Recursion will be faster,
but nope, Haskell knows
enough mathematics.
The Haskell compiler knows
enough mathematics to
optimize these things.
So it's actually better
to use comprehensions.
Really nice. I love this, right?
You've got trade-off.
Do I make it easy
to read or do I make it fast?
You use mathematics,
right? Yeah, that same.
Easy to read is faster
than hard to read.
I also wanted to show you
one other thing which
is about currying.
How many people have read
about currying in the book?
How many people
have read the book?
Okay, good. I was worried
for a moment there.
So notice that we
always do things in
Haskell in this weird way.
How do we describe this function?
Add that has two arguments.
He write it arrow,
int arrow it, it's one function.
Why are there two arrows?
And then we write add x, y.
Why do we do that?
Why don't we put
the arguments in parentheses
with a comma between them,
like every sensible
person in the world does.
Why do we do with this funny way?
Well, the answer is,
each of these looks
like it's one function.
I will now tell you the secret.
Each of these looks
like it's one function.
Because it is one function.
Haskell does not know about
functions of two arguments.
The stupid computer does not
know about functions
of two arguments.
It only knows about
functions of one argument.
So what's going on here?
What's going on is it's,
is the parentheses go this way.
So when you write add,
it takes one integer and
it returns one thing.
And the one thing it returns
is another function.
And what that other
function does is
takes an integer to an integer.
Similarly, when we write
add X, Y, the parentheses.
So when we write a
string of arrows,
the parentheses always
go to the right.
When we write an application,
the parentheses always
go to the left.
And so that means add x. Y
really means compute add
acts that will give me
a function and then apply
that function to y.
Reality. Is that work?
So what's going on here?
So my say add X,
Y equals X plus Y.
That's really the same as
saying add x is g, right?
We're returning a function.
So we return the function
g. What is the function g?
It's the function g that
takes y and then adds x to y.
This, I couldn't define this at
the top level because
it knows about x.
So x is in scope
here, so that's okay.
So if I say add three
applied to, for,
that really returns
g applied to four,
where g of y is now three plus y.
The function that
adds three to things.
We add three means
the function that takes a
number and adds three to it.
Which here I've called, Gee,
who some people are Smiley
gets fun, isn't it?
And then you've got, so then
g of four is the same as three
plus four, which is seven.
So this idea is named
for Haskell Curry,
who lived from 1900 to 1982.
I actually got to
shake his hand once.
But actually the same idea
was developed earlier by
Moses Shawn Finkel and
also by Gottlob Fraga.
So Moses shrimp Finkel,
you can guess from
his name was Jewish.
Gottlob forager was
a noted anti-Semite.
So but we call it currying.
We, the, the joke I was
told was that we could call
it shouldn't tinkling.
The currying is tastier
and I discovered actually
Fred had the same
idea even earlier.
So these people were
all logicians and they
just want a very simple
system of logic.
So they just want it
functions of one argument.
And then they went, oh, with
functions of one argument,
I can get more than one.
So we can actually take
advantage of the fact
that these are always
just functions.
And I told you can write sum of
X is fold R of plus and 0,
and then the list.
But we can also write
it more compactly.
We can just say sum is
fold R of plus and 0.
Because what folders
returning here is
a function from a list of a to a.
And we can do it with all of
these things that we
saw before, right?
So the previous day,
I updated the slides.
I put the previous
day we saw sum and
product and concat
and, and an or.
At each of these I
wrote xs equals block,
X is equals blop axis equals,
well, you don't need that.
So you can just say or
is fold R of OR and
false and leave the
axes off of both sides.
If you put it on one side, you
have to put it on the other side,
but you can leave
it off both sides.
And thanks to currying,
it means exactly the same thing.
And if you do that,
you are thinking at
a higher level because
you're no longer
thinking in terms of,
here's a function I
apply to an argument.
You're just taking a function.
What does fold R of
plus and 0 return
a function which takes a list
of int and returns an int.
And you don't even need to think
about the argument at all.
You are now all thinking
at a higher level.
Will stop there.
Thank you very much.