Good morning. Are
there any questions?
No questions.
Are people happy, unhappy?
Who feels the FP part of
the course is going okay?
Who feels drowned and
lost in the epi part?
Okay? Who kills the
CL parts going okay.
Who feels drowned and
lost in the CL part?
Okay, I'm doing
better than Michael.
Yea. Don't worry if
you're feeling lost,
you can see that there are,
there's always some proportion
of people that feel lost.
And that's fine.
What is important if you
feel loss is to take
advantage of all the different
things available to you.
Go to the labs, go to in Pals,
talk to some of the people who
raised their hand when I said,
are you feeling okay?
Talk to your friends and
preparing, go to tutorial.
All of these things
are available to
you and make sure to
take advantage of them.
It's fine to feel a bit lost.
Everybody at some
point should feel
confused and that they don't know
how to do something, right?
That's actually a good thing.
Because if you feel that you
don't know how to do something,
then you can find
out how to do it.
And that's called learning.
I remember back when I was in
high school that I
was clever enough.
So the first time I really got
stuck on something
was in high school.
I remember sitting in
my bedroom swearing at
the wall because I
couldn't follow what was
going on in the
chemistry textbook.
But that was the
beginning of learning.
So don't worry if
there's something that
you don't understand,
but don't give up, right?
That's the point at which
then learning can take place.
Ok. Any questions about that?
Ok. I was expecting
somebody to say,
Well, were you Philip?
He wants to do that.
So I was here.
So I bought back the t-shirt.
So this was the Purdue
Programming Language Center.
They didn't opening.
I think I put up the web page.
Let's see. Oh, there it is.
The Purdue Programming
Language Center,
or purple had their
opening celebration
and then they had a bunch
of keynote speakers.
And I was one of them.
See if you can guess
which one is me.
This guy's from Facebook.
He said lots of interesting PL,
stuff in functional programming.
It's named Eric
Meyer and now he's
doing guess what, deep learning.
So AI is taking over everywhere.
This guy's been Zorn,
he works at Microsoft.
And he gave a really
interesting talk
because he was pointing out that
it's not just programming
that's important, but
dealing with data.
So for instance, they
did some work looking at
Excel spreadsheets and
just saying, okay,
it is the same formula and all
the cells where one cell that has
a different formula where you
wouldn't expect it
and highlighting it.
And then they use that tool.
There's a very famous paper that
basically was used to
justify austerity here.
And in the US saying, well,
if you spend too much,
it's very bad for the economy.
And it turns out that the way
they derive that was from
a spreadsheet and it turns
out there was a bug
in the spreadsheet.
So they didn't count some of
the data that was discovered
later that if you
counted all the data there
conclusions were
completely unjustified.
So this particular justification
for austerity at least was
completely wrong due to an
error in a spreadsheet.
So Eris and spreadsheets
can be significant.
And so they were trying
to figure out, okay,
how would you notice
if there was an error
in a spreadsheet?
So that's an interesting
thing to look at.
And this has definitely work.
She's looking at making
Haskell even more complicated.
And this is Amal Ahmed.
She's a professor at
Northeastern now.
And she's looking at how you
go about proving compilers,
correct when you're doing
independent compilation.
So we've got about 30 years of
history now proving compilers,
correct, but we still don't
know how to provoke you.
Compile this bit and then compile
this bit and then
put them together.
How do you show that
that is correct.
So she's looking at how would
you go about formalizing
that and couldn't
let it works on.
I'll just go through
all that. Why not?
Cooler is at Stanford
and he was in hardware,
but then he got into
programming languages.
Because you need good
programming languages to get
a sufficiently parallel program
that it runs well
on the hardware.
So he's looking at
very high performance.
So basically what my key
lessons in this class is,
don't do what he does.
In that sometimes
really high performance
is quite important.
So in that sense, what he does
is absolutely the
right thing to do.
But many people in
computing tend to get
distracted because performance is
something you can
stick a number on.
My, my program runs in 0.1
microsecond or whatever.
So you can time it and say,
oh look how fast it's going.
And then people tend
to focus on that.
But in fact, that's the
least important thing.
It's the least important thing
because computers have
been getting faster and
faster and faster ever
since they started
building them in the
mid 19 hundreds, right?
So that, you know.
So this guy bends or went
through the history of
computing and he showed when
a supercomputer was like.
1980. And then he showed
an Xbox currently.
And an Xbox currently has
about the same power as a
supercomputer from 1980.
Now supercomputer that you
know, it's a Siri recipient.
Can we got a whole room full of
computers all as
fast as possible?
The number floating
point operations
per second they can do is
comparable to what a
single xbox can do now.
So computers are getting much,
much faster and they
have lots of power.
So if you can spend
a year of hard work programming
to make your program
run twice as fast.
Is that a good use of
your time? Probably not.
But the most important thing to
do with your computer
program is to
make it easy to read
and easy to modify.
If you look at
what all the money is
spent on with software,
it is not on writing,
the software,
is on modifying the software
after it's been written.
This is called maintenance.
So we tend to focus
on writing programs,
but it's actually maintenance.
That's the most important thing.
So the most important thing
is to write your program in
a clear way so that other
people can maintain it.
After you've done
writing it and you've
moved on to your next
company or whatever.
And it turns out there's not
a number for that, right?
Speed is a number,
so it's really easy to measure.
But clarity, people have tried to
come up with numbers for clarity.
But right, there's nothing that
works as well as just saying
my program ran in 1
tenth of a microsecond.
So people tend to ignore clarity.
But that's the important thing.
You know exactly how
important it is.
What am I going to do right now?
Jump up and down.
Maintenance is more important
than raw performance.
Clarity is more
important than speed.
And so you'll see me
spending a lot of
time talking about
how to make programs.
Clare. And I will
occasionally talk about
what makes Program slow and
how to make them faster.
It's not something
that we ignore,
but it's not the first thing.
And indeed dealing with speed
too soon is a real problem.
Premature optimization
is the root of all evil.
I found two different
famous computer scientists
who are attributed
with that quote and,
uh, and I quite believe it.
So that's why I'm jumping
up and down of eyes.
The most important thing is
writing your program
in a clear way.
And then finally, this
is push me, Cole.
And he worked for Deep Mind.
And he was talking
about all the ways in
which AI current
systems currently fail.
So AI systems are really
amazing right there much,
much better than when I
first got into the field.
Mainly because computers
have gotten so much faster.
So you can use various
brute force techniques
and they worked
surprisingly well.
So now we can simulate
millions and millions of
neurons and just see what.
Sorry, not there cold neurons,
but they're a very
simplified model of
the neurons in the human head.
But you can use neuro
simplified neurons to do
really amazing things with what
are called neural networks.
And so typically, right,
you can just train it on
lots of, lots of images.
And then you show it an image.
And it will say that's a cat
and you go, well that's right,
it was a cat and you shoot
another image and says
that's a dot and you say,
wow, that's right, it was a dog.
And then you should,
another image of
the cat with three pixels change,
so it looks identical to you.
And the program says
that's attractor.
And this is an issue
that they don't know
how to tackle yet.
So he was talking
about things that
might be done to tackle
that kind of issue.
But AI is incredibly
powerful, right?
People are using
it more and more,
but it's also in many
ways incredibly weak in
that you can't get any guarantees
about how well or badly
it's going to work.
And these are problems
that need to be solved.
These are the
problems that you are
going to need to
solve in your career.
Okay, so that was
the purple thing.
And then the I, I made
a little slideshow.
What's in my little slideshow?
Should get the little
slideshow of my trip.
Yes. Yes, this little
So the first thing he
does write my began,
I showed you all the sponsors for
the International Conference
on functional programming.
You can see they're
very similar sponsors.
For this session at
Purdue where they were
opening their new labs.
You've got Facebook
and Microsoft.
And some of these
I don't recognize.
And then this is the
National Science Foundation,
which funds a lot of
research in the US.
And this is the Defense
Advanced Research
Projects Agency,
which funds a loft
projects in the US.
In fact, what we now call
the internet used
to be called the
arpanet because what was
then called arpa did
the original funding.
And let's see.
So that's one thing.
There's the people waiting
for the seminar to begin.
That's me with Doug Hofstadter.
How many people know who Doug
Hofstadter is? About three.
So there's a book called girdle
Escher Bach and
eternal golden braid.
And if you want to
know about ideas,
about how logic and
human thinking and
consciousness might all
interact with each other.
That's a good book to read.
How many people have heard
the term Strange Loop?
There's not, I'm nobody.
Ok. There's a developer
conference called Strange Loop,
and currently there's
actually a play
on Broadway called Strange Loop,
named after this term
from Doug's book
size I holding you,
you'd have to go to New
York and see the play.
And he said, well,
they're sold out.
So that makes it
difficult for him.
And then this is Ledi Hall at
the University of Indiana.
So I also went to the
University of Indiana and
went to Northwestern
University in Chicago.
And so this is Ledi
Hall in Chicago.
It's a very nice building,
almost as nice as our
Informatics Forum.
I'm being inconsistent
because when I spoke to them,
I said our Informatics form is
almost as nice as Ledi Hall.
And they have a very nice
sculpture in the top of it.
So this is a, this is
an active sculpture.
It, it actually
has sensors in it.
And if you move around, some of
the lights will change and so on.
When it's working, of course,
it was turned off
when I was there.
But it's a nice sculpture.
And I am really jealous of this
because when they built
the informatics for him,
they said, oh, we should do
some nice kind of
interactive sculpture.
And what they ended
up doing is something
with names of the donors
to the building in ascii,
which you can see in the lobby
of the Informatics form.
So this I think, is
a much better idea
of an interactive artwork.
And I play tourist in Chicago.
So there's me playing
tourists in Chicago.
How many people
know what the funny
mirrored thing and the bottom is?
Yep. You're gone.
Do you know its name? Does
anybody know the name?
Right. So they locally
they call it the bean.
The actual name is the
Cloud Gate and it's by
an artist named Kapoor.
Can't remember his first
State SAP knows firstname.
Sorry, Amish cohort. Thank you.
So it's very nice artwork.
It's one of my favorite
things actually.
And you can see there
are lots of tourists
around it looking at
it, it's great fun.
And if you ever see
the movie source code,
which is a great name
because it makes it sound
like it's about writing
code for a computer,
but it's actually
about time travel.
There's a scene that
takes place at the beam.
So that was me playing tourist.
Okay. You can put that away.
So so that's my trip report.
Any questions?
Based on the Trip
Report or me wintering
on about how important
maintenance is.
Okay. What's more and
more about recursion?
Yeah, okay, let's learn
more about recursion.
And the reason, right?
That's why there we go.
I think we should
try that one again.
Recursions, really
exciting, right?
Who want to learn more about
recursion? There we go.
Okay, so first thing we learn
is how to count, right?
So we know how to do this
in the sense that if
I want a blank window,
yes, there's a blank window.
Let's do. Okay, so
if I do just take
a completely blank
window and their galaxy,
right, we know how to
count because we can just
type one dot dot ten, right?
It will count up to ten force.
Or we can count
one dot, dot 1000.
And it will count
up to 1000 fourths.
So you all know how to write that
in Haskell and that's the way you
should write hit
most of the time.
But how would you reduce
that down to basic stuff?
So could you write
that same definition
recursively using what
we've all ready learned.
The answer is yes.
So let's look at that.
Weight. Yep, there we go.
Back to I need to learn
the keys for view
it in full mode.
What does it control?
Apple F, of course.
Alright, control
apple F a, it worked.
Okay, so let's
learn how to count.
Right? So I wrote this
as one dot dot three.
That's actually an abbreviation
for calling a library function
called num from two, right?
And you give it where you
start and where you end.
And so this thing is just an
abbreviation for this thing.
And we do this all the time
in computing is we introduce
a special notation that
just an abbreviation for
something else and
that something else in
our case will usually
be a function call.
Pretty much everything
of interest in
functional programming
is a function,
which is sort of why it's
called functional programming.
I remember, I forgot to
show you about this.
What's this? Like? It's lambda.
And people see what
this thing is.
The funny thing after the
lambda and before the P. So
as I was going to
bring up an image of
this on the web, but
they don't have any.
So I should've taken
a photo of myself and
then showed it to you.
But that's a turnstile that's
a little T on its side.
And that's very
important for logic.
So basically,
functional programming and
logic are so important to
programming languages
that when you design
in that when you open a new
programming language centre,
this is what you put
on your t-shirt.
Functional programming, very dig.
And then a bit of
logic, a bit smaller.
But those are the two
important things.
So you're learning
the right stuff.
Like so. And then as I mentioned,
we tend to use
abbreviations for things.
So this is just a
different way of writing.
This that looks a lot
nicer and it's a
lot easier to read.
There's a name for that.
It's called syntactic sugar.
Syntactic sugar is just the name
for having a different
way of writing
something that's a
bit easier to read.
So then how do we define
the num from two?
So it takes two numbers and
it returns a list of numbers.
And if m is greater than n,
then it returns the empty list.
And if that's not the case,
and M must be less
than or equal to
n. And then m will be the
first number of the list.
And then we do cons,
and then we keep counting
from m plus one.
So the important thing is
your parameter m changes
from m to m plus one,
but your upper bound n
just stays the same.
For one thing changes and the
other one stays the same.
And that sort of pattern where
you've got a function at
some of the arguments change
a little bit and some of
them stayed the same.
To tell you when you
stop is very common.
So let's go through
and execute this.
Entering computer mode.
E num of 13 is
which equation applies
and is one, n is three.
Is one greater than three?
It's one greater than three.
No, no, it's not creative.
It's not using this equation.
Nope, not that one is, let's see,
m less than or equal to n is one
less than or equal to three.
This is the equation I use.
Okay? So now I just copy this
out with m replace by one and
m replace by one and n replaced
by 31 plus one is two.
So this gives me one.
M is one colon,
colon and a known from two of
m plus one and n is the
Num from two of 23.
Okay. I'm all done.
Oh, wait, no, I
need forgot what he
knew from two of 23 is OK.
So that matches this one and
m is now two and l is three.
Ohio State Board.
I don't take work.
We say M is bound to two.
South kinky, doesn't it?
So m is bound to two and
n is bound to three.
So now we can do the same
thing is to create a events
we know is two less
than or equal to three.
Yeah, yes. Okay, so
now we copy again.
And now n becomes two.
And from two N plus one,
N two plus one is three.
So that becomes the
loomed from 233.
Okay? And now we
do the same thing.
Yan is three greater than three?
Not quite.
Almost. Not quite.
Is three less than
or equal to three?
Yes. So we copy it out.
I can now see you're
all saying again,
I'm a computer. I don't care.
I will do the same
thing a zillion
times and I will not get tired.
E di di, di, di, di, di,
di, di, di, di, di.
Ok. So m is three.
And he knew from
two of m plus one.
And so m is 33 plus one is
four and is still three.
So we've got three
Kony num from 243.
Now we go back again is
for greater than three.
Yes. Yea, we finally get
to use the base case.
Ok, so now we just
copy out empty list.
And I've got one cons, two cons,
three cons, empty list,
which is the list 123.
So we're done. Okay, so that it's
quite a roofer ux by
wanted to go through
that in some detail.
You could see there is no
thinking involved, right?
It's very clear that if
this little guy is the
one doing the work,
there's no thinking
involved, right?
It's just following a set
of rules mechanically.
So just we, here we can write out
two lines and then
following those two
lines mechanically,
you can count, you can
form a list of the
numbers between m
and n. Is that clear
enough to people?
Okay. So you now
know how to count.
Are there any questions? Yes.
I'm not quite sure
what you're asking.
Yeah. Or you want
to count by twos.
So you want to go
13579 and then stop.
Ok, good question.
So if you we didn't
want to count by ones,
but we want to count by
some other interval.
How would we change it?
So any idea how
would you change it?
Folks, I'm glad you're
mumbling but MBL very
quietly because
otherwise I can't hear
his answer. So guess.
What we could do is if we want to
count by a certain amount.
In fact, that's actually
another one that's in the
standard library somewhere.
But let's just define it, right?
You knew from two vi.
So let's take an int and
an int and returns a list of int.
Sorry. Oh, right.
Of course it taking
three numbers now.
So M, N and a step.
Let's call it k. So we could,
we could get these names
that were easier to
read like from two and by,
let's do it that way
just to be different.
So there are two
possibilities, right?
Either from is greater than two,
and what do we get in that case?
Empty. Or from is less
than or equal to two.
And so now we've got from cons,
he knew from two by,
and now what do we put here?
So this is, this is two,
this is by and what goes here.
I'm going to ask the
fellow who asked
the question originally to see if
he's from plus bi, right?
From plus by. And
that should work.
Let's see if that works.
From 20 to all confused.
Now, try that again.
Thank you for the music.
I had the weirdest
thing on my keyboard,
which is type why?
Like I just did and puts it
somewhere else on the screen.
I get the beginning of
the thing. Is it only me?
Nobody else has seen that.
Yeah. Yeah, it only
does it for me with y.
What letter does it do for you?
So I think I've got poltergeist.
Okay, so 2V, what will count
from one to ten by two?
It did it. Well done.
Good question. Yep. You don't
think it works in every case.
Good. That's really
important to think about.
What case do you
think it doesn't work
and what happens
if Vi is negative?
Good question. Let's find out.
He knew from two by,
where do I want to count from
ten to one by minus two.
Right? Because we should
count down now, right?
No, so it's not
going to count down.
It only counts up, right?
So it's yet that this is ten,
is not smaller than
one, so we're done.
I can't count up. Well,
it sort of works.
Right? This is count
up from one to ten.
Count up from one to
ten by minus two.
By two, you can already tell
something's going to go wrong.
And what goes wrong
yet just go counts up
forever because it never
reaches ten, right?
So it's counting up to ten,
but it never gets there.
So let's, let's see Ctrl X k
Buffer yet kill that buffer.
No, do not keep the buffer there.
Okay? So, yep, good point.
So this does not work
well if bi is negative.
So we might want to
add another case,
possibly at the beginning.
Right? So one way of
doing this is to say,
if this is the case and
bi is greater than 0,
and this is the case.
And bi is greater than 0.
Or last possibility is by is
less than or equal
to 0 equals error.
That was stupid. Okay. So that
this is a much better program.
Yes. Thank you for
pointing that out.
Good. Any other questions yet?
So just Haskell's a limit as
to how deep recursion can go?
Yes, because the memory on
your computer is limited.
So if you fill up
the whole memory,
then it will say out
of, out of memory.
But computer memories are big.
So generally you don't need
to worry about that limit.
But if you wanted to
do something forever,
then you might need to
worry about that limit.
Very good question.
Good. Okay, good.
You guys are engaged
asking good questions.
Yes. Theoretically there's
there's no, That's right.
You can think of recursion
as going forever,
but you do need to
think of recursion is
using up a little bit of memory.
So sometimes you might
want to compute how much
memory you're going to use,
but generally, you don't
need to worry about
that just yet.
Okay. Let's go on.
That's the one
that's threatening.
Okay, so now we
know how to count.
So factorial, right?
Something that uses
counting, right?
So the factorial of n is
the product from one to
n. So now we know how
we could write that,
which is factorial from one to
n. We can do fat with m and
n. And so notice here
this definition.
This is just a
function definition.
I could just write two
function definitions.
I've written where and this
other definition to indicate
the only place where
this name fact is in
scope is in the definition
of factorial wrap,
the rest of the program,
I would not be able
to invoke back.
I could put it at
the top level like
the other definition and I
could invoke it elsewhere.
But here I'm saying,
No, nobody else is
going to use fat.
So I'll just define it here.
And again, the same thing.
If n is greater
than n, we're done.
So we get the product
of the empty list,
which is 11, y is at one.
Surely it should be
00. So good number.
Why isn't it 0? So what would
happen if we put 0 here?
But you get the product of ten
times nine times eight
times seven times
six times five times four times
three times two
times one times 0.
Because it will end with 0
because we've said 0 here.
And of course the product of
lot of things and 0 is 0.
So that would not work very well.
So we say one, because
if you multiply a
bunch of stuff by one,
it doesn't change it.
So it's a fancy name for that.
Does Avi know the fancy name?
We say that one is the
identity for multiplication.
Or sometimes even
the people that use,
people use as a name for
identity is unit after one,
because this cases so common.
So we can also say one is
the unit for multiplication.
So we'll talk more about
that concept later.
That actually turns out
to be pretty important.
But the important thing is,
don't use 0 all the time.
Use identity, use whatever
is the appropriate identity.
Depending on your operation,
0 is the unit of
something very important.
What is 0, the unit for the
identity for addition, right?
0 is the unit for addition.
0 plus thingy is thingy.
So 0 is important when
we're doing sums.
But for products we use one.
Ok, and so does everybody
see how factorial works?
And notice that I'm
going to copy this one out.
Let's see if I can do that.
I'm just going to
show you a couple of
variants on how we could do this.
That that's wrong. That's right.
Yay. That didn't
come out very well.
Alright, try that.
Right, so we can just try it out.
For factorial is yep,
that one worked.
I notice I've said here into it,
I probably shouldn't
have said that.
So Haskell's a bit funny.
Some things only work with int,
which is why we tend to use int.
But it really should be
integer all the time.
Because then it will work
even with very large numbers.
Oh, that didn't work at all.
Oh, I know why because
I didn't reload it.
What have I done wrong?
This one still wrong.
Very good point.
We go let's try that again.
Yeah, not works the
business by the way,
why you want to
use integer rather
than int whenever you can.
Okay? Right. So I
just want to show you
a couple of things.
One thing is, alright,
if we didn't do that,
it still works.
It does, does the same
thing with flowed.
It. But now I
can also call fact.
So if I say that
I'm one to a 100,
it gives us the same thing.
I could also call
fact if 99 to 100,
if I wanted to wear as right
when I have the Waring here.
No, load it. There we go.
Now, write factorial wrecked
still does exactly
the same thing.
But fat.
He's now not in scope variable,
not in scope fact.
Ok. And this pattern where I
wanted to find something like
the factorial up to end,
but to do it, I need
this other thing that's
changing, right?
I need this m, this lower
bound I'm counting up.
So I define another function
that has one extra argument,
and then it's that extra
argument that changes.
That's a really,
really common pattern.
So I know you all know
how to do factorial.
But the reason I'm showing
you this is this idea, oh,
I need to define a function with
one argument that
finds the factorial.
But to do it, I need
to remember that
upper bound while having another
thing that's counting up.
So to define factorial,
I need another function,
a helper function.
That oops, excuse me,
a helper function that
has an additional
argument that can vary.
That's what we've done here.
So we just want factorial
of n. But to do it,
we do it in terms of the
helper function fact of
n And n. Okay?
And if I want to be
consistent naming,
this would be call that
coil wreck helper.
But I hate really long names,
so I've just called it fact.
And because this name is
only in scope for here,
it's perfectly fine to pick
a short name because you only
need to remember it
for this definition.
Ok, questions about that.
What else have we got today?
So we can go through and do
it in exactly the same way.
Who wants to see it? That
done by the stupid computer.
Who is bored and doesn't want to
see it done by the
stupid computer.
Who didn't raise their hands
either of those times.
Right? You guys are not engaged.
I'll do that again. Come on.
Who wants to see it again?
Who doesn't want to see it again?
Yeah, that's what I thought.
Okay. And then we
could do something.
We can also count
forever in Haskell.
So you can do something like
if we say 0 dot
dot There it goes.
It's not going to stop.
Right? So we already saw
wave doing this, right?
What we were trying to count
by minus two up to ten.
Again, we got something
like this that didn't stop.
Let's see, just control SCC work.
No. Okay. Well, just
to kill that window.
Yes. Please die.
Yes. Please. Di
tri got wet again.
The acquit That sounds like a no.
Control x k. Okay.
Keep the buffer.
No, vary, go, yay.
Okay. What, what
else have we got?
So now we've got zip.
Zip takes a list of things and
another list of things
and returns a list of
pairs of corresponding elements.
So few zip 012 with ABC,
you get, alright, we can
run this one, right?
Go back to Yeah.
Alright, zip three with ABC.
And that gives us, And remember,
right when we say ABC,
Of course that's just again
that syntactic sugar for that.
So that's why you get that.
So just pairs of corresponding
elements of the list.
And the way that works is, okay,
we were talking about
corresponding outlets by
either list in fact
might be empty.
So as soon as one list
is empty, we stop.
And if they're both non-empty,
repair the first element
of the first one,
the first element
of the second one.
So the first on the left
with the first on the right.
And then we
recursively zip again.
And you can see that yep,
that would take pair
0 with a and then do
zip of 12x and BC and then pair.
Now we'll test the
front is one and b,
so we get one and
b may zip two with
C. Two and C are at the front.
And then we get zip
of two empty things.
So it's either it's
empty, it becomes empty.
And so that's why
we get that answer.
And in fact, there are two
different styles, right?
I've sort of used
the laid-back style,
which is what you find
in the standard library.
It will stop as soon as
one list becomes empty.
The other way is, is
this way which says
they must both be empty
at the same time.
And here, if you gave it to lists
of different length,
it would complain.
I would say no.
When one builds splints out
and the other one hasn't,
it said it would say,
I didn't expect
that error, error,
error warning Will Robinson
list of different lengths.
So by and large,
I recommend the Haar style,
but the standard library for
Haskell uses the laid back style.
And that's because there's
this cool trick which is.
Too cool to rule out.
So that's why we're a little bit
dangerous and we allow
lists of different lengths.
And the cool trick is you can do
this. What's that going to do?
Sorry. Slight. What
do you mean by slice?
It's going to slice the string.
Gonna cut into tiny
bits, sort of.
So what it's gonna
do, write this,
paired a number with each
element of the list.
This will also pair
a number with each
element of the list.
Of course it's
counting up from 0.
So it says the thing
at index 0 is a,
at index one is b,
at index two is C, and so on.
And also I'm counting from 0.
That's because I know
the right way to do it.
Some people thank you.
Count from one, they are what
we technically call wrong.
You always start counting from 0,
so that's what Haskell does.
So this just pairs
each home in the list.
So I can do this with
anything, right?
Sip, I want to know
where things are
in a very long sentence.
And you can see the sentences 19
characters long and well,
20 characters long.
And character number
with the index
19 is the 0s at the end
of a very long sentence.
And then what I could do
is as this other function,
you've got it here,
almost done called Search,
which finds the instances
of a character in lists.
So if I say search for E
to E is a single letters,
so that single quotes and
a very long sentence is
a list of characters.
Yep. Oh, what's wrong?
Oh, I didn't load it.
Have to load it up.
Sort of forgotten wrong.
I've got it the other way
round, right? Thank you.
Search a very long sentence
for E. And that says,
okay, 0s occurred at index
3131619 in that list and date,
if we did the other one, zip.
With a very long sentence.
You can see that the 0s
occurred at position 3131619.
Okay. We are at time where
past-time by two minutes.
You will continue
tomorrow. Thank you.