Are there any questions?
Yes. I'm sorry.
I can't hear you because
I love noise from
people wrestling around in
the room and coming in late.
Could you speak more loudly plays
between what is the difference
between sort and uniq sort?
There are lots of
different sorts.
I'm not quite sure what
you mean by unique sort in
Haskell is a special module
on Haskell called unique sort.
Great. You found stuff in
the library I didn't know about.
I will guess that
it's the equivalent of
sorting something and then
taking the knob that is removing
any duplicate elements.
Note what I did just there.
I didn't know the answer.
I didn't claim to
know the answer.
I said, I will guess that
this is really important.
If you don't know,
say you don't know,
that we'll give you credibility
with your colleagues.
It takes a little bit of
bravery to say that
you don't know,
your colleague will
recognize that as well.
They'll go, oh, that
person is confident.
It's actually a great idea
to say you don't know,
I learned that years
ago into competition in
physics involved things where
I said I didn't know
was part of the answer.
And then I sit by guess
that it must mean this.
And one of the judges came up
to me afterwards and said,
That was really good
that you did that.
I gave you extra points for that.
I still didn't win
the competition.
But it was just
physics. Who cares?
Yep, there was another question.
Know somebody just
taking off their jumper.
Okay. Any other questions?
Yet? Am I going
to go through Big O notation
today? Why? Yes, I am.
And guess. What is
the difference between what
is the difference
between type and data?
So data is a value like three.
What would the type of 3V?
Int? The type of three isn't.
So do you know the difference
between three, right?
Between three and int.
So that's the difference
between data and types.
Good question. Thank you.
Okay. Start with, I have
a question for you,
which is how are we doing?
So there's a midterm
feedback survey
that I've posted
using survey monkey.
I've posted the one for
my half of the class, FP.
So that's why it's the PHP
midterm feedback survey.
Michael's should be posting
a separate one for Cl.
It I'll help him use survey
monkey if he wants to.
But please put that answers
on this one that are
about PHP, not about Cl.
I notice a lot of you
have already responded.
I'll just check
when you responded.
Were you responding Did you
see the FP there or did you
just respond about
FP and C altogether?
How many people just
FP at PNC altogether.
Okay, relatively little
confusion that great.
So just respond about FP.
There will be a separate
midterm survey for CL
so we can see how the
two halves are doing.
Oh, and there's the
lake and that link
also is directly
on the Learn page.
I presume that's how a bunch
of you found it. I'm sorry.
Right. Okay. The
other thing I want to
tell you about is the
Influenza a PHP competitions.
We run this every year.
The prices are book
vouchers and glory.
So the book vouchers in
the past had been Amazon,
which I guess you can use
to get other stuff as well.
But I thought I'd support
local industry and give
black wells book
vouchers this year.
Okay, nobody's going, oh,
so that's what we're gonna do.
But the book voucher is
down the noise, right?
The glory is, you can say i1,
x place, third place,
or first place in
the competition.
That's always a nice thing to
be able to put on your CV.
We always get amazing entries.
Every year. Some you're there
more amazing than others.
So like some years we went, oh,
we have to give 5 second
prizes or whatever.
I think we've never given
more than one first-price BY
might be wrong about that.
So the number of
prizes will depend
on how many fantastic
entries we got.
I'm sure we will get at least a
few that are really fantastic.
So what do you do
in the competition?
You write a Haskell program
with interesting graphics.
Uab creative, I won't
follow the links now.
But if you follow this link,
you can see previous
winners for every year.
And that will give you
an idea of the kinds of
entries people make
in the competition?
Yes. Yes. You submit the
source code as well.
The I mentioned that
there are prizes,
those are sponsored by Galois.
Galois is one of
the many industrial firms
out there that use
Haskell quite heavily.
They're located in
Portland, Oregon.
They were founded by a
colleague of mine at
the University of Glasgow when we
were first creating Haskell.
So he had a lot to do with
the creation of Haskell.
And then he just founded
the company says, okay,
if Haskell so great and we
use it to write programs,
we will be better than everybody
else and we'll get
lots of business.
And he founded a company
based on that idea.
And so far they're
doing pretty well.
So among other things,
for the last Since we
started teaching in F18 a,
they've been sponsoring
the competition,
such as going to say
for the last decade,
but it's been rather more than a
decade now, decade and a half.
So you submit your code,
anger images, you list
everyone who contributed.
So the code, yes, that
includes the source.
You can use packages
from elsewhere,
but you have to be very clear
about what you've done,
that your own work and what
you're using that's
from elsewhere?
Yes. Do the graphics has
to be related to fractals.
The graphics has to
be fun to look at.
So there are things
they're fun to
look at that are not
related to fractals.
Many of the interesting
entries are
based on fractals, but
they don't have to be.
I saw another hand
up. Okay. The way
you submit is you email
your submissions to Irene.
And she asked me,
she said this year,
can you please tell them to
all use the same subject because
otherwise I get lots of
emails that it's
hard to sort out.
So please use this subject
when you make your submission
and you must make your
submission by two PM on Friday,
the 15th of November.
Yep. I'm sorry. Just speak up.
Can we or can it be interactive?
Yes, it may be interacted.
Some people have done
really interesting
interactive entries.
Although we found those hard to
post in an interactive
form to the website.
Does
I'm
not quite sure what
you're asking.
Does ascii count as human?
Can you do ascii graphics?
Sure. But if you look
at past entries,
you'll see that if you
do ascii graphics,
unless it's really
amazing ascii graphics,
it will probably look dull
compared to some of
the other entries.
But yeah, you can do really
amazing ascii graphics.
That would be great if I
could seem relatively right,
ascii graphic used to be
a big thing somebody
should be doing now,
emoji graphics, alright, where
you just build up an image
Alf lots of tiny emoji.
I've not seen
somebody do that yet,
so there's an idea for you.
Okay, if you come up with
further questions
about this, of course,
you can ask in class
or you can send
email and they'll distribute
answers to the group.
I guess you could use Piazza,
I should see it there.
So if you but just in
case send me an email.
If you have further questions
that haven't been answered,
feel free to send me an email.
Okay. No other
questions off that.
Okay. So following up
on an earlier question,
who's ready to learn
about Big O notation?
Oh, wow, great.
Everybody really excited
for nine AM on a Monday.
Okay, so Big O notation is
how you measure efficiency.
So let me remind
you about the most
important thing
to know about efficiency,
which is that
premature optimization
is the root of all evil.
Yes, sometimes it's important
to worry about efficiency,
but also sometimes
it's really important
not to worry about efficiency.
And I guarantee you
that you'll get
way ahead of all
your competitors in
the field if you simply don't
worry about efficiency
until you have to.
Because everybody
else always thinks,
oh, I better make this efficient.
And they use up a huge amount
of time and mental energy.
Introduce lots of extra bugs
trying to make it efficient.
If you don't worry about
efficiency, you will,
you will in fact be much
quicker than everybody else.
Because the important
thing usually is not
how fast your program runs,
but how quickly
you get to market.
So the most important thing
is to ignore efficiency.
Nonetheless, sometimes
knowing about
efficiency is really important.
So that's why I tell you a
little bit about it now.
But the most important
thing to know about
efficiency is don't
pay attention to it.
A similar example of this is I
have a friend who says Aikido,
which is a martial art,
which is how you
learn how to defend
yourself if somebody's
beating up on you.
And they begin by learning
the most important
defense technique,
which is runaway, right?
So the first thing
that the Dojo mastered
makes them do is run around
the stadium about a dozen
times so that they learn about
the most important technique,
run away before they
learn about how to
actually use Aikido
to fight people.
So that's the lesson I want
to teach you here, right?
What do you do when you
see an efficiency problem?
Runaway? Okay? Only sometimes
do stop and actually confront
it when you really need to.
Okay? Now, to show you how
important this quote is.
Who knows who Donald Knuth IS?
Very few of you,
okay, Donald Knuth
is a winner of the Turing Award.
How many people know what
the Turing Award is?
Uhm anymore, that's good.
How many people know what
the Nobel Prizes, okay?
There's no Nobel Prize in
computing for the obvious reason
that Nobel died long
before stored program digital
computers were invented.
There is also no Nobel
Prize in mathematics.
Mathematics was invented
before Nobel died.
And indeed there was
a famous mathematician
who was a lover,
who was the lover of Nobels wife.
So there's no Nobel
Prize in mathematics.
So in Mathematics instead
they have the Fields Medal.
And in computing, we
have the Turing Award.
So the Turing Award is the
highest award in computing.
And Donald Knuth is one of
the people who
received that award,
mainly for a series of books he
wrote called The Art of
Computer Programming.
Which is indeed all about how to
analyze your programs
to be efficient.
He then, the firm
that he was pup that
was publishing books,
changed their typesetting machine
and he thought it looked ugly.
So he thought, I can do
better using a computer.
And he developed this
system called TAC,
which is now widely
used everywhere for producing
nicely typeset things,
including the slides
for this course.
So all the slides I showed
you were produced using tech,
which was designed
by Donald Knuth.
He's a professor at Stanford.
I was lucky enough
to take classes from
him when I was an undergraduate.
And he's retired now,
but he's a great guy.
But just to show you how
important this quote is,
other people say it too.
So how many people know
who Tony Hoare is?
No wind at all. Ok, he's an,
another winner of
the Turing Award.
He headed up the lab,
the computing lab at Oxford
University for many years.
And now he's retired and
gone to work for Microsoft.
Uno 2xh. I thought there'd
be 2z when I said that.
And again, He's an
amazing person.
I think that between Don
Knuth and Tony Hoare,
you get most of the good ideas
in computing about
two-thirds of them.
And also I've been lucky enough.
I was at Oxford when
Tony was the head,
so I got to get to know him.
And I've said it
says Tony Hoare here
actually should say
Sir Anthony Hoare.
I should say Sir Tony now.
Okay. Any other questions?
Okay. So people who know
quite a bit are warning you
don't prematurely optimize.
Now having given
you that warning,
let's learn about how
to actually measure
efficiency and worry about
optimizing when we need to.
So here's an example
we saw before, right?
I said we could do fold l
from concatenate and
the empty list, right?
What does that do?
That builds up all your
parentheses to the left.
Or we could say fold R and
that builds up all your
parentheses to the right.
Which of these is better to do?
Well, if you remember appending
a list onto another list,
you take one step, Tikki, Tikki,
Tikki for each element
of the first list.
So the time to
append two lists is
proportional to the
length of the first list.
Okay? So if you work out
append of this list,
right first it's fall to
the left with the unit.
So the first thing we'll do
is append the empty list.
We'll append it to
xs. One will take
the result of that
appended to x is two.
We'll take the result of that
appended to X is three and so on.
So let's say all of
these lists each have
length N. So the empty lists
of course has length 0.
So this step takes,
that takes zeros
proportionate to 0 steps.
That's quick.
This will have write
access one has length N,
So the slip length N. So
to add that onto X is
two takes n steps. Go away, dots.
That will have length 2n to
add that onto X is three,
takes three n, and so on.
So we'll have all but one
of the list here so
that lag length m minus
one times n. When
we adding on the last
list to in general,
right, we've got n plus
2n plus 3n dot, dot,
dot up to m minus
one times n steps.
And you can do a little bit
of maths and discover, ok,
that means we have M
list of length n. That's
roughly m squared times n steps.
If M was the same as n,
if we're adding, concatenating,
enlist each of length n,
that's time n cubed.
Okay? But here, right,
if we do the folds the other
way, well, this has length N,
So that takes n
and then we add it
to the result of concatenating,
sorry, concatenated to the
result doing next ones.
The next list is also of length n
And the next 1's of
length n and so on.
So we've got enlists m times
concatenate together, right?
The last one gets
concatenated onto nil.
So we'll even do the last one.
So we have m lengths of length n,
and that takes order of n steps.
So if n is 1000,
that means the first
way of doing it is that
1000 times slower
than the second.
If N is a million,
that means the first
one is a million
times slower than the second.
Note what this means.
Say you've got a program
that's running a 1000
times slower than
another program.
Normally the program runs
in ten milliseconds.
So if it runs a
1000 times slower,
that means 10 thousand
milliseconds,
which would be about ten seconds.
So you don't need to
worry about optimizing
it unless you really care
about waiting ten seconds.
If you've got something
that's used on
the web by a very large audience,
ten seconds might be important,
but almost all the
time, you don't care.
Who cares if my program
takes ten seconds to run.
So if the size of your
data is around a 1000,
it's the difference between
a linear algorithm and
a quadratic algorithm.
The answer is, don't
care or runaway.
Okay? Alright, we're going
to learn how to runaway.
But right, if it is,
the size of N is a million, okay?
A million seconds
is about a week.
So if your program used
to run in a second,
it would now take a week.
That's a big difference.
At that point, you
really do care about
the difference between
quadratic and linear.
Okay? So that's the
important thing.
Almost always you don't care.
But if you've got a really
large amount of data,
then the difference can be
significant. Is
that clear enough?
So basically you shouldn't
even start thinking about
optimization until you've reached
a million pieces of data.
At that point it might
become important.
Basically, don't think about it
unless you're staring
at your terminal,
getting really bored, waiting
for the program to run.
That's the point at
which you might think,
oh, do I have a quadratic
algorithms here?
Maybe I should
change my full bells
to fold r so it becomes linear.
Okay? In fact, we
encourage folder as
the default for most things
in Haskell just for this reason.
So full fold are you concat,
You always with
concatenate use Fold
r. Okay, let's move on.
Now. Right? So notice
that none of the
navigation is working.
I hate that navigation working.
Wow, I really hope everything.
Okay, we're just going to go
through the lecture forward.
Right? So we've got this
thing called Big O notation.
Now showing you all that.
Notice that I just said,
oh, it's quadratic.
But I didn't say anything about
how long it takes to
add each element.
I just said it's about quadratic.
It's not actually the square.
Those of you who
know it's m times m
minus one over two
when you add up
the numbers from one to
m. So why did I just
say it's quadratic?
Why did I not care about
those differences?
Well, the answer is,
I want to show you some graphs,
but the graphs or
on the next page.
So I'm going to do this and
in the order I wrote it
down because my computers
being very strongly with me,
I don't know why behave.
That didn't fix it.
Nope, that didn't fix it.
So in a moment I will show
you a graph that will make it
abundantly clear that we
don't care about
constant factors.
We only care is it linear,
is a quadratic, is a cubic.
Those are the important things.
So we need a mathematical
definition that says,
I don't care whether the time
is 3n squared or five n squared.
I only care about
whether the time
is linear or quadratic.
So the mathematical
definition of that is
something called big O notation.
And in general, let g be
some kind of function.
Let f be another function.
So these'll basically
both be functions
of the size of the input.
So f says, give me the
size of the input.
I'll tell you how long it
takes to run your program.
G is giving an estimate
for f. And g again says,
give me the size of your input.
I'll give you an estimate for
how long it takes the program.
And that is what we want g to
be a good upper bound for f,
four big enough inputs.
So in particular, if there
are constants c and m,
such that f n is always smaller
than c times g of n for
every n bigger than m. So
there's some point at which fn.
It is always smaller than g of
n for some M and smelt some
C. So we're just multiplying
c by some amount.
And we're saying write fn is
always smaller than that,
as long as we've got a big
enough n. So for example,
2n plus ten is order n,
because 2N plus ten is
always less than or equal to
four n for all n greater than
or equal to five, right?
Because if n is bigger than five,
then 2n would be
ten plus ten is 20.
And for n is also 20.
So they're equal there.
And for everything else you
can see 2N plus ten will be
smaller than four n. Is
that clear to everybody?
Yep. Sorry.
I've just write 45 are exempt.
So 5-years our choice for m,
four is our choice for C,
and this is a choice
that makes it work.
There might be other choices
that make it work as well,
as long as there's a
choice, we're done.
Now, why do we care about that?
Taco small? Actually
know, do go small.
Maybe, Haha, maybe
it will work now.
Let's find out. Maybe
now I can navigate.
Well, it's a bit clumsy,
but it's better to be able to
navigate the not to navigate.
So that's what we're gonna do.
Okay? So here's a graph, right?
Here is 2n and here
is 0.5. n squared.
Ok? So this says we double,
sorry, each increment
and then adds one.
But this says we only
adding a 0.5 times N
squared rather than n.
So if we look at it,
we see, oh yeah,
n squared is quadratic.
So as soon as we pass,
what was the number
here? 30 to 40.
As soon as we pass 40,
it will take more time with the
quadratic one than
with the linear one.
And if you think about
it for a minute, right?
There will always be numbers
such that if this one's linear
and this one's quadratic,
no matter what this
thing in the front
is and no matter what
this thing in the front
as linear will always be
faster than quadratic once
we go far enough out,
once we get a large
enough n, right?
So in this case it was 40,
but it might be further out.
Why do we only care
about large N?
Well, what did I just say?
I said you only care
about the running time.
If you've got like a
billion steps than
you might care about
the difference
between linear and quadratic.
So that of course is a large N.
So that's why we only
worry about large N,
because it's only
for large amounts of
data that the runtime is really
going to become an issue.
Oh, I see it skipped
over the graphs.
I did have the graphs
in the right place.
Oh good. Right. And notice
this was n versus n squared.
Right there at that, right?
For n versus n square,
it passes much more
quickly, right there.
It passes at one, right?
So as long as n is
bigger than one,
linear will always be
faster than quadratic.
But then if you add
in a constant factor,
like we make this
width w And this 1.5,
it will still pass it,
but now not until 40.
Okay, so it takes much
longer to pass it,
but it will always pass it
for large enough numbers.
So basically, we don't care
about the constant in front.
We only care about linear
versus quadratic, right?
And that's a huge
simplification, right?
It's much better to only worry
about linear rather than
quadratic instead of to
have to worry about.
Oh, wait, did it take
three microseconds to process
what element of
the list or did it
take it six microseconds
to process one
element of the list.
But you'd have to do careful
measurement to find that out.
We don't care.
If you're worried
about efficiency,
all you need to do is say, wait,
is it linear or is a quadratic?
So that makes it much
easier to address
efficiency issues and to
focus your attention
appropriately.
Another way to do this,
which has taught by
Don Knuth is right,
once you have your
program running,
there are various tools
you can get that will tell
you where your program is
spending all its time.
You can just use
those tools and find
out where your program is
spending all this time.
Almost always.
It will be in a very tiny
portion of the code you write.
So you've written a
1000 lines of code,
but there are only 15 lines in
the inner loop that's
using up all the time.
Then you know where to
focus your attention.
Ok, so that's why
we're concerned with
big O notation, right?
And so right here,
lots of examples, right?
O of n. We just say that
when we mean it's linear,
it can be a n plus
b for any a and
b quadratic an squared
plus bn plus c,
We don't care cubic a
and q plus bn plus c,
n plus D. Also,
this means if it's logarithmic,
we don't carry about
the base of the log.
I think the log base ten is
three times smaller than
log base two rights actually
log base two of ten smaller.
So this is a smaller
number than this one,
but they're both again
within a constant factor.
So we just say O log n.
We don't say whether
it's log base
two or log base ten,
because we don't care.
Any questions about that.
How many people are
happy when I say things
like quadratic and log in,
how many people are
scared of mathematics?
Okay, because it's the
Wednesday morning classes.
So that should tackle
some of the things like
quadratic and log in case
people have any
worries about that.
Right, so, right, this
keeps going, right?
So linear is much
better than quadratic,
which is much better than cubic,
which is much better
than quartic, right?
If you've got choices between
algorithms that run
in quadratic time,
cubic time, quadratic time,
and linear time, linear time one.
Obviously. That's if it's
easy to do both, right?
If it's hard, find,
just use Quark poetic
time, it's not a problem.
And then the other sets
of runtimes that we
often deal with,
our log n, linear n log n,
and order two to the n, right?
And you can see right,
the differences
here are dramatic.
Log n is practically
constant time.
Log n is always going
to be very small.
But what's the biggest
number you can name has
a 100 zeros log
base ten of that is
less than a 100, right?
So log n is always very small.
Linear compared to log.
Linear looks huge, right?
You've got a choice
between linear in log.
Log is much better.
N log n, That's kind of worse.
And then, right, this is
practically a vertical
line upward, right?
Two to the n grows very,
very rapidly, right?
Two to the ten is already a,
1002 to the 20 is
already a million.
Two to the 30 is
already a trillion.
So even dealing with 30
things, if you're using,
if you have exponential
complexity,
that's going to
become intractable.
Which is kind of interesting.
How many people can think of
a problem they were given
recently where we told than here,
do it this way.
But in fact it was
exponentially slow.
Yep. White, the tautology
or SAT-solver that we did said
look at every
possible environment.
If you have n variables
in this proposition,
just look at all ways
of assigning true
and false to those n variables.
So there are two
possibilities for
one variable, for, for 28,
for 316, for 4 trillion
if you had 30 variables.
So we have a nice technical
word for trying to use
that technique on a
proposition with 30 variables.
We call it in tractable.
Nice word, right? In tractable.
So intractable is the polite way
that you can say
to your colleague.
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
Right? Intractable means this
is going to take a long time.
You might be waiting a week for
your output for
just 30 variables.
That's why we only gave you
things with five variables.
Now there are other
techniques like
SAT solvers that are much,
much better than exponential
time almost always.
So this is actually with
the amazing things that
happened during my career,
right when I started out.
The answer was, Oh,
trying to find out if an
arbitrary proposition
is satisfiable,
that's exponential time,
that's intractable, right?
So we just didn't go there.
Now, SAT solvers have
made these intractable
problems tractable.
And many people write,
logic is just suddenly
become much more useful.
Cuz you just write out a
really big formula that might
have 30 or a 100 variables in it,
but it's SAT-solver
can solve it for you.
So all of a sudden,
things that were
intractable had become tractable.
So SAT-solvers or just
an amazing development?
Yes. All right.
So is a SAT-solver
worst time exponential?
Yes. But trying to
find the ones that
actually make it exponential
or it's really hard.
It's almost always
perfectly fine.
It's really weird. Okay. Any
other questions about that?
Yep.
All right.
Is there any difference
between two to the
n and ten to the n?
Yeah, no, those are not within
a constant factor of each other.
So there it matters. Very
good question. Thank you.
Okay. And another example,
which we saw before
is doing things
sequential or in parallel, right?
So we talked about doing
sequential addition versus
doing parallel edition and
parallel edition, right?
We've broken it up so that
you get this binary tree.
And if you've got, in general,
if you take, if you're
depth d in this tree.
So here we've gone
down to depth three,
and they're already 12345678.
And you can see, oh, yeah, you'll
double the number of things you
can add for each one
increment in the step.
That means the time is
logarithmic. Wow, that's great.
That's practically constant.
So if you've got lots of
parallel computers for
doing your addition,
it goes from taking linear
time to logarithmic time.
And remember I showed you this is
how MapReduce works, right?
And that's important, right?
If you're doing something for
the entire worldwide web in
linear time, That's right,
really large N. So if
you can do something for
the entire World Wide
Web in log n time,
that's a lot better.
That's basically what makes
Google and Facebook and
everything else work,
is that they can
exploit parallelism to
do things at the scale
of the entire web.
And then of course, you've
got names for these rights.
So log n is called logarithmic,
ON is called linear n log
and doesn't have a
name, it really should.
And it's important because
all good sorting
algorithms take time n
log n. And then two to the
n is called exponential.
And example that we just saw was
tautology checking or
satisfiability checking.
If you don't use a SAT-solver.
Ok? Any question, okay.
So that's all I want
to show you about.
O numbers. Are there any
questions about that?
Fantastic. Okay, so now we're
going to put that to work.
I'm going to show you four
different ways to model sets,
each of which has a
different time complexity.
And they go from being very
simple to being really complex.
Ok. And part of what
I just told you is
almost always the really
simple one will be
perfectly fine.
So we're going to model,
the first way to model
a set is completely
obvious. It has a list.
So here's a little module.
I'm going to define
some operations on set.
So the set type,
an empty set and
adding an element to
a set and converting a
list of elements to a set,
and checking whether an element
appears in a set, right?
This is what we
call lm for lists.
Checking whether
two sets are equal
and checking whether an
element appears in a set.
So we'll Brett,
We're going to just
define a set of a is
just a list of a.
Empty will just be
the empty set will just
be the empty list.
If we want to add an
element to a list,
we just cons it on to the front.
If we want to convert a
list of things to a set,
haha, they're the
same representation,
so we do nothing at all.
If we want to check if x
is an element in the list,
we just use elem.
And if we want to check
if two sets are equal,
okay, this gets a bit trickier.
What we need to check is that
everything in axes also,
they might be in
different orders, right?
They might be have duplicates.
So is the set 12 equal
to 2121 as a list
with those be equal.
Hands up if yes. Hands up if no.
February, we've got about
equal numbers voting and
most people have no idea.
So, right, two lists
are equal if they have
the same elements
in the same order.
123 is the same as 123.
It's not the same
as three to one.
How many people are
familiar with sets?
You've gotten a
bit of set theory.
How many people have never
heard the word set before?
Good, how may people
have never seen heard
the word set but have no idea
what sets are. Just a few.
Okay? But for those few,
Just to review, a set is
a collection of things.
All we care about is does
it appear in the SAT?
We don't care about order.
When we write them down. We
don't care about duplicates.
So 12 would be a set with a one
in it and a two in
it to one-to-one.
See, there's a two in it.
There's a one in it.
The twos in it
again, I don't care.
Right. It was already in it.
You can't be more in it.
Right? It's like
being more pregnant.
Nope. You've either got it
or you don't have a two.
And same for the one.
So are the sets 12 and the set
represented by 2121,
are they equal?
We'll take a vote
again. How may say yes?
How may say know much better,
how many are unsure?
Much better, okay, so what
we need to do is check that
every element in the
first set appears in
the second and vice versa.
So that notion is called subset.
So we say one set is a subset
of another if it's smaller.
So 12 is a subset of 1234,
because 1234 has a one in it,
it has a two in it, but it's
got some other stuff as well.
So we say it's a proper subset.
In that case, 12 is also
a subset of 1212 is
not a subset of one because
one is missing the two.
Okay? So we just need to
check subset and that's easy.
When is X is a subset of wise?
Well, let's look
at each x and xs,
and that must be
an element of y's.
So for each x and xs,
we check whether x
is an element of y,
and that must be true
for all of them.
So we end it together.
So if we give this, if xs
is 12x and wise is 213,
this will return true, right?
Because we look up the one
that's an element of 2.1.3,
we look up the two,
that's an element of 213.
We add them together
and that's true.
The fact that there's also a
three doesn't show up here.
But our 12213 equal,
no, because if we do
subset the other way
around, that will fail.
Then we'll try to look for the
three in 12 and we won't find it,
so that and will fail.
So we just check to check
that they are the same.
You just check that X
is a subset of wise,
meaning every element
in x appears in wise,
and that wise is a subset of x's.
Okay? O, right,
and check then I'm just
checking this property.
What I to do, I
did a little test.
So I just make up a list wise.
I pick all the odd ones out of
that list and turn it into a set.
And then I check that
for each x in Wise,
is x an element of S?
Well, it should
be, that should be
true if x is odd and
false otherwise.
So I've just made up a list,
pick all the odd
elements of it in it,
turned it into a set,
and then check that when I,
for everything in that
original list Ys,
try looking it up.
And if it's odd,
it should be there.
And if it's not, it
shouldn't be there.
So I'm just checking that my
set operations worked properly.
Now we can look at the
times for these things.
Right? How long does empty
take it's order one.
It's constant. How
long does insert take?
It's also order one.
How long does set
take? It does nothing.
It's order one.
So these are all really fast.
How long does element take?
Well, you've got check is
if the first element in the list,
the second element in the list,
the third element and list
down the whole list
before you can say no.
So this is going to be
on average half the
length of the list.
If you're lucky.
On the worst case,
the length of the list
if it doesn't appear.
So this is order n
for sets of size n At
equal is again going to
be order n for sets of
size N. So the
timings are constant,
constant, constant,
Wow, that's great.
Linear, linear, not too bad,
at least it wasn't quadratic.
Okay? Now here's a different
way of representing lists.
That people also you, so normally
people look at that and they say,
oh no, that's too simple,
I could never do that. It's fine.
It's perfectly fine to
represent sets as list.
It's okay. You are
allowed to do that.
Just make sure that for equality,
equality not by checking
whether the lists are equal,
but by checking this,
whether each is a
subset of the other.
But as long as you do that,
everything's fine.
Okay, question.
Really good question.
So you could have written
x drawn from x's,
but the type of xs is set.
Does that work?
That's a really good question.
In general.
No, it doesn't.
So why was it okay
for me to do it here?
It's okay because look
how I've defined set.
So set of a is just a list of a.
So that means it works.
Alright, but we need to it,
what we're going to learn is you
can write bits of the
program where some of
them know that
Saturday is list of
a and some parts don't know that.
So we're doing the
implementation.
The implementation knows
how the set is represented.
So it's okay to
treat it as a list
because we know it's
represented as a list.
That's a really,
really good question.
Did I answer your question?
Good. Excellent
question. Thank you.
So the next way we can do it is
we'll again kinda
represented as a list.
But this time we're going
to have an invariant
which is successive elements
in the list are increasing.
So the list is in
increasing order
and it increases, it
properly increases.
So you don't have to
elements the same and
a route to now the list 123,
there's, sorry, the set 123,
there's only one way to
represent it as the list 123.
It's gotta be in
increasing order.
There have to be no duplicates.
So empty is just at the four.
Whoops, insert is different.
I have to keep it in order.
So if I'm inserting
something into the empty
list, that's fine.
I get the list with
that one thing.
If I'm inserting it into a list,
y cons wise, right there,
three possibilities.
X is smaller than y,
finds ticket at the front.
The old list was in orders of
the new list was in order.
X is equal to y. Haha,
it's in the list.
We don't want duplicates,
throw it away, just
keep the old list.
Or x is greater than y, Alright?
Stick Y at the front because
it will be smallest and
recursively insert x into wise.
Does everybody see
how that works?
And then what was set do?
Well, you sort the SAT and
then remove duplicates.
Suggest sort it,
and take the knob,
which are both already
defined for us in the
standard library.
How do you check if something
is an element in the list?
Okay, we can do a
little bit better now
in that we just, It's empty.
No, clearly there's
nothing in it.
If x is smaller than
y, we can stop.
We'll never find it.
If x is equal to y, we
found it, it's true.
And if x is greater than
y, okay, it's not y.
But let's look at
the tail of the list
and see if it appears
there recursively.
Ho, ho and look Equality.
Now, we just check the two
lists to see if they're equal.
And I realize I said
something that was a complete
lie before and a bad lie.
So let me fix it.
How long does it take to
check if two lists are equal?
Quadratic, right?
Because lm takes time
proportional to the
length of this list.
Of course we could do this
a number time proportional
to the length of this list.
So if these lists are
both about length n,
we have to look up
an element from
this one about n times.
So this is not linear,
this is quadratic.
So when I said it
could've been worse,
it could have been
quadratic. It is worse.
It is quadratic.
What have we got here
for the other one?
If we order them,
order one, great.
What was order one has
become order n. Bad.
Nub of sort of axes.
Case sorting takes time n
log n. Finding the knob.
What's the list is sorted?
Finding the knot is linear,
but not in the standard
prelude, doesn't know that.
So it just looks at
the first one, says,
if it's in the list,
and that looks at the second one
said is it's in the list.
That looks at the third one
and says Is this enlist.
So nub is quadratic.
You could rewrite this
to be order n log n,
which might be
important for some it,
depending on the
size of your lists.
This is going to be linear.
And this is now linear
rather than quadratic,
just comparing two
lists for equality.
So people often by default
think the simplest
possible representation of
a set is as an ordered list with
no duplicates. But that's wrong.
You now know how to
be even simpler.
Representing a set by a
list sometimes is fine.
Sometimes it's better
because adding
an element is order
one rather than order
n. But sometimes it's
worse because comparing
lists for equality is
quadratic rather than linear.
So if you're putting
in lots of elements
and hardly ever
checking for equality,
then lit than a plain
list is full line.
If you often check for equality,
you probably want to use
an ordered list
with no duplicates.
Now, there are two other
great representations,
but we're out of time.
Come back tomorrow.
See trees and balanced
trees. Thank you very much.