Okay. Good morning.
It's now 1110 I the
projector's incredibly bright.
I'd like to stand here in
the middle and I can't
because I get blinded by it.
So I'll just stand slightly to
the side so I'm less blighted.
Good morning. Ok. So I
spoke to some people.
I know some of you have
a data science tutorial
at the King's buildings
and that's why some of
you were leading early.
Does anybody plan on
leaving early today?
Who doesn't have that?
Right? Don't, don't tell me now.
But men ask all of you in future
if it's very disruptive
for people to leave early.
So if you need to leave early,
please come and tell me
before class and tell me why.
And just for the next week or so,
I'd like to data science
people to do that as well.
So I've got a sense of exactly
how many there will be.
So anytime if you
need to leave early,
let me know for the
data science people
after a week or two,
I'll say, okay, you
don't need to let
you know anymore.
I know about it.
I've also gotta be contacting
the person who teaches
data science to see if
we can sort this out.
Obviously, you should not be
put in a position where you
have less than ten minutes
to get between here and
the king's buildings.
I guess the problem is it's math
teaching it rather than
physics or geography.
Okay. Are there any questions?
Yes.
Right. This is
a very good question.
And the question is, you've done
the tutorial the way you should.
And then you look at
the tutorial solutions
the way you should,
and they differ. Oh, dear.
Does that mean that
you got it wrong?
So the answer is no.
But you have heard me jump
up and down or seen me
jump up and down
about maintenance.
Buzzword, which means it's
important that your
programs are readable.
So if there is a solution in
the tutorial That's a lot shorter
than yours solution or a lot
easier to read than
your solution,
then you should think, aha,
there's a better way of doing it.
Pretty much every
program you can write,
there's more than
one way of doing it.
The important thing, of course,
is that it is correct.
So you're given a
solution that you're
told is correct and
you've got your solution,
how can you be sure that
they're doing the same thing?
Quick check, right? So I
strongly encourage
you to run the,
your solutions against
the given solutions
using quick shack.
And that would let you
check if they're the same.
So that's a really
good thing to do.
If they're different,
then you have
to think about what
you did a bit more.
If they're the same and they're
both about equally readable,
you're in great shape.
If they're the same and the
given answers more readable,
you might want to think
of what you're doing.
If they're, if they
both behave the same,
but your answer is more readable.
Please email it to
me and we'll give
the students a better
answer the next year.
Ok. Any questions about that?
And by the way, the way the
exams are marked again,
is using quick check to
check that your answers
correspond to what we think
are the right answers.
So by enlarge, if it's okay,
if it does the right thing,
then it will be accepted.
However, I reserve the right to
mark something down
if it's unreadable.
Okay, so you have to build
some judgement about
what is readable.
And often people don't
indent things properly.
Fortunately in Haskell, sometimes
if you indent it wrong,
it just won't accept it.
If you still manage to do
bad indentation that
Haskell accepts,
you will probably
get away with it.
But I wouldn't do
it if I were you.
Right. You don't want me
unhappy when I'm
looking at your exams.
And a good way to make me
unhappy is use bad indentation.
So try to use invitation
that looks neat.
Have good comments,
write clearly and so on.
Pick good variable names.
The alternative to picking good,
unbearable days is pick
really funny variable names
that will make me laugh.
Why? Marking your exam?
That's also a good thing to do.
You're holding up
your pen. Does that
mean you have a question now?
Okay. Any other questions?
Yes.
Right. Like so
this is a really good question.
I will actually go back
and bring this up so
you can see what's
being talked about
yet and that's okay.
Recent. That would
be lecture four.
Okay, so, right.
So you're talking about
these definitions.
And notice that
there are two ways
of defining this, right?
One is using the built-in
library functions.
So we use the library function
count from two to go from
one to n. And then
the library function product
to take its product.
Or alternatively, we can just do
a recursive definition that
desert straightforwardly.
Now this one obviously counts up.
So I made this one count up.
And that means you need n For
your debt final destination
and a number for counting up.
Now for factorial, that
since it doesn't matter which
way around you multiply
numbers right there.
Commuted multiplication
is commutative.
We could've instead
counting up, counting down.
We counted down,
then you don't need
a helper function, right?
You can just do factorial
a wreck of n in terms
of factorial rack of n minus one.
So I'll leave that as
an exercise for you.
But you could do factorial
by counting down.
However, that
doesn't always work.
And that's not the easiest way
to do it using library functions.
Using library functions,
it's much easier and
clearer to count up
than to count down.
So I did it all with counting up.
And that meant you
needed helper functions.
I did that for a
pedagogical purpose.
Pedagogical means it is
helpful with teaching.
In that, even if you can do
factorial without
helper functions,
in general, you will
often need a helper
function like this.
So I thought it was
important for you to
see that pattern of doing things.
So factorial in particular,
you could do by counting down,
but not in general.
But that's a really great
question. Thank you.
I will now admit I cheated.
Both of those people asked me
questions at the end of
the lecture yesterday.
I said, That's a
really good question.
Please ask me again tomorrow.
But in general, like please ask
your questions during class
rather than being shy and
coming up after class.
Because often you have really
good questions like these,
where it's really helpful
for lots of people in
the audience to hear the
answers, not just you.
So do be good about
asking questions
in class rather than after class.
Are there any other
good questions?
Yeah. You are.
Right. The tied to ask that we've
been waving your hands
like this and shouting.
I'll repeat the question.
So good point.
She says has an I repeat
the previous question so she
understood why just answered.
And the previous question was,
you did factorial with
a helper function by counting
up, but you couldn't,
you have done it with out
a helper function by counting
down and then the answer is yes.
Thank you. Any other questions?
Right. So the person coming in
late won't have
heard me say that.
If you have to leave early,
please come to me
before class and let me
know that you will be leaving
early because leading
earliest disrupted,
coming in late is
also disruptive.
So if you need to come in late,
come to me before class to
tell me that you will be
coming in late. Thank you.
Okay. Any other questions?
Yeah. Sorry. Just say
the question again.
Would you rather do
recursion then a loop?
Yes, because in a
functional language,
what you uses recursion loops
are what you lose in use.
Loops are what you use
in imperative languages.
I think saying lose instead
of use was a Freudian slip there.
So yes, we'll be using
recursion, NOT loops.
Loops only make sense in an
imperative language where
you change something each
time through the loop.
And we're trying to avoid that in
functional languages.
But good question.
Thank you. Or the
equivalent of a loop?
A loop for loop or something
would let you say
I'm going from one
to n. Notice that here
we can say that directly
by just saying one
dot dot n. So using
list comprehensions is sort
of the equivalent
of using a loop.
Yes. Very good question.
So the question is basically
if you write aware,
you're defining a name fat
that's only available locally.
Which lines this is available in?
And the answer is only the line
of definition Immediately above.
So if your two lines
of definition.
And then aware after both
of them that whereas
only available in the
second line, not the first.
So it's one where per line of
definition and that's because
the light definition
introduces some variables and
those can actually be used here.
So you need to have one of these
per line because this variable
actually can be used here.
So I, I didn't use
it here, right?
I pass to n In explicitly.
But I should show you one
other way of doing things.
I think, let's see,
that would be x.
This didn't happen.
We'll just copy this.
Got there already. So one thing
that you could do actually,
so again, I did this because it's
easy to understand this.
You understand, oh,
we'll do the same thing.
This is equally good.
Alright, if I say, oops,
what fact, 1.2.4, right?
They both do the same thing.
But what I can do also,
a different way of
doing this in fat.
When I do it this way,
this n right here,
we say this is the
point where n is bound
and is a formal
parameter procedure.
And it's bound here.
And that means we
can use it here,
but we're actually allowed
to use it here as well.
If I could rewrite this
in a different way.
And this should still
do the same thing.
Ooh, it does not.
What's going on here?
Oh, that was applied
to too many arguments.
So it is o act as applied
to too few arguments.
No, oh, yes, so it is alright,
because we'd have to change this
the integer to integer, right?
So you can also do this
in this than does.
So now fact is not
in scope, right?
If I say fact, it says What
are you talking about?
Variable mountain scope.
But if I say factorial rec
for it again gets
the same answer.
So again, I was showing
binding and separately for
fact, for pedagogical reasons.
But you don't need to do that.
You can just have a
helper function that
only has the thing that changes.
Because the thing that
doesn't change is in scope.
So you only really need
to bind at once question.
I'm not quite sure what
you're asking there,
but you're saying something
about where you saying,
could I define fact both
here and at the top level?
All right, so when I
do it all globally,
Does the order of
definition matter?
And the answer is no.
At the top level,
definitions can be in
any order whatsoever.
Good question. Yes. Is there
a way to make an else return?
Nothing. Okay. I'm giving
you some directions
for a function.
Ok? I'm telling you how
to compute a function.
And I tell you this is
a function of x and y.
And I say if x is less than y,
return x minus y,
and otherwise return y minus x.
So I give you 24. What
are you going to give me?
An entire function
definition mode function.
What's your name?
Dale. Function, Dale Of X and
Y equals if x is less than y,
then y minus x,
else x minus y.
And then I give you two
and for what you return,
sorry, two is x and for y.
So you return to and
if I gave you 53,
also too, cuz then you go
into the else clause, right?
So either way you subtract
a great greater
number for less than.
Now I give you the
following instructions.
Function Dale prime of x and y
equals f. X is less than y,
then y minus x.
Named Amy, silent about
the rest. Me, me, me.
So now you have no else clause.
And now I give you 53.
What do you do? Right
to the question,
what can you omit the else
clause and an if then else.
Okay? Because the question is,
how do you say do nothing?
And the answer is,
this is a functional language.
Everything is a function.
It returns a value.
Doing nothing is not an option,
you must return a value.
So there is one thing and
Haskell which some of
you have discovered,
which is the error function.
And what the error
function does is it takes
your laptop and it explodes
it so that there's no need
to return a value anymore.
And it leaves behind
a piece of paper with
the error message on it.
Right, so you can
stop the program
and give an error message.
So that's sort of
like doing something,
but that's the only kind of
side effect were allowed.
You always have to do
something later in the course.
So you might say, well, but boy,
I want to do stuff.
How do I do stuff?
So later in the course,
you're going to learn
about something big word.
Well, it's a short word,
but many people for
some reason find it
a scary word, monads.
So yet don't worry about it.
Later on you'll learn
about something called
monads and those
let you do things.
But what a monad is, again,
it's a value, it's a
set of instructions.
And for monads there's
an instruction that
means do nothing.
But right now, everything
has to return a value.
So there's no way to do nothing.
Talking about doing
nothing means you've sort
of fundamentally misunderstood
everything I've said.
Sorry. That means I
explained it badly.
What about the Maybe type?
The Maybe type is
something you will
learn about in two weeks.
And I guess the Maybe
type let you say,
well either there's a value
here or there's nothing.
Literally. But we're not
doing that just yet,
but we will get to that.
So that's a way to do it of
returning nothing as a value.
But will your forehead.
Okay, good questions but
we'll leave them for later.
So I misunderstood you
were very advanced.
I thought you were somebody who
is stuck in the imperative world,
we're doing, nothing
is important,
but we're in the
functional world where
you always have to return
a value and that's
the point I was
trying to make. Yes.
Okay. So I picked this
specific question here
is I've got aware
and underneath it,
indented I define two functions.
They both in scope.
And the answer is yes.
Either function can
use the other one,
and both functions can be used in
the main body that
the where applies
to how do you
say something is
not in the where?
That's what indentation is four.
So the indented
stuff belongs to the
where an unintended stuff
does not belong to the wear.
So Haskell cares about
indentation Very much so,
yes, you must get
the indentation writing
your Haskell program.
I know like getting
an error from a program
is just really annoying.
What's going wrong
here? I can't see it.
A typical source of errors is
the indentation being wrong.
And people are so
used to ignoring
indentation that doesn't
even occur to them to look.
So it's a very
mysterious error, right?
Programs are very techie
and that means you have to
learn to be equally picky.
So stuff that you
normally not think about,
like indentation or converting
a value into a list of values.
These are all things
we do very naturally,
but we have to learn to
unthink that and be just as
picky as the stove add computer.
My computer used to have
a different voice but it's
turning into a Dalvik.
I don't know why.
Yes.
Question.
Oh, how much
indentation do you use?
Right? So basically
the first thing
that needs to be indented,
everything else needs to
be just as much indent it.
That they're all the same, right?
So the question
is, does it matter
how much things are indented?
And the answer is no. But
once you start indenting,
everything else must
be indented the same.
You're welcome. That's so
nice to get a thank you.
Yes.
All right.
So there are two
ways of indenting
when using tabs,
when using spaces.
And the question is,
is there a difference?
And I think again
that Haskell is so
picky that it only pays
attention to spaces.
So you can't use tabs.
Yep. Dot SDO bed as I am.
Can you get away without Here?
Absolutely not. You need where
to introduce a definite.
So here this we
want n to the n scope for all
the rest of the definition.
And we can only do that by having
a where clause because if it
was a separate definition,
that end would be out of scope.
So you must use
wherein you must in
debt to write the
program in this way.
The other way, the other,
if you pass and
around explicitly,
you could do it either way.
That's I showed before.
Okay, good. Let's go
onto today's lecture.
That's fine. It's
okay to have lots of
questions about yesterday's
lecture. That's good.
That means you're
asking about all the
things I didn't explain.
Okay, so we're gonna do this.
Control alt S. Yes.
So today you get to learn
about three more functions,
select, Take, and Drop.
So let's look about selective.
So this double exclamation point.
So, right, this is funny
character exclamation point.
We use this in
computing all the time.
So saying exclamation point
all the time gets too painful.
So exclamation point we
often abbreviate as bang.
And question mark, we
abbreviate as query.
I think Bang sounds too
loud and too scary.
So there's another name that
people sometimes use for this,
which I think sounds much more
pleasant, which is clean.
So I'm gonna prompts
that says please.
So quote words unquote,
playing thing three means this is
a list and this means pick out
character number
three from the list.
And of course, where do we
start counting from 0, right?
Not one. So 0123.
So we get the character
d. Notice this is List.
Double-quotes. And this is
one element of the list which is
a character sets in single
quotes and to d. Ok.
So select, picks a particular
element out from a list.
Take, takes the
first three elements
from a list, counting from 0.
So 0 would be nothing.
One would be the first
23 would be the first
three characters.
So that would give you
WOR and drop three,
removes the first
three characters.
So that would give you DS.
Let's just do a
few more examples.
So we can do the list of
numbers from 0 to ten.
And if I select the fifth element
of that list, what will it be?
Altogether?
Now the fifth element of
a list of numbers from
0 to ten will be five.
Correct? The fifth number
in the list of numbers from
one to ten will be what?
Six? Correct. We can
also count down, right?
109 dot, dot, dot one.
Oops. No, that's not
how we count down.
That's how we count down.
So that counts down.
And then if we take that
list which is called it,
and select its fifth
element, what will we get?
Five, right, because it's 012345.
Ok. Any questions about that?
Yep. Just speak up
a little ladder.
Oh, what is it?
It is a key word that stands
for the very last
expression that you
type, correct? Good question.
Yes. Is it a white?
When I say you mean here,
is that creating a new list?
So I can't see where
you're pointing.
And when I write yet that
refers to the previous list.
It twinkling five.
Or does it remove
it from bullets?
No. No. No, no, no, no, no.
The list stays the same.
Sorry, what's your name?
Sheldon. Let's do one too.
Oh, that's okay. I make
I've given you a new name.
Okay, so let's Sheldon
BY a through z.
So if I say what is
Sheldon? It's that list.
If I say what is the fifth
element of Sheldon, it's that.
And if I say what is
the sixth element of
Sheldon, it's that.
And then if I ask
what Sheldon is,
it's still the same thing.
It's functional programming.
It's immutable.
Things don't change.
So you have to change your
mind to stop thinking about
mutable things and start
thinking about immutable things.
Sorry. You know, it's,
it's, this is a list
of values that's
returning one of
the values, right?
You don't, if we're talking
about the number 42, right?
That's always the number 42.
It doesn't stopping
some different number
when you multiply,
it's always 42.
And without that mass
would be really hard.
So it's exactly the same
idea and it isn't amazing.
It's such a simple idea.
But if you first learn
some imperative
programming language
like Java or JavaScript,
all of a sudden it
becomes a hard idea.
But it's a really easy idea.
You have to unlearn some of
the other ideas perhaps
that you've learned
for some of you?
Yes.
Okay. So I
apologize for using it.
I just did it to keep
from typing so much.
But it is a convenient
abbreviation.
If you say it, it
just means the value
of the expression on the
line in front before it.
So in this case, it standards
for the list 10987654321.
Ok. Shirt. Sorry, I
didn't explain that
well enough before.
Yes. Every single value
in Haskell is immutable.
Value means it's immutable.
Can you redefine?
Alright, so the question is,
can you redefine that
to later be a to q?
And the answer is no.
So it looks like you can
I guess I can say this.
Let Sheldon the a
to q. Whoops, to Q.
So I changed shell,
but no, I didn't.
This is a different Sheldon.
Right? The first one was
that children sitting over
there and the second one was
that Sheldon sitting
over there, right.
You know, lots of people
that buy everybody here
knows at least 25 people
named Sheldon, right?
So these two Sheldon's
or different
Sheldon, nothing ever changes.
That's the whole point of
functional programming.
Nothing changes.
You just have values and
the old values do not
change because your
computing new values
or binding new variables
to new values.
And here it's really two
different variables,
even though they
have the same name.
It always gives you the
most recent Sheldon.
That's right.
So Sheldon by default just
refers to the most recent
Sheldon that you talked about.
Almost exactly like in English.
There are loads of
questions here,
but I think maybe I
need to gallons I'll
just take one more
and then get all yes.
Sorry. You me.
Can I give playing
playing a list?
Right? So could I say
plink laying 123?
Nope. But the way you can do
that is say Sheldon playing,
playing i, i for index for
each i, drawn from 123.
Ok, good question.
That's what list
comprehensions are four.
Okay, let's go on.
So select, Take, and Drop
can be define with
comprehensions.
So select with comprehensions
would be formed lists of all x.
Remember way how you zip to
parent number with its index.
So here's the list of j x pairs,
where j is an index and X
is the element of the list.
And then if j is equal to i,
so these would be all the
things at position i.
There will be, there should
be exactly one, right?
If this is well-defined.
So we define a function v,
which takes a list of
one thing and returns
that one thing that would
give us an error otherwise.
So let's just try that out.
Let's just copy all
these into the code
so I can use them.
Alright, invitation has to be
correct. Yeah, that will work.
Okay. Oops. Let's make sure
the arguments stand out.
Okay, so now if I say, whoops,
select from a, B, C,
D, E, the element number, oops.
Try this again. Right?
What's that going to give?
C? Correct. And let's
just check that select
cop does the same thing.
Yep, I did the same thing.
And let's just check
how this works.
So this first, this zip of
0 dot dot with a, b, c, d,
e. And that gives us 0 paired
with a one paragraph b,
two paired with the three
paragraph D for paired with a.
Covered that yesterday.
Is that clear to
everybody how that works?
That's the key step.
So we get that.
And then we select from it by
all the x for jx bound
from can I say it here?
I'm going to say it such
that j is equal to two.
So this will be all the
pairs with index two.
So there'll be the 2i pair.
So two will be J, C will be x,
and we'll just return F.
So what does this return?
Like? This returns
a list containing,
just see, a list
containing, just see.
So there's a list
containing just c,
but we want the letter c. So
let's define a function the,
so the takes a list
with one element
in it and it returns
that one element.
So the of the list C
is C. The of the list
to is just to the
of the list 23 is the
computer explodes.
It says No, you didn't
tell me what that means.
And indeed what happens.
So that's it for selecting
an index, right?
That will always work,
but it could be 0 if we
try to index beyond
the end of the list,
let's see if these both
do the same thing.
I'm not sure they do actually.
I want the tenth element of
that list that says
nope, index too large.
I didn't quite
defined it that way.
But if I say select comp,
ABCDE, and ten, and again,
you get an exception, right?
It's not defined. Okay? Yep.
Explain in the second line.
V, right?
It's what's defined right here.
It's a function defined by
saying V. I could give it.
It takes a list of a
and it returns an a.
So takes a list with
just one element in it and
it returns that element.
Okay? So then take
is very similar,
says Get all the indexes
and returned the things
whose index is less than i and
drop is very similar tastes
says take all the
indexes and return
everything that's greater
than or equal to i.
And then we could also,
so there's an example
worked out in detail,
but we did one already.
Knows why work out this
example in detail.
I want to show you what
happens when we draw
j from x for this list of pairs.
So what I did is here,
I've replaced J by 0.
So we get j less than three
becomes 0 less than three,
and x by w. So we get
the list of W such that
0 is less than three.
Notes. You can do a comprehension
without a drawn from, right.
This will either be
if the guard is true,
a list of length
one or if the guard
is false, a list of length 0.
So yes, that, that's
what we get here, right?
The first three become
lists of length one,
last to become lists of length 0.
So there's an example of take
working very similar to I
showed you for Select Working.
And notice this is an
important idea, right?
Lists are defined recursively.
Right? So we say what is a list?
It's either, no,
that's the base case.
It's not recursive or
it's built with cons.
If it's a list of
a, the head will be
an a and the tail
will be a list of a.
For defining list of a
in terms of something
whose tail is also a list of a.
And that's really
neat because that
gives us an infinite number of
lists defined in just two lines.
And we can write
just two lines and
our recursive functions
and they will
deal with every possible list.
All you need to worry about is,
is it a nil or is it a cons?
If you explain what you
do for those two cases,
you're done. Our
definitions, right?
Like take, whoops,
take recursive,
which we'll get to in a minute.
We'll be recursive in the list.
Now we can do exactly the
same trick with numbers.
This is very helpful
with natural numbers.
So we can think of three.
What is three?
Well, you start
with 0 and you add
one and you add one
and you add one
to every number is
either 0 or a successor.
So its successors
written n plus one.
And just like we
talked about, the tail
of a list is a list.
The predecessor of a natural
number is a natural number.
So the predecessor
of three is what?
To write too is what
precedes three.
And the predecessor of two is.
And the predecessor of one is.
And the predecessor of 0 is.
The predecessor of 0 is.
Don't be silly.
0 is our base case.
So we've not defined
predecessor for
Zara because we're only
defining the natural numbers,
not all of the integers.
So select, Take and
Drop can be written this
way using recursion.
So we either have a base case
or we have an inductive case.
It's an inductive case.
We have to refer
to the predecessor
which will be i minus one.
So for select, right,
either it's a cons
and the 0th element,
it's the first ones that
would be x, or it's a cons.
And the i-th element,
if i is not 0, will
be recursively.
Look at the tail axes and
select the i minus one element.
Okay? And similarly, but wow,
wait a minute, what
about the empty case?
Select never works
on an empty list.
You're picking an
element out of a list.
You can't from the empty list.
So we don't need
the empty list case here
knows our base case is zeros,
not the empty list.
Take is very similar.
How do you take 0
things from a list?
Well, that's the empty list.
How do you take i things
from the empty list?
We will also define that
to be the empty list.
So if I say take five things
from a list of length three,
it will give me the whole
list of length three.
And then drop, drop 0 things,
right guys, I'm going to finish
three minutes so that
people don't leave early.
Guess. Instead of, you can
put an underscore here,
cuz you don't use the variable.
You can put an underscore here,
But either way it's
equally fine I think.
And then similarly drop,
if you're removing Xero things
from a list, it's the list.
If you're dropping eye
things from a empty list,
that just gives you
the empty list.
If you draw I things
from x cons, xs,
then you drop I
minus one from x's.
To remember, right,
with pattern matching,
it expanded into if, then else.
And let's, so write,
you can write things
compactly like this,
or you can expand
it out with doing
a no vast people
not to leave early,
but I will finish very soon
so that those of you who need to
get somewhere for your
next lab can be able,
we'll be able to do so.
So, and then we bind, right?
This x gets bound to
the head of the list.
This axis gets bound to the tail,
and then we compute
the body, right?
So this bit just gets copied out.
So similarly, if we do
a pattern like this,
it says, in this case we've
got two patterns here.
Say, well, if i is 0,
that's the first line.
Or if x is,
if w is called the argument,
w's is empty, then
do the empty list.
Otherwise, again, find x
and xs and then do x cons,
take i minus one of axes.
We can also do that with guards,
Of course a, right?
So here I just used the fact
that we've checked
for 0 already here.
I'm very explicit about it.
Here I'm to explicitly say no,
I'm expecting i to
be greater than 0.
This is a better way to
write things because
the order of equations
doesn't matter.
So here's one example
and then we'll stop.
So how do we do take
three of words?
So which line applies is 30.
Nope. So I'll bite I to three.
And is words the empty list?
Nope. So on in the
third line and i
is three and x is the
first thing which is W,
and X is the tail, which is odds.
So now I do acts.
So that's w cons, which is cons.
Take i minus one, i is three,
i minus one is two
axises or it's,
so take two affords.
Let's do it again
because this is fun.
So now the first letter of or,
this one doesn't apply.
This one doesn't apply.
X is o, x is this RDS i is two,
i minus one is one.
So it's zerocoins Take
one of RDS and so on.
See items.
And this also works
for infinite list.
So I'll just show you
that quickly and we
can stop there, right?
If I remember, if
I said 0 dot dot,
it goes on forever.
If I say, take the first
ten things of plus 0 dot,
dot, what will I get?
List from one to nine.
So even worked with infinite
stuff, isn't that fun?
You may all applaud and go away.
I got I believe
it is special. Right.