So we're moving along
at a clip, right?
First you've seen this
exciting idea of data,
things like numbers and strings.
And then you learned about
functions over that data.
And then you learned about things
like recursion as a way of
defining functions
and comprehensions,
as way of defining
functions over lists.
And now we've learned about
higher-order functions,
which captures certain powers
of patterns and computation.
We ended up writing the same
program lots of times over.
We wrote some, we wrote
product, we wrote,
and if all the elements
in the list, we wrote,
concatenate all the
elements of the list
by using a pen, and so on.
And they were all
the same pattern
which could be
captured in a single
function fold R. So
we've learned all
these important ideas.
But remember on the
first day we said,
here you've got some
data like the numbers.
Or here you've got some
data like the lists.
data like Booleans.
And they just sort of were
delivered from a
ball above, right?
Fill in his magnitude
when he designed Haskell,
decided there would be
booleans and decided
there would be
numbers and decided
lists and gifted them unto you.
But wait, you say,
I don't actually believe
Phil is all powerful.
I believe that I might
want my own datatypes.
Where does the data come from?
I hear you ask.
Alright, I don't
hear you asking it.
Where does the data come from?
So that is the exciting thing
that you're going to
learn today, right?
You should be excited because
between the idea of how
you do data declarations,
which I'm showing today.
And the idea of how
you define functions,
which you've seen before.
That's it. That's everything.
You are now all powerful.
We actually have a name
for that in computing.
So congratulate yourselves
after today's lecture,
you will be Turing complete.
And that's a technical word.
But what it means is you
will know how to write
any program that's sensible
to get a computer to execute.
So Turing complete
means as powerful as
anything you could
do with a computer.
That's sort of interesting
that that idea
could be defined in
the 130s just before stored
program computers were built.
We'll talk more about Turing.
Later. I will show
you my stand-up
routine entering on the last day.
But for now, the
important idea is,
there is this important notion of
anything that a computer can do.
This programming language can do.
And Haskell, among many,
many other languages,
is Turing complete.
And today I'm going to unlock
for you the last level.
Well, it's not the last level,
but it's the level that
get you to the full power.
So beyond this, everything
else is just nuance.
After today, you know how to
do anything that you
might want to do.
Are you ready or
some of your ready?
Let's try that again.
Are you ready?
Okay, so the technical name for
this thing is algebraic
data types or ADTs,
sometimes shortened
to algebraic types.
So you can do
everything this way.
So we'll go through
these in more detail.
But Booleans are
an algebraic type.
You can define
things like seasons
or shapes, lists, right?
Which are clearly
very important to us,
are an algebraic type.
Natural numbers are
an algebraic type
that's important because
how many natural
numbers are there?
Right? A lot to
the technical word for that
is an infinite number.
Ok? So there are
really a big number
of naturals and yet all of
them can be written down in
this one line that defines
all the natural numbers.
Expressions write Haskell is
about writing down expressions.
We can actually capture
expressions as a
Haskell datatype,
we can capture trees.
Trees are very important
data structure.
As a Haskell datatype,
there's a type called maybe,
which is what you'll use
if you have a function and
sometimes it knows how to
answer and sometimes it doesn't.
So you want either be able to
say yep, here's the answer,
I've got it or sometimes
want to say, I don't know.
So maybe is very good for
that pairs which
you've already seen.
And, and either type.
So this is like products,
it turns out, and
this is like SMS.
So ordinary operations on
numbers become lifted to
operations on data type thing of
an algebra of data types.
So all of these things can
be done as algebraic types.
Okay, is that clear?
We can all go home
now we can end the lecture early.
Would you want to see a
couple of examples in detail?
Okay, let's do that.
Let's start with the
booleans because this
is something you're
already familiar with.
So we're going to define
the Booleans and write a Boolean
is either false or true.
And not is a function
on Booleans.
And not of false is true
and not of true is false.
And then we have AND, and OR
as functions on Booleans.
And we've got false and
something, it is false.
But we've got true and
something that will just
be the something else.
So this tells us
immediately by the way,
that false is a 04 and,
and the truth, the identity.
And then for, or it's the
other way round false or
something is just the something
but true or something
is always true.
So as soon as you see a false,
it goes to False.
As soon as you see a
true, it goes to true.
And otherwise, if you've got
a list of things that
you're adding together,
you go down the list
and down the list.
Do these look a bit familiar?
Are there any questions
about that gap?
Is it weird that I'm using
functions to define functions?
So can you, so here I've
got three definitions
of functions,
but not, I'm just giving
the definition here.
There no more
functions that appear.
And here there's no more
functions that appear in, here.
There's no more
functions that appear.
Of course in general, you can
use other functions here.
Any other functions
that are defined,
including the
function that you're
defining If you're
using recursion.
So, but here there aren't
any other function,
so I'm not sure if I've got
understood your
question properly.
Right. So you're
thinking there must
be a place where it ends.
So far, everything
has been like that.
So the technical
word for describing
us aren't there some
primitive things?
So some primitive
values like say,
the numbers at some
primitive operations
on them, like addition.
And indeed it,
everything we've showed
you so far, that's true.
And for the computers
we use, that's true.
There must be some
way in which numbers,
like either integers or
floating point numbers
are built into Haskell
and operations like
plus and times on
them are built into
Haskell because they're built
into our computer hardware.
By computers have specialists.
They know especially
about those data formats.
They know specially about
operations on those data formats.
So at some point we
need to tell Haskell,
this is the one you're using.
Use this one because it's
built-in and it will be
much more efficient.
So your question wasn't
about is it functions
all the way down.
Your question was,
are there primitive
datatype somewhere that we
build everything up from?
And the answer is yes.
And you've seen that, however,
the most important
primitive data types
are Booleans and Naturals.
I'm going to show you how
to define those using this.
So the answer is,
we could do it all
with no primitives whatsoever.
Which is really important
because that says,
oh, anything I can
think of, I can do,
I don't need to rely on
the primitives that
somebody else work out
for me a long time
ago and that are built
into the hardware.
I can just do everything
all for myself.
However, if you want to
be a 1000 times faster,
you will use the
built-in primitives.
So that's a really good
question, is saying,
but wait, where do primitives
come into all this?
And the answer is yes,
you do want to use primitives.
You already know all about them,
things like numbers and Booleans.
But you could just cut
them from whole cloth.
There'll be a bit less efficient.
But we're not going
to worry about that
today because efficiency
is the devil's tool.
Okay. So that was a really
good question. Thank you.
Are there other questions?
Okay. And I'll just
show you that all
this works. Let's see.
Oh, that's interesting.
Okay. Yes.
So here's the actual code.
But notice that, right,
Haskell already
has a prelude that
defines bool and true
and false for you.
So here, here I've
just called them my bool
and my false and so on.
So now I've got my nought and my,
and, and my 4x.
And we've also got some other
things like equal and show.
So my knot takes my false to my
True and my true to my false.
And then my, and if
you give it my false,
it returns my false.
But if you give it my true,
it returns the second argument.
So this is just what we saw.
And all I want to show you
is that oh, that's weird.
Okay. Let's kill that one.
Let's have just one at a time.
But here it is loaded up.
So now I can say
something like my
true and my true and what's
that going to return?
Oh, oh, wait, wha,
wha it's my And of course
my true my and my True.
She doesn't know how to print it.
Ok. So if I just ask,
are these two thing that author,
okay, so much for trying to
show you how things
actually work.
There's one more trick
that will you learn later,
which is you can tell
Haskell how to print it.
And in fact, we've gotten
the instance of that
here, but I haven't
done that yet.
So that's why this
one's not quite working
the way we want it to
house. No, no, no, no, no.
Oh, I know what's wrong.
I just need to tell Haskell I
wanted to know how to show it.
So if I say deriving show,
now, let's go into
the right window.
There we go. Now it says
my true, as we'd expect.
You must add this
line deriving show.
If you want to show something,
I'll say a little bit more
about those lines later.
Yes. Yes, you can leave out
the prelude if you want to.
There's a way of doing that.
And I can't remember what it is.
I think it's, we can
try it. Let's see.
I think it's import Prelude.
And then what am I going to
import from the prelude?
Absolutely nothing.
And i, possibly if I do that,
no, right, then I've referred
to string somewhere else.
So that's not going to work.
Maybe if I take this
out, it will work.
Let's find out.
No, now it doesn't know
what show is and so on.
So yes, you can,
but then you need to
figure out which bits of
the prelude you need so you
can print strings and so on.
You can do it, but it
gets a bit fiddly,
Which is why didn't
do it. Okay, good.
Other questions. Yes. Can you
create your own type
classes, right.
So you've read ahead
and you know that
this is referring to something
called a type class.
And that just means
a collection of
things that are not
understood for many,
many different data types.
And we'll talk more about
how to do that later.
So yes, you can define
your own type classes,
but we won't learn
about that now.
For now, just know
that if you want
to have Haskell actually
able to print something,
you have to say deriving show.
Okay, good.
Let's go back to this.
So a couple of other
things we could do with
Booleans are check that they are
equal and also convert
one to a string.
So show bull would take false
to false and true to true.
And then you put this inside
something called a
type class and then
that it's actually this function
that it uses for printing things.
Add this one, let's just say, so.
What does equality return
o it returns a boolean.
Does equality makes sense
for Booleans? Yes, it does.
Are false and false equal?
Yes, they are, are
false and true equal?
No, they're not.
Are true and false
equal? No, they're not.
Are true and true equal
y, yes, they are.
Ok. So even something
like equality,
you can just define by hand,
it does not need to be built in.
Yes. Right? So
another thing that we
could say here is deriving IQ.
And show. There we go.
Oh, and then we need
the prelude back.
And then it works. You
can also derive equality.
And then it knows about
how to do things like Is
true equal to true?
And what's the antibody debate?
Of course, that for
ordinary booleans,
right? We were doing it for.
My booleans, right?
And that returns true.
Other questions. Okay? So you
don't need to do it just
for booleans, right?
You can do for your own things.
So you can have another
form of boolean, right?
Booleans for an
indeterminate logic
where you've got
three truth values,
true, false, and I don't know.
So you could do that, or here
an example is during seasons.
So we've got four seasons,
winter, spring, summer, and fall.
And then we have
an operation next,
which takes a season to season.
So the axes and after
winter is spring,
the next season after
spring is summer.
The next season after
summer is fall,
and the next season
after fall is winter.
And then we can
define things like,
what does it mean for
two seasons to be equal?
And now takes a
season to season that
it returns a bool, right?
Equality always returns a bool.
A winter and winter
or the same spring
and spring are the
same summer in summer,
the same fall and fall.
A. The say, if you've got
any two other things, right?
If one of these four
equation says and apply,
and the stupid
computer falls down to
the bottom of this list,
it will return false.
If they're the same,
we return equal,
and otherwise we return false.
Of course show is very easy.
Winter becomes winter,
spring becomes spring,
somebody becomes summer
and fall becomes fall.
Okay? We could also
have ways of converting
between seasons in integers.
So right to int,
we could say, OK,
I will assign arbitrarily,
winter is 0, spring is one,
summer is two, and fall is three.
And then from it is
determined, right?
Xero better go to winter,
one better go to spring,
to better go to summer.
Three goes to fall,
as you give it.
What happens if I get,
say from int a four,
what will I get?
Right? Says pattern match,
fail or failure to have
exhaustive equations or
something like that.
So we'll just say, sorry,
none of these 34 equations apply.
You will get it wrong.
Shame on you.
Ok. And then we've
got another wave
to finding next, right?
So previously we defined
next by being very specific.
But once we've defined
numbers, right,
we could just say as
converted to an integer,
add one, take it mod four, right?
So mod four means three plus
one is 44, mod four is 0.
So we go back to the
beginning again.
That's what the modest for.
And then convert from an IT.
And you've seen this
sort of thing before.
This is exactly how
you did shifting
in the CaesarCipher. Same idea.
Convert a character to a number,
add something to that number,
take it modulo to
get you back into
the list of 26 characters.
Then convert it back again.
So this should be fairly
familiar to people like this.
If it's familiar and go like
this if it's not familiar.
Okay? And then equality becomes
much easier to dissolve.
Fine, cuz we can say
two seasons are equal.
What will convert
them both to numbers?
And you can see by
looking at this, right,
that if the numbers are
equal than the seasons are
equal and if the numbers are
different than the
seasons are different.
So we can just convert to
numbers and then compare those.
Okay? Ready to speed
up a little bit.
So the next thing we can
do is our data types.
These things can have components.
So circle now takes
a radius and rectangle
takes a width and a height.
And notice I've
just radius, width,
a height, all just
different names
for the floating
point number type.
And I can compute an area.
So the area of a circle is
pi times the radius squared.
Whereas a rectangle with a width
and a height to get its area,
I just take the width and
the height, and I multiply them.
Okay? Now, I should give
you a few buzzwords.
Radius, width, height, float,
and shape are all called types.
In Haskell we have values
like 123 or the
list containing 56.
Those are values.
We have types like
integer, Boolean,
list of integer, list of
list of integer, and so on.
So these are all types.
Now, circle here and wrecked are
more like functions
we can apply them to.
So circle you give it
a floating point and it
gives you back a shape.
Wreck. You give it a
width and a height,
and it gives you back a shape.
So these are basically functions.
This is a right?
Weight by weight functions.
Yes, this is a function.
How many functions
this winter take?
Sorry, how many arguments
does winter tech nun,
right, the 0 cases,
very important.
So this is a function
of no arguments.
And another name for a function
of no arguments is value.
So in this case,
these are functions
that take arguments,
but they are very
special functions.
So they get a special name.
What's special about them is
we cannot only write them on
the right hand side of an
equal sign, like right here.
All right, we've got
things that are returning
different shapes.
And we'll try that again.
We've got things that are
returning different seasons.
And here in a moment
we'll see things that
can return different shapes.
But for right now.
What we're returning is a float.
But here we've got shapes.
We've got shapes on
the left hand side
of an equation in a pattern,
and we match against
that pattern.
So terms appear on the
right of an equation.
Patterns appear on the left.
Every function is a term.
So if it's a
function, you can use
it after the equal sign.
But only things that can be in
patterns can appear to the
left of an equal sign.
So special things go to
the left of an equal sign.
Their name for that special
thing is construct door.
Okay? So I'm telling you is
circle is a constructor.
Rect is a constructor.
If we go back winter,
spring, summer,
and fall, are constructors,
true and false are constructors.
So that means you can
use that anywhere.
You want to use a term
anywhere on the right
of an equal sign,
but also on the left.
So constructors are special.
Those are the only
things that can
go to the left of an equal sign.
Right? And I just want to check,
oh, I've got no examples of
functions on shapes
that return shapes.
That's horrible. Let's give
an example. Oops, yeah.
So right Frisbee,
check this works,
that's OK. And now I
want one thing that takes
a shape to a shape.
Well, one example of a
function that yields
a shape is something that takes
a width and returns a
Shape called square.
And what is square of w going to
return a rectangle whose width
and height are the same.
But again, right, so that loads.
And now I can say,
what is the area of a
square of size ten?
And what's the
answer going to be?
Yes, it's going to be 40 to know.
Okay. How many people think
it's something other than 42?
Okay. What is it? Speak up.
Oh, what us right?
Square is not a constructor.
So it begins with
lowercase letter.
There we go, a 100 because
it's a floating point number.
So it returns a 100.
That actually brings up a
really important point.
Notice that all of our variables,
all of our functions,
begin with a small letter.
All of our types begin
with a capital letter.
All of our constructors
begin with a capital letter.
The reason for this
is so that you can
tell immediately which things are
constructors and which things are
variables or functions, right?
That distinction is so
important that we actually
write them in a different way.
So constructors always begin
with a capital letter.
Functions always begin
with a small letter.
So when can you put
it in a pattern?
If it begins with
a capital letter.
Okay?
Okay, so we can then check,
are two shapes equal?
So two circles will
be equal if they're
both circles and they both
have the same radius.
Two rectangles are
equal if they're
both rectangles
and they both have
the same width and they
both have the same height.
How do we show a CR?
And otherwise they're not equal.
How do you show a shape?
If it's a circle, you say circle,
and then you follow it by
the result of converting the
floating point number r to
a string for rectangle,
say rectangle, and
then the width,
and then a space,
and then the height.
And notice that what
we're printing here is
exactly what Haskell expects
you to type in when you're
typing in one of these things.
And then finally, how do you
show floating point number?
If it's greater than or
equal to 0, just show it.
But if it's negative,
we better put some
parentheses around it.
And that's because if we
said rectangle minus three,
well, let's do circle,
circle minus three.
Sorry, if we say
circle minus three,
it's going to take
its circle minus
three as good say
that's ill typed.
Subtraction expects to numbers
and circle isn't a number.
But if we say circle
minus three, like that.
Oh, that's because I haven't
done deriving hahaha.
Try that again. Right, you
just print circled minus 3.
So minus signs are special and
need to be in parentheses.
Is all that saying?
Because otherwise, it'll think
you're trying to do subtraction.
We can take a vote programming
language design question vote.
So there are two
ways of doing this.
You can either say,
right minus sign is going to be
special and has to
be in parentheses.
Or you can say, unlike all
the rest of mathematics,
we will use a different
symbol for a negative number.
So minus means subtraction,
and we'll use a different
symbol for a negative number.
So Haskell uses the same symbol
for both and then needs
to do things special.
There's a different
language designed here,
standard ML, which just
prints the negative in
front of a number
in a different way.
How many people think
it's better to just make
minus especial case
and use it for both.
How many people
think it'd be better
to use a different symbol?
Ok, and how many people say I'm
not a programming language
designer, I'm not sure.
Give me a room of
a thousand undergraduates
like attest ansi,
which they made fewer errors on.
And then I'd know which to do.
Okay, I'm in the latter class.
Actually, white
people begun to do
these sorts of measurements
for programming languages.
I don't know anybody that's
done that experiment.
In fourth year, you can
do a fourth-year project.
Come see me if you want
to do that experiment.
Right? Okay, let's go back.
Okay, and then we could
make a test, right?
Like is it a circle?
Well fits a circle will say true.
But if it's a rectangle
will say false.
Or we can say things like
get me out the radius.
Radius, right?
If we give it a circle,
it will return its radius.
What happens here?
If we give it a rectangle?
Error, exhaustive
patterns, 88888,
don't do that, right?
So you must give this a circle.
Otherwise it gives
you an error width,
you must give it a
rectangle otherwise.
And notice that if
you use all of these,
you don't need patterns anymore.
You can always just
do things with
if-then-else and on the
right hand side of equation
and you're functions will do
exactly the same thing if
you write them properly,
but they will be twice as long
and half as easy to read.
So that's why we use
pattern matching.
Pattern matching is just
a really great idea.
And I realize I have to
tell you this right?
Pattern matching was invented
here in Edinburgh
BY ROD versatile,
used to be a professor
in this department.
So it's a great idea and you
all have to thank Rod
versatile for it.
I have to thank him too.
So now we can take right area.
We can either write it this way.
The circle if r is pi r
squared and the rectangle is
W5 take or we could
say if it's a circle,
then let R be the radius and
then return pi R squared.
Or if it's a rectangle,
then let W be the width.
H be the height and
Richard W times H,
or otherwise, return
an error message.
So we can do the same thing,
but it becomes much longer.
Ok? So our favorite data
type here is the list.
So can we do list?
Yes, it's just the same thing.
So list now takes a
type parameter, right?
This is a type variable and
it's either nil or a cons,
whose head is a and
whose tail is list of a.
And notice a is I type
variable and it begins
with a small letter.
So it's the same trick.
Type. Names begin
with the capital.
Type variables, begin
with a small letter.
Constructor names
begin with a capital.
Variables like append
value variables
begin with a small letter.
So capital versus small,
it's actually quite
important in Haskell.
And then append, right,
takes two lists and
returns a list.
And how is that defined?
Append of the empty list and y
is just wise append of
cons of x and x's and y's.
Notice the parentheses
here are really important.
Is cons of x and then
append of x's and y's.
And again, the parentheses
here are important.
So all the parentheses
there need to be there.
And you've seen exactly
that definition before,
but we wrote it this way using
double plus and nil and call it.
And all of these declarations
are legal Haskell except for nil.
So that's very, something
very special built in.
But you can define your own.
Again, if you
throughout the prelude,
you can define your own
thing called colon.
If you want to. Wait, wait, wait.
You told be constructors
have to begin with
a capital letter.
If it's all made up of symbols,
how can it began with
a capital letter?
So there's a very funny
I'm constraint in Haskell,
which is if you want to use a
symbol as your constructor,
it must begin with a colon.
And colon begins with a colon.
So capitals for symbols means
it begins with a colon.
So any type name or
any constructor name that's
infix must begin with a colon.
Sorry, that's made of symbols.
Okay? And then the
same trek, right?
You could define is null.
You could define, get the
head from a non-empty list,
get the tail from
a non-empty list.
We've seen all those before.
So all the same tricks work
and we can just do lists.
And then the other
nice thing we can
do is natural numbers.
So again, you can
say data a natural
is either 0 or it's the
successor of a natural.
And then you could say
power, for instance,
who takes a floating
point number and
raises it to a natural number.
So x raised to the 0th
power is always 1.00.
X raised to the successor of n is
X times, so successor of n,
and this is x times
power of x to the n.
So the way you'd
write that out as
a definition in Haskell is
x raised to the 0th power,
is 1, x raised to the nth power.
So this won't be 0 because
0 matches this line.
So x raised to the nth power is x
times x raised to
the n minus one.
At this point you could think,
oh, it would be nice if you
could just write
n plus one there.
And then just write end there.
And Haskell used to support
that as a very special case.
But they took it out. I was
sad when they took it out.
So this is the way you have
to do it in Haskell now.
But it's the same idea.
A number is either
going to be 0 or
it's the successor of
some other number.
And notice that it would take,
right, how do you
write down four here?
We successor of successor of,
successor of successor of 0.
Right? Writing down a million
would take a long time.
But it's very simple notation,
this idea, by the way.
So this idea you can do
every natural number
this way, right?
Natural numbers are
probably as old as people.
Certainly going
back to the Greeks,
they did a lot of
things with numbers.
So 2 thousand years ago
they knew about numbers.
But this trick,
this way of writing
down all infinity
of natural numbers,
that trick only goes to
the mid 18 hundreds.
So data kind thought this
up and p-hat gives Cephei
piano thought this up.
In the mid 18 hundreds.
They were the first
people to do it.
So it's fairly
recent. This trick.
Right? I love classes
where you get to
call something in the mid
18 hundreds, fairly recent.
So and then we can do things like
write adding or
multiplying numbers.
So if we add m to 0, it's m,
but we add m to the successor
of n. That would be
the successor of recursively
adding m and n. If
you think about it,
that will give you
the right thing.
Or again, for multiplication,
if you want to multiply
m by 0, it's 0.
Rightness, this tells us 0
is a right identity for addition.
0 is a white 0 for
multiplication.
And then if you multiply
n by the successor of n,
How will we do that?
We'll multiply m by n.
And now we need one more,
so we add m to it.
And then this is
how you would write
the same things in
ordinary notation.
And let's see, I have this here.
Let's find out.
Yes. We did that one.
Let's do. So what did I do?
It takes two nets.
So x and 0.
I call that m and n
by m and 0 gives us
m and add em to
successor of n gives
us the successor of
recursively adding n and
m. And let's just try it.
Is two plus to add the successor
of the successor of 0.
Well, let's do this more easily.
Let to be the successor of
the successor of 0
footprint to oh yeah.
Let's try this again.
Okay. Too. But SCAP escape he,
escape, escape P. Okay,
now print to that
gives us what we want.
The tension mounts, what
do you think will get j?
Ok, so you can go off and
play stupid computer and
see why it gives you that answer.
You all know enough
to do this now.
So all the things that we
thought were primitive,
we now know how to define.
We don't need to be given
numbers as a primitive.
We can build them up from
scratch using this technique.
We don't need to be given
list as a primitive.
We can build them up
from this technique.
And now tomorrow we'll
start learning how to do
new data structures like tree,
like trees and expression trees.
Okay. Thank you very much.