Good morning. Are
there any questions?
No questions.
Yes. Do I know the time that
the exams for every subject?
No, I do not. Okay.
Any other questions?
Okay. So last week,
oats decide to autoplay.
No, don't do that. Go away.
Try again.
Last week.
We were looking at
expression trees as
algebraic data types.
And we got through how to
do numerical
expressions like this.
And then we were on to
how to do propositions.
And we got partway through
what you couldn't do
with propositions.
And today I will do the
rest if there's time,
I'll tell you about infinity.
So before I get
started into this,
are there any questions
about expressions?
You're all really
quiet this morning.
I was expecting zillions of
questions about the
class exam tomorrow.
Subclass exam will
be tomorrow at 1110,
our usual meeting time,
and it will extend
for 35 minutes,
I think at 1 I said 50 minutes,
but that's because I forgot
some people get extra time.
So the exam is plan
for 35 minutes.
It's been 35 minutes
every year since 2003,
so I should have
remembered it was
35 minutes, but I forgot.
So the exam will be 35 minutes.
And you will have seen
that on the exam paper?
Yes. If you have not been
told to go elsewhere,
which you might have
been if you have
some special requirements
such as extra time,
the exam will be in here.
And it will be closed book.
And you should bring
a pencil or a pen.
Any other questions?
Oh, I'll just remind you now,
when you take the exam,
write your name on it.
Yes. Yes. Your hand is up.
Yes. Sorry. You need speak up.
No, you don't need to
give import that says
explicitly that you don't
need to get him ports.
Any other questions?
Yes.
Okay, so this
is a good question.
So if you're given a
function to write say,
called F And you even
its type signature.
And then you are given
another function G here.
So G does the same thing as f.
Do you need to write
the type signature
for G as well as F?
Well, strictly speaking, yes,
That's going to be the least
important part obviously.
Because that will
be fairly clear.
Yes. Do you have
to write everything you
import note you do not.
That was the same
question that was
asked previously where I said,
no, you don't need to give
importance on the classics app.
That was my fault for not
repeating the question.
Yes. Is it allowed to use fold?
Well, it's designed to be
answered without using fold.
So if you answer with fold,
you might get some credit for it.
But that wasn't the
intended answer.
Any other questions.
So I didn't repeat the
question by Hope that
was obvious from answered
the question was,
what about using
fold on the exam?
Yeah.
The question should
say which things you can use.
If it doesn't say
and you're in doubt,
ask individually, come over
because it should say.
Did you find any on the
past exams that didn't say
sorry, was there a question
on an exam that didn't
say whether you were
supposed to use
library functions are basic
functions and recursion.
Good. Well, after
come up and tell me
which exam it was and
I will double-check
that because that was mistake
if I did it that way,
I hope there will be
no mistakes this year.
Yep. Anything else?
But ok. Now,
that gets the class
exam out of the way.
The class exam right,
is part of your education.
So I will PV P2,
my favorite quote
from Mark Twain,
sorry, it's part of
the university, right?
And I'll repeat you my favorite
quote from Mark Twain,
which is, don't let school
get in the way of your education.
So the class exam is the school,
but we've got that
out of the way.
And now Jose interested in
education, learning stuff.
Yay. Okay, so any questions about
expression trees or representing
propositions as a data type?
Ok, remember, one of the
most important skills.
You will learn at university
is how to ask a question.
I'm sure some of you are confused
and you're not quite sure
what question to ask.
So you're just like this
not asking the question.
There's also the problem that in
the Scottish education system,
I think sometimes if
in primary school or
secondary school,
you ask a question,
the teacher, so it gives you
a reaction which is like, oh,
well you don't understand
everything perfectly
because you're asking
a question and all
the good students
understand things perfectly.
So you're not as
good as students,
so they start teaching
you not to ask questions.
Has anybody had that?
Very few people have had that?
I think more if you've had
that then are letting on.
So my job is to undo
that and to teach you
to ask questions.
I was once at Oxford sitting at
a job interview for a
lecture ship position,
very prestigious at Oxford.
And they did something,
No, I tell you this story before.
Now. They did
something very mean.
They made all the candidates for
the post attend talks by
the other candidates.
You usually make the
candidates give talks.
You don't make the other
candidates attend the talks.
But they did. That was
little standard
Oxford torture test.
And one of the candidates
asked a question that
every single talk.
His name is Richard Byrd.
He was the one who was hired.
He and I went on to
write a book on Haskell
together called an introduction
to functional programming.
So, so by all means,
don't ask questions.
If you don't want to be appointed
to a lecture ship at Oxford,
that's the way to do it.
Okay, so I'll ask again,
are there any questions?
Alright, let's see
if I can spark some.
So here was a datatype
for propositions.
So we're going to let names
or atoms range over strings.
So these will just be
the variables like P, Q,
and R. And their proposition is
either going to be a
variable with a name or F,
which stands for false,
or T which stands for true or
not applied to
another proposition.
Or, or of two propositions
or end of two propositions.
And or I spelled in
this funny way and,
and I spelled in this funny
way, connect with Colin's.
Can anybody remember why?
Speak up, raise your
hand if you can
remember why. Good, why?
Because, right,
so we can distinguish
constructors from
variables in a pattern.
Constructors always begin with
a capital name variables,
sorry, let me try that again.
Constructors always begin
with a capital letter.
Variables always begin
with a small letter.
And if you've got a symbol,
how do you make a symbol that
begins with a capital letter?
So this is very
funny convention in
Haskell that if it
begins with a colon,
it's a constructor
and otherwise not.
So colon is sort
of capital symbol.
Okay? And then we've
got this deriving here,
which says you can do equality on
these things and you can do
less than on these things.
You can also say deriving Show,
which means it will
print these things out,
but we're going to do our own way
of showing these things.
And then we're going
to use names as
an abbreviation for list of names
and end as an list
of name Bool pairs.
Why would we want a list of
name value pairs, right?
Well, every name
here as a variable.
And what we're saying here is
whether that variable should
be considered as true or
false when we're
working out whether
the proposition is true or false.
So far. P and Q is a
trowel or is it false?
Good answer. Like the answer
to the question p and q.
Is it true or is it false?
As I don't know.
And why don't you know,
because you don't know what P
is and you don't know what Q is.
P is true, Q is true,
P and Q true.
Now it's not true,
true, it's p and q.
So it's true. Okay, so those
are the sorts of questions,
maybe with a little
less violence in
the asking that we
want the computer to
be able to deal with.
Right? So show is just how
we're going to print
out a proposition.
So show converts a
proposition to a string.
So it's a variable.
You just give the variable name.
If it's f, will do F.
If it's TiVo duty.
If it's not, we
will do a tilde E,
which sometimes means not,
followed by the proposition.
If it's or will do the
first proposition,
followed by a vertical bar,
followed by the second.
And if it's, And we'll
do the same with an ad.
And for these last three,
we will put
parentheses around it.
So I'll put an open
parenthesis at
the front of the argument,
par and a closed
parenthesis after.
Is that clear enough that we
can actually execute this?
Let's go ahead and
get it running.
Oops. Let's try that again.
Just, let's get this set up.
I'll just make this
large enough to look at.
Okay, so we've type C,
this always breaks the
screen up into two and away.
I don't like Let's try
doing this differently.
No, it still doesn't that way.
Alright. Alright. Alright, so
here is show just
as we typed it in.
And then if we do,
let's get some testdata and
thank those who've down here.
So here's a proposition and
here's p1, a proposition.
P one says a and B
or not a and not B.
And
there we go.
So now if I say show prop of
p 0, what am I going to get?
Error? I hope I don't get there.
Let's find out. Now. So
I get a string, right?
And it's a and b in parentheses
ord with not a and not B.
And you can see
every time there's
a constructor like and or not,
or it puts parentheses around
it so that the structure
is absolutely clear
and unambiguous.
Okay? I could also just
print out what P itself is.
And notice that that
gives you this,
which looks a little
bit different but has
exactly the same structure.
And then the next important
thing is to evaluate,
to evaluate a term, right?
So we get one line
for each weigh,
each different kind
of constructor.
And noticed that means we've
covered all the possibilities.
And that's very important
when you're writing code.
You want to be sure
you're covering
all the possibilities.
I've seen lots of examples where
people like do the cons case,
but they forget to
do the nil case.
Well, you aren't covering
all the possibilities.
If you do that.
I see peak cases where there was
the nil case and two
cons is at the front.
And somebody said, Why do I
need the case for a
list of length one?
Well, because if you've got
two constants at the front,
you have at least two
elements in the list.
And therefore you
need to worry about
what if there's only one
element in the list?
So you need a one case.
Sometimes people have
a perfectly good case
for the variable excess in it.
It works for every single list.
But in front of it they add
a special case for
the empty list.
Why do they do that? Anybody now?
So very rarely they're doing that
because empty list behaves
differently than everything else.
Okay, but that's a very
unusual situation.
What you should always
check is the empty list
behaves the same as
everything else.
So when people have one
line that looks like this,
I'll just put them in
here for a moment.
Write f of nil equals whatever.
And one line that
looks like this,
f of x cons xs equals,
sorry, that of course
is what you should do.
But every now and then,
you'll have something
that looks like this.
Just f of xs equals something.
And they put in an
extra mine for now.
Why do people do
that? Anybody know?
Yes. Thought the function
doesn't faulty it.
That's if you need a
special case for this,
but they always does
the right thing.
So right, here's an example.
Par of xs.
Is this.
Just put a parentheses
around axes.
Why is this? There we go.
And let's say they put in
a special case,
which is this one.
Okay, why have people done that?
Why would you write
the function that way?
You've answered before, guess
hence up that over there.
Because if you didn't have
this line and we did
part of empty list,
we would get, no,
this is a list of characters.
So we've got the empty
list of characters.
So it would be open parenthesis
and then nothing and
then close parenthesis.
So it would be exactly that.
This does not change the answer.
So what you'd want to do it
if it changed the answer,
but here it doesn't
change the answer.
So why have people done that?
Why would you do such a thing?
Yes. Sorry, speak up.
To make the code more readable.
Right? So making the code
more readable is a good idea.
But in fact, this is
making the code less
readable because there's
more of it to do.
And looking at that, I would take
maybe it's doing something
special for the empty list thing.
You look at this when
you discover no,
it's not doing anything
special for the empty list.
But you want to design your code.
So if you're not doing
a definition by recursion where
you look at nil and cons.
If you're just doing it on axes,
which we do sometime,
you want it to
work uniformly for everything.
So you'd want to avoid
special cases like this.
It's more to read,
more to test, more to write.
So why are people
doing it this way?
Right when look over people's
shoulders and tutorials,
about half people do it this way.
Why are people doing it this way?
Yes. To make the
code more efficient,
actually, it makes the
code less efficient
because you need to test
for a special case.
It makes it slightly faster
in this special case.
But since almost never are
things nil every other time,
the pore stupid computers
that is saying is if
VIP List No itself
the empty list.
And that's a few more
milliseconds going on.
So it actually, to,
the suggested answer
was because it makes it
more efficient that the answer is
doing this makes
it less efficient.
If I normally don't
talk about efficiency.
So I should have given
a complete list.
It makes it more to
write, more to read,
harder to understand, more
to test, and less efficient.
Sorry, I left that one out.
Any other suggestions?
Yes. What people
are very good answer.
People are doing it
by force of habit.
And because they're
not used to treating
the empty case as uniform,
that they want to make
it into a special case.
So people have force of
habit for doing this.
I think that's a good answer.
That's why people do
it. And I'm going to
summarize that in
a different way.
The reason why people
tend to put in this case,
when they're writing things,
is because they are
doing it wrong.
And I've seen lots of you do it.
It's a very natural habits for
exactly the reason this person
has had its force of habit.
What does it do that advocate,
it's good to think about what
does it do on the empty case.
But relay, right?
You don't need here.
So if you've just
had an axis, right?
If you don't have cons,
if you don't need a
special base case
and you put this in,
always put a comment.
I really need this
because it's different.
I, and here it's not different.
But if the answer was
right in that case,
suppose to say I am empty, right,
then it's different, right?
And then always add
a comment like that.
So I know you're thinking about
what you're doing, right.
If you always add a comment for
a case that seems to
be covered elsewhere,
then you'll think about, wait,
do I really need this case?
Right? But the basic answer
to adding special cases
for special situations
is don't do that.
Make it work in general.
Okay, end of rant.
That to function.
So in this case, right
then those special cases,
just one for each constructor.
That's what you'd normally say.
And then for the subparts
are of the same type.
We have recursive calls.
That's what you'd normally say.
So for a variable,
remember I said, well,
if you're given p or q,
you need to know what p or q,
r. That's what the
environment is.
Four, so we'll look it
up in the environment,
will check that in a minute.
If it's f, just return false.
If it's T, returns true.
If it's not p, recursively
evaluate p, take its negation.
If it's, or recursively
evaluate p and q and
all of them together.
If it's and recursively
evaluate P and Q and
add them together.
That's all there is to it.
Notice that every time you
do recursive evaluation,
we also pass in this environment.
And then last we
need to say, well,
how do I look up a variable?
So you've got function
look up here.
It takes a list of
AB pairs and you give it
an a and it returns a B.
So in our case, we're going
to give it an environment.
Remember an environment
is a list of name
Boolean pairs where
names are just strings.
This EQ, EI here just means
whatever the Type a is,
it must have equality
defined on it.
Have we defined
equality on strings?
Yes. So that's okay.
So now how do we
look something up?
We just say, let x prime
and y be bound to each.
Pair in this list.
So x primes the first
element of the pair wise,
the second we do this once
for each pair in the list.
And if x and x prime are
the same, we found it.
So we just return y.
So now we've got the list of
every y for where
the first thing in the
list has the same name.
Now, we want each name
to appear once, right?
P is true, Q is false.
We don't want to do something
like P is true. Q is false.
P is false.
Because then we've
said twice what P is,
we shouldn't do this, we
shouldn't even do P is true,
P is true, Q is false.
We only need to say at once.
So we're checking that it
appears just once in the list.
So the list, you have
exactly one thing in it.
So we write it in
square brackets to me,
this is a list of length one
and X is its sole element.
And then we return
that soil element.
So then if we too, right,
It's told us that
right. There we go.
So I think we've gotten
environment and 0, we do.
So that says a is
false and B is false.
And now what happens if
we evaluate p 0 and n 0?
What should we get as our
answer? Let's find it out.
So a is going to be what?
Please don't all answer at once.
It really makes it
difficult for everybody.
Let's try that again.
So we've got here, a
is false, B is false.
I now have a point.
Stupid computer
is going to evaluate things.
And the first thing
it sees is this,
or there's an, or, it's an OR.
Okay. Great way.
Totally different
task that was shown.
Okay, wait, let's just do here.
It's, it's this or right.
So the P bit is going
to be this one.
And the cubit, it's
going to be this one.
And then it looks at the PPE that
and what do we do if the pivot,
we evaluate it using
the same environment
that was the one that
says a is false and B is false.
Okay? So we're going
to evaluate this.
Let's see what's there
or what's an end,
okay, it matches this line here,
it's an and P is
going to be var a,
and q is going to be var b.
And then we're going to evaluate
IEP and is the same as before.
Okay, so now I'm evaluating
P. Here's var a,
so that's this line here.
Oh, okay.
So X is going to be a and
I'm looking up at in E,
and E is a is false
and B is false.
I wonder what looking
up and acts as a.
So I'm going to look at a and
a is false and B is false.
I wonder what answer?
Oh God, I have no idea.
I'm a supercomputer. I just
do what it tells me to sweat.
It tells me to is.
Wait, wait. That's
a list of things.
Was the case nobody
potent in no case.
Does the computer ever say that?
No, it doesn't care.
Right? It just says,
Oh, okay, so x,
y's, that gets down to
a list of AB pairs.
It's this list right here.
That's what XYZ is.
And x that gets that
compound to a, okay?
So I just copy this out,
except everytime X appears,
I'll replace it by a.
And every time XYZ appears,
I'll replace it by
the list I was given.
So this will be and it should
copy out the V as well.
Alright, so just copy
that out like this.
And this is m 0 and this
is a is equal to x prime.
And then it will get
the answer, which is,
what will the answer be?
K, we'll take a vote.
How many people think
the answer is true?
the answer is false?
Okay, let's see if
democracy is correct.
Boo variable not in
scope the right.
I haven't defined V here,
so it doesn't know
what to do with these.
So that's fine. Let's
just do the same line.
Will take the V out.
Now what's this going to return?
It's going to return a list.
What listed will it return?
How many people think
the empty list?
the list containing true
and true to truth?
How may people think list's
containing one true?
I make people think the
list containing one false.
Okay, lots of one falses.
And that indeed is
what it returned.
Why? So right, the first time
around x prime will be a,
y will be false.
A x prime will be bound to a.
So a is the same as a.
So it returns a list without
wine it which is false.
Then the next time
around it's B and false.
So this is B, this is false,
and a equals B is
false or that element doesn't
appear in the final
list, it's filtered out.
So we just get one
thing which is false.
And then v is defined by.
So if we say v of the list false,
what are we going to get?
Just false. Okay? Again, it's
worth pointing out, right?
This is here because it says,
I want a list of just one thing.
This is here because it
says the type of the
argument is a list.
Not necessarily just one
thing, right? It's a list.
It could be a list
of a thousand pairs,
as long as the first thing has
type a and the second
thing has type B.
In our case, this
would be a string
and this would be a Boolean.
So this means a
list of any length.
But here it stands for
a list of length one.
So I've seen some people
get confused about that.
So in a tight
brackets mean a list,
but in a pattern,
brackets around just one thing,
mean our list of length one.
And that's the only place
you use brackets if you
want a list of some
specific length.
So it might be bracket x
will not be bracket x, y,
but it's going to give you a
list of a specific length,
not an arbitrary list.
Some people just say, oh,
put brackets around it.
That will mean it's list.
No, do not do that.
Okay. So are people
clear on how eval works?
So the next step
is we want to get the computer
to do our homework for us.
So what we're going to do, oh,
notice by the way,
what is this here for?
Why did I put that
in the program?
Nobody has any idea.
Yeah. Well, it just
returns a Boolean.
It returns true or false.
Perfect answer.
Like the reason this
is here, it's a test.
And I clearly went
through and tested
the code once, right.
And clearly I'm perfect.
So the first time I wrote
the code, It was right.
I never needed to alter it again.
Okay. So even for me,
that is not true, right?
I have to change the code
again and again and again.
And of course having changed,
I'd want to test it still, right?
So by writing the test here, y,
all I need to do is run
test prop and make sure
that that returns true.
That's designed to return true.
So you put tests in
your code so that when
you change the code,
you can do it over again.
Okay, it's really important to
be putting, testing your code.
You will be marked on this,
on the final, right,
on the final, I will
expect you to do
this sort of thing
with your code.
And on the final, you will
want to do this sort of
thing with your code because you
want the final to be right.
How do you make it right?
Test it should include tests
like this in your code.
And in fact, I put it in
the same form as things are
used for quick check
on purpose so that if
no, go away.
So I can say quick
check, test, PRP.
And it will say, okay,
passed one test, right?
It normally, remember it says
it's passed a 100 tests.
But quick check is
clever enough to know
that if you gave it no arguments,
it's going to return the
same Boolean every times.
It just needs to run this
and check it returns true.
So doing that is just
the same as saying,
Well wait, what did test
prop returned was true.
So I can just run test
prop. And yep, it's true.
Okay. Now the next thing
we're going to do is we want
to do our homework four.
So that means we want
to check whether
a formula is a tautology
or unsatisfiable.
So if it's satisfiable,
that means there is
some way to assign
true and false to
the different variables
that will give us,
that will give us true.
So what we want is to look at
all possible ways of doing it.
Ok, So we've got two variables.
How many different
ways are there that we
can assign true and false
to two different variables.
The two possibilities for
the first 12 possibilities
for the second one.
So two times two is four.
If we had three variables,
how many possibilities
would there be?
Two times two? I
need another hand.
Times two is eight.
So let's just check this out.
So we're gonna give it a list of
names that's going to give us,
give us all the possibilities.
So if we give it names a and b,
right there, four
possibilities here,
let's just check
the length, right?
That, that was a
list of length four.
And I'm actually
going to go back and
edit it so you can
see what they are
easily. Doesn't like that.
Alright? Alright, what were
the four things that list will
a is false and B is false.
Next was a is false,
and B is true.
Then a is true and B is false.
Last was a is true and B is true.
Okay, those are the four
possibilities that it found.
So how does it do that?
So thus it returns an XB pair.
So if the, if the list
has at least length one,
that acts as the head
accesses the tail.
And what it's gonna do
is Xs gets paired with
b for each b from fall,
the list false, true.
So we'll start with false
and then we'll go to true.
And then recursively
we do the same thing.
So in the course of
evaluating this,
we're going to evaluate ends
of this listed is just b.
Sorry. The list containing
just the name b.
And what's that going
to give us? Same thing.
So be paired with false
and be paired with true.
Wait for that to work.
Okay, axis b, axes
is the empty list.
Xs drawn from B and E be
drawn from these and they'll
all possible environments.
So we're going to say there's
one environment where there
are no variables
bound to no values.
So that's why this returns
the list of one thing,
which is the empty list.
We could've said empty, right?
That would be the
obvious thing to
say, then it won't work.
If we change that to say empty,
what will we get as the answer?
Will get no things loaded
because I've got
this drug curvature.
Right? If I say empty there,
what now do I get as the answer?
If I do end of a,
B, what will I get?
A may know. Yep. We'll
get the empty list.
Variables not in
scope and yes, it is.
I just loaded it. Oh,
no, I didn't fail.
No models or Oh, that's right.
Didn't load. Okay, try again.
And a, b, c. Why is that?
Well, for to compute that, right,
it had to compute ends,
be back, gave us the empty list.
So to compute that
it had to do this or
that gave us the
empty list, right?
So that's going to give
us empty because if we do
be paired with a Boolean value B,
cons onto e for each
be drawn from false,
true had each E drawn from ends.
The, the empty list of strings.
But we get the empty list.
The way to see this
is if you do x,
y for each x drawn
from 123 and each y,
how long is the
answer going to be?
Nine? Because the three
possibilities for
the first three possibilities
for the second.
Yep. If you count that
up, that's 12345678.
Yep. There nine
possibilities there.
So if I do, I know
it's boring y-type.
Now, how long is the
answer list going to be?
Six? Cuz there's three
possibilities for the first slot,
the only two for the second.
And now how long is the
answer going to be?
Three by three different
possibilities for the first slot,
but only one for the second.
And now how longest the
answer list going to be 0?
And you notice that in general,
if this list has length m
and this one has length n,
the total thing will
be m times n, right?
So if one of them has length 0,
the result will have length 0.
And by the way, the name for
this sort of thing is it's
called the Cartesian
product of two lists.
And the important thing
to note there is it
has product in it,
which is a hint, The length of
the result is the product
of the lengths of the arguments.
Okay? It's called Cartesian
in honor of re ne Descartes.
We did interesting
things with pairs.
So, okay.
So now if we do something
like ends of a,
B, B, C, D,
it's really hard to
type to misspell be.
Ok. How long is the list
from this one gonna
Bay site
16 to 42 possibilities
for a two for B,
two for C2 for day.
Two times two times,
two times two is 16.
Outright. You have to use
the right definition
that would outweigh.
I don't want to
count it. I'll get
the computer to count it for me.
Yes, has 16 elements.
Okay, do people
see how that work?
And very importantly, we
need here a list of length
one because the product of
know things is one, right?
Remember we learned
that for product,
product of know things,
some of know things has 0.
Product of know things is one.
This is a kind of product.
So we need a list of length one.
And in particular,
the empty list is exactly
what we want in this case.
So it's really important to think
through what you want
for the empty list.
And notice here, right, we
cover all possibilities.
Either it's an empty
list, is non-empty.
So recovering all
the possibilities,
as you'd expect for a
recursive definition.
And no special case, right?
This is just the base case,
but you have to think
carefully about
what the right answer
for the base case is.
So now, right, so there's some,
a couple of tests.
And then you can just define
satisfiability very easily.
Because you just, for each
possible environment,
for all the names in p,
you just evaluate P in one
of those environments.
And if it works for any of
them than it satisfiable.
So we guessed or them altogether.
You can guess how you'd
vary this together.
Topology. And then we had
to particular formulas,
right? P0 and P1.
So remember, P 0 is that,
is that satisfiable.
But the satisfying value of that,
there are actually several.
So if a is false and B is false,
what is the value
of this expression?
So false and false is false
or what's not a false?
What's not a false?
And what's true and true.
And thingy or true is true.
So it should be satisfiable.
And if we do satisfiable,
p 0, it says yep, it was true.
And P1 is either a,
it's both a and naught
a is that satisfiable?
Really? Let's just check.
So if a is true, this is true.
Ha, ha, we're on our way
and what's not true?
False, so true and
false as false.
Okay, that one didn't work,
but maybe the other one
will work if a is false.
So if a is true, now we did that.
When if a is false, this
is false and false.
False and anything
is false, okay,
we don't even need
to look at that one.
It's going to be false.
So it's not satisfiable.
And indeed up, let's try P1,
that would work
better, wouldn't it?
So that's false as we expected.
Notice it's very important to
type one rather than 0
when you want to type one.
And then, right, we're at time.
But just to see right,
we have this other
function names which
returned all the
names in the term.
You can go back and study
that one if you want.
Okay, so that's all I
wanted to show you today.
And I'm not going to wish
you good luck on the test
tomorrow because I don't think
luck should have
anything to do with it.
I wish you good knowledge.