Okay. So I went
into this very
briefly at the end.
Yes, it so we've got
the idea of a list.
And her two things that
help you build up lists.
One is called cons and
one is called append,
written as two plus signs.
And you will say have almost
the same type, right?
This takes an a and a list
of a and gives you a list of a.
And this one takes you a
list of a and a list of
a and gives you a list of a.
And one of the skills you
need to develop is to see these,
to see and remember these
pretty subtle differences.
If you're speaking
a natural language,
that's if you're talking
to another person
rather than to a computer,
it's very rare to make
a distinction between
a list with one item in
it and the item itself.
What are you buying at the store?
I buying yogurt and eggs.
I buying yogurt.
It all looks the same.
We don't make a difference.
But in computing, we do.
Right? So give me an integer,
one is very different,
then give me a list of integers,
right? Square bracket 23.
And these things are
again different, right?
One is very different
from square bracket,
one close square bracket.
So you can see, oh, of
course those are different.
But in language we don't
make that distinction.
But with computers we must.
So learning to be very picky
about things like this
is really important.
Sometimes I put is that
we're very clever, right?
And we just naturally convert
between these things very easily,
but the computer doesn't.
And indeed, I was reading
a paper yesterday
about saying, okay,
we made the computer automatically
convert between lots
of things and people
use it all the time.
And then the programs
get very confusing.
And there were lots
of quotes saying,
this is actually a bad way
to design your programs
because it makes it hard to
understand what's going on.
So computers make
picky distinctions,
and possibly that's the easiest
way to deal with things.
But this means you need to
learn to make picky distinctions.
So the way I explain
this sometimes
is you're used to being smart.
What you'd lead to learn to D is
stupid the way
computer is stupid.
So that's one of my
main purposes in
this class to teach
you to be stupid,
stupid in the right way.
So his example,
the number one cons onto
the list 23 gives us 123.
The letter L cons onto the list
IS t gives us the list L IST.
So for characters,
lists of characters,
we have a special
way of writing them,
which is inside double quotes.
So again, there's a difference
between single brackets,
single quotes around L,
which is a character,
and double-quotes round l,
which is a string,
also known as a list
of characters, right?
If you get this wrong, right,
any of these will give
you a type error.
So this colon is pronounced Cons,
short for construct,
because we're using
it to build up lists.
And double plus is
pronounced a pen.
And you knows here
I just wrote a.
And this a is what's
called a type variable.
And that's because actually
with this stands for,
is it has this tight
for any way in
which you can any value of A-U,
like if we can
choose a to be int.
And that would match this usage,
or we can choose a to be
char and that would
match this usage.
Okay, is that clear for people?
Yeah. Could you put a
list in an element?
No type error.
But you could have a list
of lift and then you could.
So let's try that out.
Right? So we can actually
do all of these, right?
All right, that gives us 123.
But if we do this zap,
you get more on message.
Oh wow, That wasn't even
what I was expecting.
Interesting. But you get
a long confusing message.
But basically it's trying to fit.
I see what happens.
Okay, let me show you the
next thing that we could do.
We could constants aren't with
less what could we cancelled
onto by a list of lists.
So we get that. Right. And then
of course it could be
a list of more things.
Okay? So you get a
list of anything
you like, including lists.
And just to show you right,
if we look at the type of ABC
that says its brightness,
it's not written
string, it's written,
it's a list of char.
And indeed if I write a, b,
c, That's also ADC.
Ok, any questions about
popped? Clear enough?
Then it comes out
as a type error.
Right? Because what it said,
it says here is the first
thing must be of type a,
but the next thing
must be a list of a,
and then you get a list of a.
So if you, if you tried
for this to be a list
of int and this to be a list
of it. It doesn't match
what you wrote them
in the other order.
As I said, the computer gets
very picky about things.
So people would be
fine with that.
Computer will be
very unhappy, right?
And we can just try that.
Right, is going to be
WE unhappy, right?
Because it's expecting,
say an int here and
elicit event here.
So this one's wrong
and this one's wrong.
And again, it gives you
a long error message.
By the way, the funny error
message that we got here,
but it was actually saying is OK,
you've given me a list of one.
So this is a list of numbers.
The rest of this must be a
list of list of numbers.
So too should be a list of
numbers, but it's a number.
And what's actually
saying here is, again,
I said sometimes
conversions are convenient.
It that we do have
conversions for numbers.
So you can write T2 and
it can be taken both as
an integer and a
floating point number.
And then here, and you can
define what two converts to.
So here it says, I
don't know how to
convert to a list of numbers.
That's the error
message it's giving.
It's a fairly confusing
error message.
What you should do with
error messages in
Haskell, what I do,
which is to re,
read through it if it's obvious
what's wrong and
sometimes it will be,
the error message
will give you help.
And if you read it and it
doesn't make any sense to you,
which is what often
happens to me.
Just ignore it and say, wait,
no, I know the rules
of Haskell, okay.
Telling me something's
wrong here.
Let me see if I
can figure it out.
Sometimes the error
message will be a help.
But if it's not a
help, that's fine.
You know, enough to work
it out on your own.
Yes. Okay. To you
saying it's unclear to you why
we do things in this
very uniform way.
So one goes onto 23 like that,
and then list of one
goes on to list of 23,
lists of different
numbers this time.
Like that. What would you
how would you want to put?
So are you saying, oh,
I only want to work with
numbers, lists of numbers.
I don't want list
of list of numbers.
I'm sorry, I'm not
following your question.
Oh, dear. No, that's no good.
Alright. Come up and
talk to me later.
We'll see if we can sort it out.
Okay. Let's move on.
Okay, so we have
lists of any kind.
And the computer's quite
picky about things.
So you need to be careful
to look for the difference
between a list
containing 11 itself.
These are different things.
And every list, right,
we call it collins because we can
use this to construct
every possible list.
So 123 is the same
as start with nil,
cons three onto the front of it.
Okay, that's a list
containing three cons,
two on the front of
that, that's list 23.
And then we already learned
that one cons 23 is 123.
Similarly, a list of characters,
like start with the empty list,
put T on the front,
put S on the front of that, eye,
on the front of that, put
L on the front of that.
Okay? So now I can give you
a recursive definition.
Right? A list is either empty,
which will just write as open,
close, or it's constructed.
And then we write it
with cons x, cons xs.
And we call X the head,
the axes, the tail.
And the head will be an element,
but the tail will
again be a list.
And then we can write
definitions which actually use
these in place of a variable.
So we'll see this in a minute.
But we can write nil as
what's called a pattern.
So that's more general,
that variable,
or we can write x cons, xs.
And what happens then is x.
If we pass a list here,
x gets bound to the head of that,
and Xs gets bound to the tail.
We'll see examples
of that in a minute.
This is doing what I
said, which is our case.
You can say something like
let my list B.
Let's just do this.
That's what she's
much more fun to do
this online activist called list.
I hate long names.
And I can say at this
point I've defined list,
say list, it gives me
back what I defined.
That list never changes.
By the way, that never
changes that list is
just always 1234.
Like functional
languages that are
immutable, things never change.
But wait a minute,
you say, I'll get
your question that
amount with thank you.
But wait a minute,
you say What? I can.
I can just do the
same thing again.
It different. Sc lists changed.
No, the list 1234 did not change.
What changed is here,
we're saying that this is
the name of this thing.
And here we're using the same
name for different things,
but this is actually a
completely different variable.
It just happens to
be spelled the same.
Okay, so it's like
Mark Twain's old joke.
I don't think Shakespeare's plays
were written by Shakespeare.
They were written by somebody
else with the same name.
So that's exactly
what's going on here.
These are just two
different variables,
but they happened to be
spelled the same way.
Of course, once you
introduce this one,
you can never access this went
again that's called shadowing.
What you've gotten
name and scope.
There might be other names in
scope that you can't reach
anymore because you're using
the same thing for both,
for the convention
is the most recently
defined one is what it refers to.
So you had a question.
You want me to be higher
so it's easy to see.
Thank you. Good advice.
Yes. Can we does it
delete the first list?
No, but you can't
reach it anymore.
And the way memory is used
is when it can't reach
something anymore,
it reclaims the memory.
That's called, that's
called garbage collection.
So yeah, once you can't
use something anymore,
it can reclaim the
memory. Good point.
Yep. Sorry. Speak up.
Can we for the first
three letters?
Oh, LET sorry.
Right. So if I just say,
I think if I say list equals 123,
it will get upset.
Oh, it doesn't. Okay.
Okay. Forget about wet.
So right. If you just, if you say
let variable equals expression,
it evaluates the expression
and bites the variable to that.
Yet say, variable equals
expression to say,
We can also just bind
a variable locally,
which gives us that.
But now a wait,
let me do it with
something different.
Now here if I say Fred,
it doesn't know what
Fred is, right?
It's only defying Fred
for in the scope after the
word in, but nowhere else.
So that's where the
let comes from,
is it's a local binding.
So it says the variables
defined here, but nowhere else.
So special thing in
the interpreter is you
can say let variable
equal gras without an in.
And that just means
the variable is
bound for the rest of the time.
Okay, so just conveniently
gives you a name for the
rest of the session.
If you can create two things
with the same name, like no.
So you're allowed to
reuse names and that's the
most recent one you defined.
Yet though there is
no option to say no,
don't let me do that once it
aims to find out,
let me redefine it.
That might be a useful option,
but we don't have that yet.
We redefine a list
by itself sideways.
Or could I make,
Could I bind list to
something that's different?
Like a different type?
Like the number 42?
Yes. Yep.
Sorry, you've used a
word there that I don't
know because I'm a
functional programmer.
You use the word change.
Could you explain
that to me, please?
Yeah. Oh, I see
what you're saying,
right. So what happens?
Very good question. What
happens if I do let x equal
three and let y equal x,
and let x equal four.
Now I'm going to type y.
What am I going to get?
Three? Why did I get three?
Y told you why?
X is just a variable here.
This refers to the variable,
this is a completely
different variable
that happens to be called x.
So at this point,
x was the name of this variable,
and so it gives you three.
That was a really good question.
Both of you are
used to imperative
programming will find
this very strange.
Most of you, I noticed,
murmured out three
rather than four.
So you're already getting
the hang of functional
programming.
That's very good.
Excellent question.
Thank you. Another question here.
White. So as long
as y is in scope,
this variable is still
in scope and that three
would not be garbage
collected, correct? Very good.
Yup.
Yup. Yup. That's a
very good point.
So let's try to put
this in this file.
And now I can say x equals three,
y equals x, x equals four.
And what's it going to say?
They say no, you
reuse the variable x.
So let us do this in a script,
but not in a Haskell program.
Right? There can
only be 1X in scope
and a Haskell program and it
won't let you redefine it.
Yep. Yeah, you can
reuse names in scripts but
not in natural Haskell programs.
Okay, let's move on. I meant
to focus on list today,
not variable binding,
but that's okay.
Right. All right,
so then I wanted to
show you about binding.
So now that we know
about variables,
we can do something like this.
Let, let x is equal
some list 123.
So as I mentioned,
you can put a pattern here,
so we can do this.
Let's choose different names.
So what's y going to be?
And what Y is going to be?
The L23, right?
Sub y is now one and
Ys is the list 23.
And now we can use this
to define functions.
I'll show you that in a minute.
Okay, and notice when I did this,
right, houses defied, okay,
a list is either empty
or it's constructed,
which means it's written x cons,
xs at its head.
X is an element, its
tail xs is a list.
Wait a minute. You
are defining list.
You have defined list
in terms of less.
This is very gay dress
warning, warning, warning.
So we all know from experience
that defining something in
terms of itself is not always
a sensible thing to do.
Nonetheless, right?
I told you yesterday about
two important principles, right?
Build small things
out of bigger things.
Don't, don't pay attention to
details or ignore details
that are unimportant,
also called abstraction.
This is the third
important things
I guess I have to
jump up and down.
Alright? Ok, that's done.
This is the third important thing
which is called recursion.
And what recursion means is
defining a thing in
terms of itself.
But that's dangerous.
It's fine. It's fine.
As long as the thing you
defined it in terms of is
a smaller instance
of the thing itself.
So yes, we defined list
in terms of lists.
But we're building a list
up from shorter lists.
And eventually we, so this is
called the recursive case.
This is called the base case.
And you knows, all
the lists we looked
at had a base case.
And that's essentially
why this technique works.
You define a list in terms of
a shorter list, then it's okay.
Yes. Sorry. Right. Each tail
then has its own head
and tail exactly.
On that. I've tried to look like
somebody somewhere must
have composited picture,
which is something
like an alligator,
which has a head and has
no body, has a tail.
And what is the tale of
that alligator compose up
ahead and another tail which
is just a, a and so on.
But I've never found a good
picture that looks like that.
So one of you can come up with
one, please show it to me.
Yes. What are the head
and tail of a list which has
just one element? Let's find out.
Very good question.
So here's a list with just
one element and its head.
You know what that is? And what
do you think it's
tail is going to be?
The empty list.
Ok, good question.
Indeed, here's an example.
We've got another function, null.
So null is either true or false.
And it does, it returns,
it takes a list and
returns a boolean.
And it's true for
the empty list and false
for everything else.
So basically either
no will be true
or we can take the head
and tail of the list.
Those are the two possible
cases, or in the base case,
it's empty or we're
not in the base case,
and then it has a
head and a tail.
So just using those ideas,
right to yesterday, I told
you about comprehensions.
Rise it, here's the
comprehension that gives you,
that squares every
element of list.
Actually, let's just do it.
Actually, it's right here.
Right? So your square boxes
is defined as x times
x for each x drawn
from axis, right?
Net squares, every
element of list.
Now that might have seemed
almost like magic, right?
So that's sort of a
whoosh explanation.
Let me show you.
There's also a Tikki,
Tikki, Tikki Tikki explanation.
So let me show you
the Tikki, Tikki,
Tikki explanation of what.
So here's the definition.
We're going to give a recursive
definition of squares.
And there are two cases, right?
It's either empty or It's a cons.
So if it's empty,
we can just return the
empty list, right?
How do you square every
element in the empty list?
That's still the empty list.
Okay? How do use where
every element in the
list whose head is
x and whose tail is x's.
Okay, well we can square
the head to get the
head of the new list.
And then, oh, this
sounds a lot like what I
was already asked to do.
Oh, if only I could just call
the same function on defining.
I can, it's called recursion.
Recursion, by the way,
isn't a very old idea.
So they idea, it
will turn out you
can also define natural
numbers this way.
And that was only done in
the mid 18 hundreds by
two mathematicians independently
around the same time.
Data kind and piano.
For this idea of
recursive definition is
really quite new, right?
Civilization goes back to
the ancient Greeks a
few thousand years.
This idea is only a
150 years old or so.
But it's a great idea.
You can use it to do literally
everything a computer can do.
That was kind of the first
great result in computing.
And that only goes
back to the 130s.
So that's it. You've
just learned how
to do everything a
computer can do.
Now, there's another way of
thinking of the meaning
of this, right?
We can say, here's
the same definition,
not using pattern
matching, right?
So we can say, okay,
we've got a list w's,
if it's empty, then to
square everything and it
just return the empty list.
Otherwise, let XP its head,
x is b its tail,
and then return x times x
and recursively square
everything in the tail.
Okay? And now you can see
o y pattern matching is
such a great idea, right?
Because this is much shorter and
much easier to read than this.
But it's a pattern matching is
just a very nice notational idea.
Doing definitions in this style.
And again, this is quite
recent As far as I know.
This idea was first
proposed by Rob Percival,
who was it professor here at
the University of Edinburgh
in the 19 seventies,
late 19 seventies.
So this idea is way younger than
I am and way older than you are.
Let's just check
that all this works.
Right? So now we've
got squares loaded in.
And I can check like,
no, don't do that.
Right? So squares
123 is indeed 149.
Squares, one through ten.
That's what we want. And
let's do squares wreck.
Yep, and let's do squares.
Cond. Yep. And then
the property we want,
remember I said do things
twice and check that
they're the same.
So that's what we're doing again.
And you notice that
here I've defined a prop
is property of squares,
is that for any list xs,
squares of xs and squares rack
of axes should be the same.
That let's make this
property stronger.
And squares of X's
should also equal
squares COND of xs.
And now if I load all that
up and I can just say,
okay, is that really true?
Make up a 100 random list for
me and check whether that's true.
Okay? Okay. Wait,
what if I made up
a different 100 list will
still be true? Still true.
Still true. Maybe it's true.
Of course, there are
an infinite number of
integers and an infinite
number of lists of integers.
So there are lots that
I haven't tested yet.
You might want to
actually prove it.
If you want to learn how to
prove it, you have to take,
take the class I
teach in fourth year,
which is about how
to use Abduh to
prove things like this question.
How does it know to call
the empty list one when
the atlas dissent?
What I've just said,
this is what it's doing.
Let's look in detail at
what's doing in that
might clarify the answer
to your question.
So how does the computer
actually do this?
So normally. So there
are other ways of modeling
what a computer does.
And if you're doing an
imperative program,
the monthly becomes quite
hard because you need
a box for every variable
and you need to change
what's in the box.
And you sort of need a
little animation over time.
But the nice thing about
functional programming is we can
just write it out in
a very simple way,
similar to what we
learned in grade school.
So we start with
squares wreck of 123.
Okay, and now, hello,
I am that computer.
I will execute this
program for you.
Here is the definition of squares
rec, which line applies?
I know it's tough. It's
site from the signature,
it takes a list of int and
returns a list of it is 123.
I miss the event.
It is yes, good,
good, good, good.
You're following the rules.
Excellent. No type error.
Okay. Which equation applies?
Is the list 123?
No. No, no, it's not.
Not that equation, is it? No, no.
Yes. Boom, it's the list 123.
What is its had its
head is named E, one.
What is its tail?
Its tail is Nin,
ie, the list 23.
So x will be one,
add axes will be 23.
I will now copy out.
I have now matched
the left hand side of the
equation. Good for me.
I will now copy it
out the right hand
side of the equation
using the variable values I
determined from the
left-hand side.
So x times x,
x is, let me remember this.
It's hard. Ox is one,
so x times x will
be one times one.
Colin will be colon, squares,
rack of axes, axes is me,
me, me, me thou list 23.
So this will be squares
rack of that list 230.
So i did step first, right,
to show you that 1-2-3 is
actually built up in
terms of cons a nil,
which makes it easy to
answer these things.
So now, right, x is
going to be one,
axis is going to be the last
two cons, three cons now.
So what we get, right,
x is one, x, this is this.
We get one times one.
And now we need to work out
what Squares wreck of 23 is.
So the computer goes again.
Ok, I need to work out squares,
rack of two cons,
three cons nil is it now?
Now, second equation matches
what is X this time, right?
Something completely
different, right?
This time x is to y
is x is this time
it's three cons nil.
So we do the same thing.
We're just going to copy
out the right hand side.
I will get two times
two colon squares
wreck of this list.
And you see that's what we get.
And then you won't
be surprised to
see this is what we get.
And now you ask how does it
know when it's reached
the end of the list?
So just by copying,
at some point, the tail of
the list is the empty list.
So that's what it
copies in there.
And at that point he goes, OK.
Now the first equation applies.
And so I'll copy out nil.
And now we're done.
Of course that is just an
abbreviation for that,
which is just an
abbreviation for that.
So you can always show how
your programs are
going to execute just
by writing out a series of
equations in this style.
Question.
Or what the computer
actually does is completely
different because
the computer hardware is
imperative, not functional.
So it changes all this.
But you don't need
to think about that.
You can think at a
lofty or higher level,
and you can think
of it in this way.
What actually happens in the
computer is very different.
But that's an important
point. That good question.
Yep.
So we saw an example
of that, right?
Let variable equals expression,
variable equals expression in,
and then another expression.
And these variables are in
scope here but nowhere else.
What is the what does it do?
It goes, oh, I'm, I'm not quite.
You always have to write
as an expression by envy.
In the Haskell
interpreter in a script,
you can just write let
variable equal thing,
but new to programming,
you could never do that.
It's always let variable
equals expression,
variable equals
expression any number of
times in some expression.
That's just how you
write down a let.
Yep. Sorry, what
is a stack frame?
I work at a very high level.
I have no idea what a
sack frame as Wait,
I'm the low-level computer.
I will get a very low level.
I know about stat. Yes, it does.
How does it keep from
allocating to Make it
might allocate to
make stack frames
that says out-of-memory.
Let's see, let's move on.
So you've seen how to do this.
Let's let me check on the time.
Right? We only have
a few minutes.
Right. So we've
done this testing,
so we can do everything
else we saw the same way.
So remember to get the
odd things we'd say x
for x drawn from
x's with OT of x.
And again, we can do
that with recursion.
So we can say odds Wreck of
the empty list is
the empty list or 4ths
wreck of x cons xs,
and these are called
guards again.
So we say if x is odd, do this,
and otherwise do this,
it just goes through
these in order.
And otherwise is actually
shorthand for true rights.
So we could write that
out as well, right?
So that says, okay, if it's no,
do this otherwise, right,
let x be the head and
excess B the tail,
and then check if it's odd.
Right? Do this, and
otherwise do that.
So we copy in the number if it's
odd and we just do a
recursive call otherwise.
And so as an example, we've
got our trek of 123, right?
That's 4xh wreck of this.
And we only have three minutes.
So I'm not going to go into
annoying, stupid computer mode.
But right exit down to one x is,
is this an odd if one
turns out to be true?
So we use this equation,
the one in blue, and again,
we just copy this out.
So we copy out X is one.
Odds wreck of x's
becomes o Rekha 23 nil.
Recursively, we do
the same thing.
So this time x is two,
x is as little as three
nill an odd if T2 is false.
So now we use this thing, right?
We don't put a cons there.
We just have odds Wreck of the
tail and we drop the head.
And then recursively again,
we do the same thing.
This time we get
three cons outbreak.
And then finally
we've got our trek of
the empty list. So we get that.
So we get that. Okay. Any
questions about that?
Yet? Oh, is there a way to
pronounce the vertical line?
You could say, if
you could say when,
you could say guard,
you could say bar.
Any of those is fine.
So you could say
odds wreck x cons,
xs when odd of x is equal
to x cons outbreak and otherwise,
nothing to pronounce there.
It's all trek of axis.
Ok, good question.
And same thing, right?
If we tested those, we
would see they're the same.
And then finally,
the other thing we
saw was summing up a list.
So again, we can find that
what is the sum of
the empty list?
It's 0. What is the sum of
the list whose head is x
and whose tail is axis?
Well it's x plus.
And then recursively sum up
the remainder of the list.
Then someone to
three becomes that.
Which becomes, so x matches one,
xs matches the tail,
which is 23 nil.
So we get one plus the
sum of the list 23.
And then we go through
the same thing.
So the head is two,
so we get 2x plus
the sum of the tail,
which is three cons nil.
And so then we get one plus two
plus three plus the sum of NIL,
which gives us one plus
two plus three plus 0,
which gives us six.
Guess. What? Why have
we chosen the sum of
the empty list to be 0?
Is that your question? Like
so if we're doing products,
we wouldn't choose it to be Zara,
we would choose it to be one very
important, a general, right?
Most operators had something
called an identity,
something that
leaves it unchanged.
So 0 plus anything is
the same as anything.
And so that's why we pick 0 here.
That's a very good question.
I'll talk more about
that in two weeks.
Everybody's getting antsy because
it's taught to ask me afterwards.
You're done. You now know
how to do wash using Tikki.
Tikki, Tikki, Tikki. Thank you.