Are there any questions?
Yes. Speak up.
In programming, what's a pointer?
Something you will learn
about in the next term,
we don't need to use
pointers in Haskell,
but they're very important in
object oriented languages.
Any other questions?
Yes. When the tutorial
tutorial for be available,
I think it might have
been put up last night.
I still have to review it today,
which won't happen until
it's not there yet.
It will be there soon by
the end of today, I expect.
All right. Any other questions?
Yes. People, if
you're all lumbering,
I can't hear the person
asking the question.
You don't have access to
the solutions for tutorial
to I believe they were
posted on the Learn
page. Is that correct?
Yes. You don't have
access to the Learn page?
Oh, I see. Only certain people
have been given access
to the solutions.
The permissions have been
set wrongly on them.
Right? So that the
access permissions
for tutorial to have been set.
Wong, thank you for
letting me know.
I will get that fixed.
I will write an email to
myself. No, I won't wreck.
Here's what you do. I just
told you I will fix it,
but I'm going to forget.
I'm a professor.
And what goes with that
is being absent-minded.
So do you know my email address?
It's on the webpage.
You know my last
name, my last name,
spell it. Easy to do.
So. I have a recommendation
for all of you.
If you intend to be academic,
I highly recommend that
you have a weird lastName.
It means that all citations to
your work actually go to you.
I have a colleague who's
a highly distinguished
named John use.
You can imagine what
difficulties he has.
There are even two
different researchers
in functional programming,
both named John Hughes.
So that can be an issue.
So I'm easy to find.
Please send me an email.
Saying just what you've just said
and I will make sure
to get it fixed.
If I forget the email will
remind me. Thank you.
Yes. You saw me on the street
and you didn't know few,
she'd say hi, you should,
and then I will
look very confused.
But yes, no, I like it when
people say hi to me, thank you.
If I'm with my wife.
She is a primary
teacher in Brazil,
sorry, secondary school
teacher in Brazil.
And about once a day
she get some message
on her social media saying,
I had you as my teacher 25
years ago, you were amazing.
You changed my life,
all of which is true.
She's a really amazing person.
So if you see me on
the street, say,
wow, I really like your classes,
you're changing my life.
And then I can sort of begin
to creepy even with her.
Okay. Thank you.
Great question. Any
other questions?
Right. I think you've been
told about in face before.
Is that right? So the in-phase
people wanted me to remind
you that in face exists.
So there are lots of
different resources
you can use in this class.
You have class where you can
ask questions on Piazza.
You have tutorials which are very
important for dealing
with your questions.
You have drop in labs every day.
And then another
thing is in face,
which is actually run by
informatics students.
So you can see in
very tiny print,
they've got their
when their schedule,
but I'm sure you can find that
here on their schedule online.
This is in the slides
for today's lecture,
and that's another resource
for you to take advantage of.
So again, I encourage you to
go to in facing to consider,
that's one of the places
you can go to get help.
Ok. Any questions about that?
Ok. And there are a lot of you,
you might have noticed this.
There are many more of
you than last year.
So we've always had a
difficulty in teaching
this course that there
are ME, excuse me.
We can't fit you all.
So your final exam,
as I believe we've been told,
is going to be online.
That's important to
me pedagogically,
because the whole point of
computing is that a computer
can catch lots of your errors.
And that you can write
your programs and
test them using things like
quick check to make sure that
you don't make any errors.
Talking about I'm not
jumping up and down anymore.
I'm hitting the table.
Talking about not making
errors is one of the most
important things I can do.
Because the tradition within
the field of computing and
software has been quite
different than the tradition
in fields like engineering.
In engineering, generally,
most of the time,
your car runs well and
fit doesn't run well.
You're surprised if you use
an app and it misbehaves.
Are you surprised?
Right, that wrong tradition.
I would like to teach you treat.
I would like to teach you
in the right tradition.
And that means you
use the computer as
a tool to get things, right.
And that's why it's very
important that you have access to
a computer on your final exam
so that you can get things right.
So I believe very
strongly in that.
But there's an issue.
There are a lot of you
there are too many of you
to fit in one room
equipped with computers.
We just don't have enough
computers to do that.
So in the past,
we've had two exams.
That means after right to
different final exams.
But guess what?
There are even more
of you this year.
So we have to have three exams.
And guess what?
The university is very inflexible
and it's scheduling and
we can't fit in three exams
during the exam period.
So what we're going to
do is have the exams at
the end of revision week.
That gives you relatively
little time to revise,
but it lets you get the
exams out of the way early.
So we want to make
sure that you are
notified of this as
soon as possible.
So exams will be on Thursday,
the fifth of December,
Friday, the sixth of December.
Those days will not change.
I have asked IF possibly we
can fit them all in one day
rather than in two days,
but I don't know if
that will happen.
Certainly they will
be on those two days.
We we want to make sure to notify
you as far in
advance as possible.
If there's somebody
who this yes question.
Oh sorry. That's very important.
I talking about the
functional programming exams,
the computing and logic
exams are done in
a different way.
I believe they're done on
paper and pencil as it were,
so that they don't
pose the same issue.
We do have rooms
large enough to crown
all of you into do a
paper and pencil exam?
Yes. And another question.
Are these exams or
the questions on all
these exams the same?
Why on earth would
I tell you that?
No, we take steps so
that it will not be
possible for people to
move answers from
one to the other.
As I mentioned to you
in previous years,
both exams have been different.
Guess. How long is the exam?
You know what i mentioned?
I'm an absent-minded professor.
I'm not sure I
remember correctly,
but if I'm remembering correctly,
it is two hours.
Yes. Where you'd be
using your computers or
the dice computers,
that's very important.
And the answer is you will
be using dice computers.
So you need to spend at least
a little bit of time with
dice computers so
you're comfortable
enough with them to
do the exam on them.
We do them on dice
computers for security.
You do not have access
to the internet.
During the exams, you will have
access to some
reference materials.
I don't intend that
you should need to
memorize stuff before the exam,
but I do intend that
you should need to
learn stuff before the exam.
Other questions?
Okay. If there's somebody who's
severely inconvenienced by that,
please do get in touch with based
on at least aware
of the situation.
I don't think we
can change things,
but I do want to
know if somebody has
been inconvenienced by us.
First tell you exams
are being during
exam period and then as
early as possible telling
you that they would
be a bit earlier?
Yes. Question. Can you
bring portable disks
and USB to the exams?
No. No. The idea
is we will provide
you some materials so you
don't need to memorize stuff.
But that is not to
let you bring in,
say all the answers
to past exams.
Any other questions?
Okay, good.
So that's the admin stuff.
So today's lecture is on
map, filter and fold.
I don't know if you've
noticed, but sort of
every lecture I get excited.
You know, this is a
cool thing that you've
never seen before and
it's really exciting.
But this is probably,
this is the whole point of
functional programming.
The whole point of
functional programming
is that you, well,
the whole point of
computing is that
you can abstract, right?
And we've learned a lot
already about abstraction.
Functions are, one of
the name for a function
is an abstraction, right?
And this is the first step.
So first you learn two times,
two is 43 times three is
94 times four is 165
times five is 25.
And then you abstract.
You say there's a pattern there,
which is you take a
number, let's call it x,
and you return x
multiplied by itself,
the square of x, or
even x raised to the second
power, the square of x.
But something you're defining
a new function in terms of
things you already know about.
That's called abstraction.
You've picked out a pattern and
you've given it a name squaring.
So that's the most important idea
in computing its
abstraction that you can
define functions that work for
any value that you pass to them.
And many of you are
probably used to
that EMBL Isaiah about it, right?
But that was a very
important step.
The Greeks didn't
have that, right.
The idea of algebra
where you come up with
a variable in a formula
and you can instantiate
that variable.
That wasn't until the
Arabs in the mid.
Oh, I can't remember where,
but somewhere in what we call
the Middle Ages finally came
up with the idea of algebra.
And that was done by Al qua
resume out of after
whom were named.
Two important things that
we work with every day.
Algorithm's name
for al cor is me,
not name for Al Gore.
And algebra also named
for our queries me.
So this idea that you
can have what we call
a variable and then instantiate
it to any value that you
have in your pocket.
So you just write down a formula
and then learn about
an instantiated.
It actually took a long
chunk of human history,
more than 1000 years
after the Greeks,
before we came up with that idea.
And that idea is absolutely
central to computing.
You've absorbed all of it.
Now, the key idea that
you're gonna learn
about today is
going higher order.
That's the key
buzzword for Today.
We are now going to
be of a higher order.
And what that means is not
only can you abstract
over values,
but you can also,
you can craft over every value.
And I'm now going to tell you
something very important.
Yes, this is important enough
to jump up and down four.
A function is value.
Okay? So functions are values
that we can pass around.
Just like numbers, just like
strings, just like lists.
Functions are values two.
And among other things,
that means you can
have a function that
returns a function.
You can have a
function that takes
a function as an argument.
They're going to get,
that's completely obvious,
right? Yeah, it is.
Once you've seen it, it is
entirely and completely obvious.
It only took us 2 thousand
years to get there.
Okay? And this is the key idea
behind functional programming.
By the way, this idea shows
up pretty early in the
history of computing.
The first stored
program computers
were built in the 19 forties.
The first models of that
came along in the 130s.
One by Alan Turing.
How many people
have heard of him?
Right? Lots of u.
One by Kurt girdle.
How many people
have heard of him?
Quite a few of you well done.
Add one by Alonzo Church.
How many people
have heard of him?
Fewer. Okay. So Alonzo Church,
he was actually first,
he came up with
the first model of
a computer in the 19 thirties.
And it was called
the lambda calculus,
and it was based
entirely on the idea.
So in lambda calculus,
the first one,
not only were functions values,
they were the only values,
everything was a function.
Even numbers were functions.
So this is a quite old
idea in computing,
even though it's a
relatively recent idea and
a very exciting idea in
the history of thought.
So you've got the Greeks,
they have some great ideas,
weight 2 thousand years.
And finally you get that
higher-order functions.
And so that's what
I'm going to show you
today. That was my tap talk.
So here's some patterns
we've seen, right?
So first we defined not
square but squares, right?
We had two different
ways to define it.
Squares of xs is x times x for
each x drawn from x's using
a list comprehension.
Or equivalently, you can
say the squares of
a list of nothing.
The empty list is the empty list.
And the squares of a
list whose head is
x and his tails, this axes.
You multiply x by itself to
get the head of the new list.
And recursively you
square the tail.
So those should both be
funding it milieu by now.
So go nadia.
Yeah, I'm bored.
One person is nodding,
three people are nodding.
Most of you are not naughty.
Does anybody want to ask
a question about these?
Okay. So you've
seen these before.
I believe even though you're
not willing to admit it.
Let's see another example, Ord.
So we want to convert
a character to its 4D,
which is its ascii code.
So the code for a is 97,
the code for two is 50.
The code for C is 992
greater than the code for a,
and the code for 3511 greater
than the code for two.
So, or it takes a list
of characters and
returns a list of
integers, right?
And with list comprehensions,
who'd be ord of x for
each x drone from x's,
and otherwise would
be order of nil is
nil else another name
for the empty list,
an ordered list whose head
is x and whose tail is
xs is order x for the head.
And 4ths recursively applied
of axes for the tail.
Okay. Do you notice a
common pattern there?
Say they noticed
a common pattern.
Right? So you've
got some function.
It might be squaring,
it might be 4D.
Maybe we can do that
for other functions.
And you're either write,
applying it to each
thing in the list here,
or recursively applying it
to each thing from the list here.
So now we call this
map and we say
map f. So now we're
passing in the function
as an argument.
Map f of xs is f of x for
each x drawn from x's.
And map f of nil is
nil map f of x cons,
xs, list with head x and tail xs.
We use cons again
to get a new list.
Its head is F applied to X.
And recursively, we map f over
axes for the tail of the list.
And there's some types here which
I'll go back to in a moment.
But let's see some examples.
So now we've got a third
way of defining squares.
We can say squares of xs is map,
square of x's, where square
of x is just x times x.
And similarly or IDS is
just map 4D over access.
Ok. Is that clear to people?
It's what you've seen.
It, it's a completely
simple idea.
And it's an idea
that's been known in,
to logicians since the 130s.
But as I say,
it's only that recent.
So less than a 100 years old.
Look, a newborn baby idea is dqD.
Ok? Any questions yet? Yes.
That's a really good question.
Is there a technical difficulty?
Why wasn't this used
in languages like C?
Yes, there was a
technical difficulty.
The people who didn't know who,
the people who invented
see, we're ignorant.
Ignorant in the sense that
they were not educated
in these ideas,
even though they were
developed in the 130s.
It took a while before
it became common
to teach first-year
students about these ideas.
In fact, right?
You guys are unusual.
There are relatively few courses,
the UK or in the
world where people
get this as the first
thing they learn.
You might learn it
in your fourth year,
but not in your first year,
but you guys get to learn
in your first year.
So the idea is we're not
widely known and that was
the main difficulty with
doing it. These days.
Languages like C plus plus,
The standards are being
modified to include
support for being able to do
exactly this sort of thing.
And indeed in C You can
pass functions around,
but it's not as neat or
easy as this good question.
Any other questions?
Yes. Ok. Good point to
you knows the difference.
So here I just said
map ord of axes.
And that's because 4D is
a function of the
standard library.
So it's already,
there is a function.
But here, I didn't
bother to bring in square
from the standard library.
I just defined it myself.
So you can do it either way.
You need a function name,
but you can either define
the function yourself
or you might have already
defined it, right?
I could just defined square
on the previous line
and then use it.
So it doesn't need to
be in a where clause.
I just need some definition
of squares so I can task,
I need a name for it so I can
pass it in as an argument.
Good question. Yes.
Very good question.
Is map a library function
or do you need to
define it yourself?
It's a library function.
You can just import it.
Very good question.
Yep. Can we,
can you pass an operator
to the map function?
We will see that shortly.
Yes. Very good questions.
Right? So I thought maybe
somebody would say,
wait, what's all this
stuff on the top?
Can you explain that to me?
Right? So here we are
getting the type of map,
of course has the
same type both times.
And we say it takes an
a to B and it returns,
sorry, and that takes a
list of a and then it gives
back a list of V. So
it's got two arguments.
And in this case,
the first argument
is itself a function.
So you see this is written inside
just as an arrow and a to b
function inside parentheses,
because otherwise
it would look like
you had three argument,
an a, a, B and a list of a.
So we have one argument
which is an a to b function.
And then it takes list of
eight returns a list to be,
of course these are
tight variables.
So if you apply map to
square, it works out.
The type of square is number two,
number in this case into int.
So it instantiates a
to B and B to be int.
And so this must be a list of int
and it returns a list event.
Similarly, whoops.
Similarly here, 4D takes a
character and returns an int.
So this must be a
list of character
and it returns a list event.
In this case, a is
char and B isn't.
Any questions about that.
Okay, and do you want to get
one example of how the
stupid computer
deals with all this.
Some people are nodding,
who's bored with the stupid?
Raise your hand if you
do not want to see
the stupid computer do this.
And if you do, okay.
Sorry, sorry, those
of you who don't,
you have to put up with it.
So where was my example?
Right here is how it works.
Here is map is defined
as a list comprehension.
Map takes two arguments.
One is F, its type is a to b.
Weight function.
Isn't that cool?
The second argument
is a list of a,
we're going to call
that acts as o.
We always do that. Okay, boring.
And the body of it is
the list comprehension
f of x for each act
drawn from axes.
Okay? So map of square
of one to three is,
let's just copy it out.
F is square, xs is the list 123.
Let's copy the open
square bracket.
And then f that becomes
square and x that becomes x,
vertical bar, that
becomes vertical bar.
And then acts that becomes x.
And drawn from that
becomes drawn from
an axes that matches 1-2-3,
so that becomes 123.
Okay? And I know
how to do square of
x for each x from one to three.
I just copy out the unit list
once with x replaced by one,
once with x replaced by two,
once with x replaced by three,
I've got square one, square two,
square three, which is,
this is list of one to 49.
I concatenate them.
I get the list 149.
That are all done.
Right? And if we're doing
it with the other
recursive definition,
it's the same thing but
more long winded map
of square of 1.2.3,
which equation applies is 123.
No, no, no, it's not.
It's 123. I'll list
with a head and a tail.
Guess it is, and the head
is H1 and the tale is
that list 23 to
now copy this out.
And so f maps to
square, f, sorry,
f binds to square and X binds
to one x as banks have L23.
So I guess copy X that
becomes square of
one and map of
f of x that becomes map
of square of x is 23.
So two cons, three cons nil.
And let's do it
again. That was fun.
So this time, f is
square and x is two,
and x is, is the list
consisting of three.
And the body is f of x.
So that becomes square of two
because x is 2x and f is square.
And map ethics is,
becomes map square because
f is square at xs is
three cons nil the list
beginning with three.
Do it again. So let's see,
is three cons nil the empty list.
Oh no, it's not. Oh dear.
Okay. But is it a list with
a head and a tail? It is.
And the head is three.
At the tail is the empty
list and we copy it out.
And f is square and x is three,
and map is map and f is square.
At xs is the empty list,
o k. You know,
I'm tired of always looking at
the equations in the same order.
I'm going to look at them
in a different order.
See, because it's
always the second one.
So is nil the same?
Does it match x cons,
xs. Oh, it doesn't.
Alright, does it match
this one better work.
Does it match nil, it dies.
It's the same as I copy this out.
I just get, no hope
That was easy.
That's the list square of one,
that's one, square of two,
that's four, square
root of three,
that's nine squares are easy.
I'm not going to go through
the details of that.
You all know that, right?
Yeah. Okay. And nil is ill and so
that's the list 149 Gay.
Okay. So it's just as
boring as it was before.
Okay. So that's map.
Now we've got, here's
another pattern
that you've seen a lot of filter.
So let's work out.
Let's define what the
positive numbers,
absolute positive numbers and
list one minus 23 are 13.
Notice I've actually removed
the negative number,
unlike one of the examples that
we gave you in one
of the tutorials,
where we forgot and let
the negative number in
the answer and you are all
quite rightly confused.
Sorry about that. So positives
takes a list of integers and
returns a list of integers.
And positive x is x.
We use list comprehensions x
for each x drawn from x's,
with the guard that
x is greater than 0.
So only take the ones
that are greater
than 0 and positive.
The recursive
definitions is positive.
The empty list is the empty list.
And other wise you've got list
with head X entails X is.
And then we've got two
possible conditions.
These are called guards.
Again, either x is
greater than 0,
and then we stick acts on
the head of the list and
recursively take the tail.
Or otherwise we leave acts
out because it's
not greater than 0.
And we just recursively take
all the things greater
than 0 in the tail.
Okay? You've seen that
pattern before as well.
Here's another example.
Digits takes a list of
characters to a
list of characters.
So we'll take each
x for extra from
x's where isdigit holds of x.
Or we could do a
recursive definition.
Digits of the empty
list is the empty list.
Digits of x cons, xs.
If it's digits holds,
then we stick x on the front
and recursively call digits.
Or otherwise, we just
recursively call the digits.
We leave out because
it's not hydrogen.
Again, you've seen
those patterns.
Not if you're bored
because you've seen those
before and you're very
familiar with them.
We're not giving you
guys enough tutorials.
You should all be nodding, right?
This should all be familiar
and boring by now.
So I'm just gonna pretend
it's familiar and
boring if it's not learned
enough so that it is.
So this is all familiar, boring.
So it's a pattern, right? We keep
seeing the same pattern.
So again, we can say filter of
p. So now I'm using p
rather than f. F
stands for function,
P stands for predicate.
So a predicate is something
that returns a Boolean.
It's either holds or it
doesn't hold that either
returns true or it returns false.
And axes is still list.
And then we return all
X for X drawn from
X is such that P of that's holds.
And for the filter,
further recursive
definition, right?
Again, for empty kids,
empty for list with
head axe entails X
is if p of x holds,
then we stick axons in the front,
recursively filter the tail,
and otherwise we don't include
acts and we just recursively
filter the tail.
And so as an example,
we can do filter of
pause of x's where
pause of x is x greater than 0.
Or for digits we can
do filter visit digit.
Again. I needed a where clause
because pauses into
library function.
But isdigit is already
defined as a function,
so you just need to have a
function defined in some way.
This case it's a function
that returns a Boolean.
So another name for a
function that returns
a boolean is a predicate.
And again, looking at the types.
Now our first argument p is
a function from a to bool.
Or first argument now is a
function from a to bool.
And then we get a list of a
and we return a list of a.
Any questions about that?
Yeah. So filter is also library
function just like map.
Yes. Oh, good question.
Is the definition in
the library a list comprehension
or is it by recursion?
Why do you care?
I'm actually quite
serious about this.
It's really important
in fact that I
don't tell you it's a secret.
And the reason why is
that means I can change
my mind later and
defined it another way,
if that becomes more efficient,
quantum computers are becoming
a thing next year
I'm going to use
the quantum computer
implementation
using quantum list
comprehensions,
which haven't been invented yet.
But next year they
will be and I'll
want to rewrite my
library to use them.
Right? So the question is,
which is it in the library?
Is it defined as a
list comprehension?
Is it defined as a function?
And the answer is,
don't ask that question.
Right? All you care about is what
it does and I'm
allowed to pick them,
but what I think it's
the best implementation
for the library.
Now there are actually
exceptions to that.
Sometimes you need to know the
efficiency of functions in
the library so that you can
design your own thing
to be efficient.
So it's not the case
that you never,
ever, ever want to know this.
But by default, basically,
you don't care,
you care about what it does,
not, how it does it.
And that's another
form of abstraction.
It's abstraction away from
the implementation so that
you're only concerned
with the specification
of what it does and
not with the details of
how it's implemented.
That's actually really important.
If I had to know
the details of how
everything in the
library was implemented,
I'd never be able
to write anything.
So this kind of abstraction
is a really important idea.
So that was a great question.
Yep. Yeah.
Good question. Can you have
more than one argument
that's a function.
Absolutely. Right? And you
can do all sorts of other things
we haven't talked about yet.
Like you can have
lists of numbers,
lists of characters, you can have
lists of lists of characters.
Guess what? You can have
lists of functions.
You have list of functions
whose argument is a list of
functions from a to B
that return and so on.
But you can combine things
and all sorts of ways.
But this is actually a
very important principle,
which is that once you
learn a basic idea,
you can use it any way
it fits together, right?
It's just like Lego.
And that Lego like
aspect to any two bits
that fit together,
maybe put together
is really important.
Kind of uniformity.
When people first
started Ryan computers,
they were small and
slow and they couldn't
make things uniform.
But we pretty quickly learn, No,
you should always
make things uniform.
So of course, if
you can have more
than one number argument,
you can also have more than
one function argument.
That's actually a really
important principle.
And took us awhile
to discover that.
Good question. Okay, good.
Are you ready for
your third pattern?
And this third pattern
is important because
both the patterns I showed
you are already built in,
in the form of list
comprehensions.
Write a map is not much
shorter than a list
comprehension.
Filter is not much shorter
than the list comprehension.
Probably you will very
rarely use map and filter,
except sometimes you'll be
forced to use them on exam.
But probably you'll
be very rarely use it
because you can use list
comprehensions instead.
But now I'm going to
show you one for which
a list comprehension
does not exist.
And that one is full.
So here's another pattern we've
seen some of 1234 is ten.
And how do we define that?
Some of the empty list is 0,
sum of x cons,
xs is take X
the head and added to
recursively sum up the tail.
Or we can do product.
So the product of a list,
if it's the empty list, it's one.
Or if it's blissed with
headaches and tells x's thing,
you take the head and
you multiply it by
recursively finding the
product of the tail.
Thick. I've got
third example here.
Yep, concatenate takes
a list of lists.
So concatenate of the list
123 and list 45 returns List
12345 and concatenate concat
of lists with four things in it.
Con, cat.
And, and eight gives us,
of course, concatenate.
So concat takes a list of lists,
each of type a, and it
returns a list of Taipei.
So concat of the empty
list is the empty list.
And concat of x,
x is not x because its list cons,
xs is, because it's
a list of lists,
is X is at the front.
And then plus, plus,
and then concat
recursively of XSS.
Okay? So you've seen
that pattern before.
And a really important
part of this pattern
is what do you do
for the empty list?
Right? So here it's 0,
but here it's one.
And here it's the empty list.
How did I choose which
thing to do? Use there?
Sorry, the identity, right?
So let's just fire up
Haskell for a moment.
Here we go up wrong one
bugger. Try that again.
So if I do 0 plus five,
what am I going to get?
And if I do one times 42,
And if I do empty string,
empty list, plus the list,
one dot, dot 20, what
am I going to get?
Oh, very good.
But if I was actually
doing concatenation,
what am I going to get
a list from one to 20?
Alright, and furthermore, it's
identity both ways around.
So five plus 0 is also
542 times one is also
421 dot dot 20
plus the empty list is o is
one dot dot pointing case.
You always pick the
thing that leads the,
you're trying to squeeze a
list down using an operator.
So you always pick the thing that
leaves a value with that
operator unchanged.
That's the rule for what
to do with the empty list.
Okay, so we've got pattern fold.
It's called foliar.
There's also a fold l,
which I'll teach you
about a different day.
So fold R takes a
function from a to a to
a function that takes
two a's and returns an a
and it takes a single a.
So this would be like plus,
this would be like 0.
This is a list of,
list of integer and that returns
an a that takes two arguments,
f and v. And list,
if it's the empty list,
just return v. If it's a
list with a head and a tail,
do fold R of f and
v and that list and
then just take f and apply
it to those two arguments.
So f, the head of the list and
recursively fold the tail.
We can also write this
with the infix notation.
So if you write back
tick F backed tech,
it's a backed tech,
not a single quote.
Then we can write
f in the middle,
which looks more like the
other things we define.
So now we can do some axis
is Fold r plus and 0.
And plus in parentheses
is the name of the
addition function.
So x plus y and plus applied to x
and y both mean exactly
the same thing.
This is just sort of a
nice way of writing this.
The real meaning is this.
Functions always take all
their arguments after them.
Infix is just what we
call syntactic sugar.
Right? Sorry. Right where
I want she is, right?
So when we write this, it's
again syntactic trigger x
f thingy is just
syntactic sugar for,
well, f Thing one Thing,
e2 is the real meaning,
but you can write that as x.
And back. Sorry, thingy, thing,
one thing, E2, they're
both the same thing.
Okay? So sum becomes
fold r plus and 0.
Product becomes folder
of times and one.
And concat becomes folder of
double plus an empty list.
Right? And there are
other things we can
do in that style.
So for instance, you've got
and which takes a list.
What's this going to return?
It's going to return.
What's this going to
return? We'll take a vote.
How many people think
it's going to return?
42 people.
How many people think it's
going to return true?
going to return false?
Alright, let's try
to work it out.
What's the identity?
For addition?
Actually, let's just do x
and y for each x drawn from,
let's count from false to true.
And for y, it's the floating y.
And y goes from false to true.
Let's see if that works.
I think falses smaller
than true. No, it's not.
Alright. Try that again.
How many falses or
am I going to get?
And how many trues, right?
And in this one,
x is false and y was
false and we get false.
So falses leave
things and changed.
Oh, sorry, falses
always give you false.
But notice that false
and true is false.
True and false is false
and true and true is true,
so true and something
leaves it unchanged, right?
True. We could write a quick
check property to test this.
I'm not sure I do that.
Now.
I'm not going to write the
QuickCheck poverty right now.
Sam, I've got five minutes.
Okay, import.
It's test dot quick.
Check this out, right?
Let's see if this works.
Good. Let prop and
identity of x and
y is equal to x and y equals x.
So this is checking that,
no, hate that with what?
This is checking that
x is the identity for
and and then if I do
a quick check, prop,
prop and By D
of true variable Mountains go,
oh, it's because I misspelled it.
Bugger. Yeah, live coding.
It's tough guys. It's pressure.
Right? Or I could have
written that another way.
But made it would've been
easier if I wrote it like this.
And we can check that's the
identity both ways right?
Now if I do quick check again
of that property, fail.
What what what what what
what what did I do wrong?
Somebody tell me
what I did wrong.
Sorry. Oh, no, that
should be okay.
Sorry. No, true and
why should always equal
y no matter what y is.
Now this should be, this
should both be true.
Alright? Alright, I've
done something wrong here.
I'm not sure what
I've done wrong.
Somebody will come
up after class and
explained to me the
idiotic thing I did.
But let's just check that one.
That one should work.
Alright, wait, I have
to redo the line.
Heating. Oh, yeah.
Now QuickCheck,
better return true or
else I will be sad.
What? Alright, well that's
what's going wrong.
But why? Why unfolds
should be equal to y?
Oh, I see what's going
wrong. Thank you.
Varicose. Haha. Haha. Thank you.
Right. It's a precedence error.
Okay. Okay. There we go.
You have to get the precedence,
Right. Thank you for that.
Okay, so now what's
hand of the empty list
going to give us?
And what's or the empty list
going to give us false.
And then we can do, right again.
Let prop and xs
is AND of x is always
equal to fold R and,
and true and x's.
So and can just be defined
using fold R. Will this work?
The tension mounts?
Yea. I'll stop.
I'm ahead. Thank you very much.