In the previous video,
we introduced the room for n and
justified it by looking
at this Venn diagram.
C is contained in the
intersection of a and b.
If and only if C is
contained in a and C is
contained in B. I asked
you to do the same again.
Start with the same Venn
Diagram that we started with,
but now made the Euler diagram
where you say something
about the relationship between
your new thing and a or B.
And I have 0B is of
course the union.
And try and write down a rule.
If we're going to draw
a general thing that's
related to a or B.
And what we want to do
is to draw outside.
If you went back and
imagine this on the sphere,
it wouldn't look so different.
If you imagine the original
one for end on the sphere,
and imagine this
one on the sphere,
then they'd be the same,
except that you
will be considering
the positive direction for
a and b to be reversed.
That's all the differences.
I'm not going to try and
draw it on the board.
It's easier to do with
the physical pole,
but it's worth thinking
about it because
that fact, really
DeMorgan's laws.
Try and think of this stretched
out, wrapped round sphere.
And try and think of the previous
diagram done the same way.
And you will find that they are
the same diagram that just
looked at upside down.
Again, it's this thing of
if we change the direction,
if we go to negatives,
then we get these
nice symmetry is
going that we've seen
with contraposition.
This blue thing is C,
and C is greater than this.
In other words,
everything in here is x3,
it everything in AC,
and everything in
B is C. So again,
we get a row, goes two ways.
And it really is the same rule,
same backwards if you
draw it on the sphere.
This is just like a slide for n,
except we've changed
the truth table up
the top to be the truth table
for all its only
when both are false,
then we return a
false part from that.
This is just the name
for all the semantic or,
the, or on predicates it sort of.
Returning to the previous slide.
Notice that a or B
satisfy C if and
only if a satisfies C
and B satisfies S0.
Sometimes people think
this should be an O.
That's an and here,
just as there was in
the room for end.
But the a's and b's
are on the left here,
whereas in the roof and
they're on the right.
Look, look at this diagram.
It's not one of them is
contained in the blue one.
They both have to be
contained in the blue one
is the blue one is going
to encompass a or b,
which is what we are saying.
This is I obey and it says,
the blue one includes
everything and I obey.
You have to get your
head around it.
But once you get your
head around it, it works.
I hope if I draw
a blue one and I've got
to draw it around AOB.
Aob is just the union
of those two circles.
So the only way to
draw it around AOB is
it certainly has to go around a
and it has to go
around B and said,
oh, I could draw
something around a that
doesn't go ramping.
Now we have simple rules for not.
And, and all.
These are valid in
any universe for any
predicates a, B, and C.