Now we're going to
do the same thing
for things. On the right.
We have the laws about not,
which say that a satisfies
the comedy if and only if a and
not the satisfies P. So we
take effectively the
diagram we had before.
But this time we're saying we're
focusing on the things
that don't satisfy
D. So this corresponds
to looking at things
which don't satisfy dy.
Doing that with a delta here.
To bring that delta
over here first,
we need to make all of
the deltas to make
it into one thing,
then we can bring it over here.
So that's not all delta.
What does it mean to
say not all delta?
I gave you three property.
It's not big or Reg
what does that mean?
It's not big and it's not red.
So to say that some
things in this is to
say every single one of the
properties in delta is false.
Something that's here. If any of
the properties in delta true,
it would be over here
because then we'd have,
yes, it's true for one of them.
So it's true for the
or of all of them.
So that takes us to,
if we have a delta on the right,
then this is valid in you.
If this is valid in
the universe of all
those things for which
everybody in delta is false.
And then of course
we're going to put
those two pictures together.
So here's the picture for
where every G is true.
Here's the picture for where
every day in delta is false.
And I can take the things
where every G is true,
that keeps me above
the green line,
where every day is false that
B brings me below the red line.
And that means that I'm looking
at this pit that's left.
This is the only one of
those few slides that
you need to remember.
This is the end point
of this little story.
It says that if I look at
one of these sequence
and a satisfies B,
which we're very familiar
with the extended
by putting a gamma
and adults are there.
How should we understand or
how can we understand it?
Because by choosing
different a's and b's,
we can always put things
in different orders.
So we could choose a different
day out of gamma and put
this one back or different
B out of delta is one back.
We choose an i and v. And then we
can say what we want
to know now is,
is a satisfies P valid in
the universe are those
things for which
every G and gamma is true.
And everyday in delta is false.
So that's a way of reading
it and putting it back
to something that's just
talking about every ISP,
which we can understand
more easily.