Now we're going to see how to
use these rules constructively.
Going to take an
expression and use
the rules to simplify it to
an equivalent expression.
The expression I've
chosen to simplify it,
just a randomly chosen example
created using the
connectives and, or and not.
The procedure we use will
work for any example.
I wanted to find a rule
that will leave me above
the line with something
simpler than what I
have below the line.
How can I make something
simpler above the line?
By simpler?
What I mean is I'll get rid of
some of these connective
so we call NOT and, OR,
and later on other operations
on Boolean values connectives,
because we're thinking now is
connecting this statement
with this statement.
This is made up by saying
we have this thing
within brackets
or p. That means we have an
OH on the right hand side.
So we look at this
rule to simplify it.
How has that happened?
We took the rule here.
The a was matched against
this thing in parentheses.
The B was matched against that
P. Those are the things
that are joined by all.
And we replace that
or by a comma.
And then of course we
could take off some of
the brackets because they
just get in the way.
We don't need them anymore.
So what's going to happen next?
Which rule are we going to use?
The only thing we can do is
to take the main connective.
We can't get inside these things.
We can't reach those knots
yet because they're inside.
An expression that's
been made with
end and is the main thing here,
and it's on the right.
We'll use the rule.
And on the right, we should
expect to get that rule.
And what will we get on top?
Try thinking what it'll
pay and see if you agree.
There. We have this
piece and this piece,
and then delta is
just p. So we're
here and we've got
the end on the right,
and the delta is
just a singleton.
It's got p. So I take the
left-hand thing of this,
which is not p or q,
and the right hand thing
of this which is not p,
and I split them and I put
this one here with delta,
and this one here
with delta was next.
We can do that one because
it's not a simple one.
Will do the rule not are.
If I do that, then I
get the p on the left.
And then immediately
I can notice that,
wow, there is the same
thing, left and right.
What does this tell me
if I stop at this stage,
it tells me that this is
satisfied in some universe.
If and only if this is
satisfied in the same universe.
If and only if this and this
are satisfied in a universe.
And by the way, this
is satisfied and
the universe if and only if this
is, and they certainly is.
So this pits, we
don't need anymore.
And what we've now shown
is that this thing
satisfied is equivalent
to that being satisfied.
We can keep going next row.
What's it going to be?
What's the main
connective is not o.
The o is the o.
We do the 4x and that just
replaces the O with a comma.
And now what we do,
we're gonna get rid of
all the connectives
and we've only got one left.
So we're going to use
not on the right,
we move the p across
with the not,
then we have an immediate rule.
Now what we've found is these are
both valid in any universe.
So these are valid.
This is valid, this is valid.
This is valid in every universe.
We've started with
some expression
and we've broken
it down like that.