What I want you to do now
is to try and keep
up with the machine.
It'll just start doing
this itself slowly.
I want you to look
at what's here and
think what's the next
stage going to be?
For instance, here, this
is the main connective,
is to the right of the turnstile.
So we'll use or on the right.
That's this one.
We'll replace it with a comma,
or what I want you to do is
to just try and keep up.
We've identified the or
the comma goes in and we
get that one on the right.
Now what's the main connective?
It's not on the outside there.
When there's a choice
between doing something
that moves one thing or
something, branches.
Do the one thing first,
because you'll get rid of it.
You won't have two copies of it.
So what's the next connective?
We could either do an end on
the left or on or on the right.
And since those are both easy,
because what do we do with ans on
the left replaced
them with commerce.
And what do we do with
Always On the right
replaced them with commerce.
So this time we will just
replace those with commerce.
And now let's start on the left,
I think is where I've
decided to do it.
Yes. What happens
within or on the left?
This all this proves
that means that we have to
have, this proves that.
And this proves that both of
them have to go on the left,
so we have to duplicate it.
We get the not a
and then the rest,
and we get the b.
And then the rest.
Now doesn't have to be
a single letter that's
repeated there.
We've seen that not a
occurs on both sides.
So we can immediately
say it's immediate.
And bore line on top.
That deals with that side.
What happens on the other side?
Again, we got the all rule.
So we get this Nazi at
the beginning and a
not b and we replace,
we do both of those
with the resp repeated.
So the first one is
the B and then the
Nazi that comes from left
hand side of the 4x,
and then whatever's on the right,
next one is the B, the B again.
And then whatever
came on the right.
So now we're going to move that
see across while
moving that c across.
This gives me two
things on the right,
I might as well just write one of
them because this is a set.
If I look at that, I
can now move the a,
it's a not, so I move
it to the other side.
There's a stray comma
there, but never mind.
And once we have that,
we can't go any further.
So we come down here and look
up what's happening here.
We had to be so we'll just
keep one of them and they
say we'll move over to the
left and that's the end.
We can't go any further.
We can't do anything with this.
And well, this is the same,
but that's just by chance.
What does this tell me?
Here? We know that
this is always valid.
So if this is valid,
tendencies apart,
in order to say
that this is valid,
we have to say that this one is
valid and this one's valid.
So we've got a much simpler
way of talking about this.
Let's suppose this is valid than
we've deduced that
these must be valid.
And in fact, since
they're the same,
but we've deduced that
this must be valid.
Similarly, if these are valid,
then we can track back down
because these are all
double, double line rules.
And say this is valid,
this is valid if and only if
this is valid. It's magic.
So the upshot of that is,
these things are valid
in some universe U,
if and only if this is
valid in that universe.
That means effectively,
we've derived a new rule.
Has to be a bit silly to
have around as a rule
because this is rather
special purpose thing.
Why would we want it?
But if it was some very
important thing to us,
we can have that there and say,
actually, we've got a rule
that deals with this,
whatever that funny
combination is.
Okay? So this is a way that
you can make new rows.
If you're given
something like this,
you can make a rule that says,
how do I treat it when
it's on the right.
You could also take
something and put
it on the left of the
turnstile and then say,
how do I treat it when
it's on the left?
Using the same tricks?
And in this example, of course,
because those two things are
actually the same thing,
we can write it as that rule.
This also lets us
show when some complicated
expression is false,
if I want to produce
a universe in which
this doesn't hold,
then I just need to produce
a universe where
this doesn't hold.
Because any universe
where this is valid,
this is valid and vice versa.
So if I make something
where this doesn't hold,
I know that in that
universe, this won't hope.
How do I make a comma b
satisfies, say not hold.
What kind of individual
Do I need to
show you to show that
that's not true?
Because remember
saying it holds is
to say for every individual,
if a and B are both properties
of that individual,
then c is a property.
So in order to show
that that's not true,
we just needed to
produce one individual
for which a holds and p holds,
but C doesn't hold.
So how do we do that? Make
a world with an individual?
A is true, that
individual pay is true,
that individual and C is false
that you can, for example,
counterexample to that,
makes every antecedent,
everything on the left True,
and every succeeding false,
everything on the right false.
And then we've got
a counterexample
that will work to provide
a counterexample.
Even if you've got 20
things on the right,
30 things on the left,
nothing on the right,
nothing on the left.
Any number any number
as big as you like.
That's what it means to have
a counterexample is to say,
I'll give you something for
which everything on
the left is true.
Everything on the right is false.
The only time you
could get something
that looks a bit like this
and couldn't do that
would be the same.
Latter occurred both on
the left and the right.
But when the same letter
occurs both on the
left and the right,
then we can apply
the immediate rule.
So we'd never get one of those.
If we end up with one
of these sequence,
then we can always
produce a counterexample.
If there are many of them
counterexample to any one of
them will be a counter-example
to what's at the bottom,
two different inference trees.
On the left, we've got
the first one we did.
Every branch is terminated.
We think that this is a tree
that we draw the tree for you.
Trees start from
the ground and they
grow up and they have branches.
Cedar trees. That's what
a tree is mathematically.
The tree on the left,
every branch is terminated
by an immediate rule.
So we call those pieces of
the tree branches
paths ago of flight.
That sequent we started from
is valid in every universe.
That's what we get from that.
On the other hand, we can
get a case like this where
some branches lead,
lead to leaves.
And these leaves are
sequences with only atoms
because we couldn't get
rid of any connective.
There's a role for
it. So we just keep
applying the rules to be got
rid of all the connectives.
That's what simpler means.
We're making them simpler by
getting rid of connective.
If anatomy occurs on both sides,
then we can apply the immediate
rule so we don't get a leaf.
But if it doesn't,
then we can make a counterexample
jaw starting sequence
is valid in some universe U,
if and only if each of
the leaves is valid.
To make it invalid,
we just have to invalidate
one of the leaves.
That gives you huge power.
I can make it very complicated
down the bottom and mechanically,
just now, find the right rule.
Sometimes there will be more
than one rule that applies,
doesn't matter which
one you do first,
you will get an
equivalent answer.
Whichever way you do it, it
might take longer for you.
Sometimes if you choose
to do a branching thing
before you do a single
continuing one,
you'll get there in
the end, it will
terminate. Why will it terminate?
Why does this procedure stop?
How do I know I can get
some really tricky formula
where it will keep going.
I think the easiest
way is to talk
about the death of connectors.
We talk about, but not next to
pay years having
depth one let say.
And then if I put that together,
that's got depth true.
So we're talking about
how deeply nested
It is and the depth,
the maximum depth is coming
down cuz you always take
the maximum depth one
and get rid of it.
Now you bought
smaller ones and that
can only be finite
many of that depth.
So you'll get through all
those finite the many.
And now you've taken
the depth down.
So you can write
that kind of proof.
All I want you to do is
not write down the proof.
I want you to really believe
it in your head that
this is going to stop.
It may get complicated.
You may need more paper,
but it will start it.
That's achieved what I want
you to get over in this lecture,
there are these roles with
the gammas and deltas.
The gammas and deltas
can be added to rules
because they're
just talking about some
particular sub universe.
I think Amazon deltas aren't
conceptually difficult.
The sense of what does it mean,
they just mean you're looking
at some sub universe.
They are very useful
because they enable you to
do proofs in ways you
couldn't without having them.
That this keeps track all
complicated arguments.
If this word then
we could look at
this sub universe and
that will be true.
And you don't need to do that.
You just manipulate the rules
and it's doing it for you.
And you can apply those
rules mechanically.
And either you'll end up with
immediate rules everywhere.
In which case, the
thing you were talking
about is valid in every
universe or you weren't.
In which case, you will
find various sequence at
the top that enable
you to construct
counterexamples that show that
it's not valid everywhere.