When we were doing that,
we were writing things down
like a and B and not B.
And these are talking
about actual predicate.
So I'm thinking of
those just the way
when you write in algebra,
you write down things
like a squared minus b,
x plus c. But they're
really talking
about numbers set quite
often in algebra,
we just think of
ourselves as dealing with
equations and we're
gonna do the same.
It's logic. Are we going
to do it a bit more
formally than you
normally do in algebra?
So far, we've been
treating logic just
the same way as you
normally use algebra.
We're talking about things.
We write connectives down.
When we interpret it,
we give values to the variables.
For us, the values
were predicates.
The operators were and are not.
Here. The values are
numbers, the operators,
multiplication and so forth.
But it's very similar.
We've talked about
predicates because
they enable you to
have this picture of
every a is b means the
collection of things that have
the property a is contained
in the collection of things
that have the property B.
You have a nice picture of
this inclusion relation.
And actually everything has come
out of that inclusion relation.
The way we axiomatize where
we gave the roles for and,
and or was by looking at that
picture and saying, well,
how do we describe the way
the intersection of
these two things work?
Some things contained in the
intersection if and only
if it's contained in
both of the things you
were intersecting.
And similarly with all
the other way round,
the union is contained
in something.
If each of the things in
that union is contained
in something,
what I want to do now is
to look at it
slightly differently because
we can simplify things.
We don't need to think
of all Universities
where there might be millions
of them and these
people and stuff,
we can apply our stuff
to those universes.
But when we're working,
we can actually focus
down and look at
a much smaller set of things
to see what's going on.
Let's just see what we've done.
We've got predicates.
We've got various operations on
predicates like and, and, or.
And. We have these
subsets as predicates.
Propositions are predicates.
There just functions
from U to blue.
And we can lift the
logical operations,
like not up to operations
on predicates.
And we've done the same friend.
And that's quite confusing,
but it's something
you really should
keep looking and get
your head around because
it's a very important
idea that we
lift the operations from
just operations on Boolean values
to operations on
predicates or sets.
How many things are there?
How many properties?
We don't actually need to look at
everything that might be,
because we're going
to treat things the
same if they're the same for
the properties we've got.
So this is a principle.
Leibnitz protein.
Lipid says, well, what does it
mean to say there are two things.
If there are two
things, you need to be
able to tell the
difference between them.
So if you can't tell the
difference that the same.
And we're going to
use that principle,
but we're going to use it in the,
in the formal setting off.
If we're just talking
about five properties,
then we can only ever need
a universe that has two to
the fifth different individuals.
Because that was the only
different possibilities
we can have.
And as far as we're concerned,
either we have something
with that combination of
properties or we don't have
something with that
combination of properties.
Here you see, we say end is done
on properties by extending this,
lifting it up to this
to get that's a and b.
That a or B.
But in general, when we do that,
we just get some collection
of these regions.
Each part of this is either
in our property or it's not.
So we only need
one representative
for each of those things.
So I've now label these.
There is no label in
the white PIT outside
because none of the
properties is true.
This is a Venn diagram
for four variables.
And these are the various labels
where these are the
things that are true.
So right in the
middle that as ABCD,
all four of them are true.
Elsewhere, there
are a lot of things
with three of them true.
Withdraw them true, with
only one of them true,
and then outside with
none of them true.
Ok. So these things can be
labeled just with here.
A is true, P is false,
C is false, and this is true.
All we need to look
at is individuals.
Like this. As an individual,
which we'll call tau false,
false true as an individual
which we'll call false,
false, true, true.
If we have those individuals,
that's all we need.
Cost terror, the labels a, b, c,
d. So what are these?
For each of my variables,
I got a truth value.
So each one of these could
be done as a list of pairs.
It could play a is
true, b is true,
c is false, or it could be
besides just the function.
So again, we're going
to use functions.
There's going to be
called valuations.
And that's where I'm going to
stop for today. Thank you.