In this video, we're
going to introduce
implication by giving a
rule for implication.
Many of you wanted to
interpret this as a implies b.
That's exactly right.
If that is valid in a universe,
it means the same thing as saying
that in that universe,
a implies B.
We're going to analyze
what that means.
If we take a satisfies b,
then one thing we can
do with the rules we
have is to take the
a to the other side and
negate it. So we
get not a, b.
And once we've done that,
we can apply the rule
for OR on the right,
and we find not a or b.
If we put this
together with that,
we can play our
usual trick: because
these rules are valid
in any universe,
we can add gammas
and deltas. Here,
here, and the delta here.
Once we have that,
we know that we have a chain.
This is equivalent to this,
which is equivalent to this.
I'll put it at the bottom
just so we can see it.
Gamma satisfies a implies b or delta.
If we let delta be empty and
we let gamma be not a or b,
then this says not a or b
satisfies not a or b,
but that's the same as not a
or b satisfies a implies b.
And that works the
other way round.
If I put a implies b for gamma,
then here I get a implies
b satisfies not a or b.
So these two will be equivalent.
We can write the truth
table for implies.
So here we have false and true,
and here we have false and true.
Let say this is a and that's b
for a implies b.
When is it false
that a implies b?
It's false that a
implies b if we can
make 'a' true and 'b' false.
So if a is true and
b is false. False there,
but it must be true
everywhere else,
precisely because this is
valid wherever that is valid.
So that's a rule for a implies b.
Now we can do another trick:
let's find a rule for
a implies b on the left. If we have
a implies b satisfies something.
We're going to replace that
with what we found
was equivalent to a implies b:
not a OR b.
Now we're just playing our
normal game of reducing.
So we can use the rule for that,
which is if gamma together with
not a satisfies delta
and gamma together with
b satisfies delta.
So now we've said the rule for
a implies b on the left is this.
We can simplify slightly more.
That is the same as gamma
satisfies a comma delta.
So the rule that we end up with
for implication on the
left is that we have
gamma satisfies a comma delta
and gamma comma b
satisfies delta.
That's equivalent to gamma a
implies b satisfies delta.
So that's the rule for
implies on the left.