Normally Claudia does that,
but it seems we are
without her, which is fine.
Okay, let me just recap
briefly for the recording.
We're looking at
this sequent here,
and we're trying to reduce
it using the rules.
And we'll see what
reduction means as we
go through to the
first thing I did.
This is not A or B satisfies
not a and not B,
which is one of the De Morgan's rules
for pushing negations inside.
In this case inside
the disjunction, I negate,
these two, which turns the
disjunction into a conjunction.
The first thing
we're going to do is
to address the fact we got an
not here by taking this
rule for negation.
Rule for negation on the left,
which says if I have a
negation on the left,
I can move the a turnstile
and change the sign.
So what I've done is to
move this not a or b,
across the turnstile,
change its sign.
And this is just copied up.
Now I am going to address
this and I'm going to
focus on this conjunction here.
I want the rule for
conjunction on the right.
And that is that if I'm a groups
a delta and gamma
sorry satisfies,
and that is B comma delta that
happened from gamma.
I can deduce a or
delta from gamma.
I can deduce b or delta.
Then I can deduce a and
B are delta, though.
Either something in delta is true,
in which case we can certainly
deduce the delta.
So what we're seeing
now is that a and
B here and match it against this?
We can't hear you.
Can you hear me now?
Yes. Sorry, good. I've no
idea why this happened.
It suddenly decided I couldn't
share audio or video.
And you now see the camera?
Yes, you can. I have no
idea what that was.
Technical glitch
which came out of
nowhere. Between these two lines
is what you were asking me about?
Yes. Yes. So what I
did was to focus on
this connective, if I
could have focused
on this or and done things
in a different order.
But I chose to focus on this and
then I look for a rule
that will help me
simplify by getting rid of
this conjunction rule and the rule that I
used was this rule up here,
which we call and on the right.
Okay and that rule says in
a slightly different
order because we have,
think we're focusing on with
the end this first
here and then delta,
because it's a set, I could not have the
delta before, it's the same.
So delta in this case
will just be this.
I just copy the
delta up in each case.
So I copy this A or B up
in each of those cases.
Then where I had where I
had a I had
not a and not B that matches
against the a and B.
So instead of copying up
the a, coming up the B,
I'm applying the rule to
this cropping up the not a,
I've got here and there not
be which I've got here.
Because literally I
match against this rule.
And on the right, provided
I've got the matching right,
I just write up here that
the matching for that
one was in the rule.
I have a matching it
to what did I have?
I had a naught a in the row.
I had to be. Do you think I
was matching it to I had a not B.
And that's because I
was matching a and B
against a and not B.
This one was in the rule,
and this was in the
actual example that
I'm doing. In the rule.
I have a delta and I'm
matching that against
the singleton which
only contains a or b.
So that's the way that this line,
o and gamma is empty.
Because that'll make sense.
Yes. Thank you. Thank you.
I am completely against this
line. With this matching.
I'll rewrite the top line,
getting this dictionary
effectively. Okay, thank you.
No way to write it down,
but normally you can do
it in your head once
you've got the idea,
but the first time I should
have explained it like that.
You're right. That
help. Thank you.
Thank you very much. A other
questions on this one?
I don't hear anybody.
Are you there?
I know one.
They will raise a hand.
I think I'm not online.
Weekend here. It's probably
no questions. No questions.
It's amazing what we're going to
do the remainder of this week
and next week's tutorial.
The tutorial assignment
is really just to go
through a couple examples
like this and work through them.
In the tutorial.
Audio has cut-off.
Come back. Can you hear me?
Yes, we can hear you now.
So my question was,
I can only use two
questions and I
get four different
values for that rate.
So I need to get 00011011 for
me to get used to is right into.
My next question was,
in the videos for this week.
You talked about or
this conjunction in that
it was every C is a and B.
But you made a diagram in
which intersection of
AB was supposed to be.
But you made the sea
circle a bit smaller.
Not all the elements of a and B.
Is there a particular
reason for that?
That certainly was
the re the reason is
we want to talk about
the condition where
every say included a and
every city is included in B.
We're not talking about a
being equal to a and B.
We're saying if C is
included in a and C
is included in B,
that's the same as saying that
C is included in a and B.
So the diagram is like this.
We've got a and we've got B.
And now we want to say,
when is city in here?
We don't have an inequality.
What we're talking about here
is an inequality effectively,
we are saying when is c
contained in a, contained in B?
That the picture is we
want to know when C
is contained in them.
So not necessarily it would be
true for the
intersection of them.
It's certainly true that
the intersection satisfies
a and the intersection B.
That's because a and B
is contained in a and B.
This is a more general
thing that we say.
In some sense. That's
the big difference
between logic and
ordinary algebra.
We're interested in or in
these relationships
rather than inequalities.
That make some sense.
Yeah, I got that.
My other question
was in terms of the
and that we use the one
which has and colon.
And yes, it is from Yue Du Bu.
Like one function you
double than it is.
Again, you do bool and
at the end it gives
you Y does not give you
only bool at the end.
Like why is it you who ruined?
Because, okay, what we want to do
is in this case we
want to take a and B.
And both of those
and the functions,
this is a picture of a function.
So a is of type due to boom
and be a tie due to bool.
And what we want to do
is to make something.
We've got one predicate,
we got another predicate.
We want to make the predicate,
which is the intersection,
so, which is this piece?
And how do we define it?
We defined it by
saying, Dave, I take,
I'll write it without the
Haskell premium if I take
a and B and apply to x,
and that's the same as taking.
We are taking a point in here,
an x, we're saying
is again a and B.
So here it's not because
it's in B, but not in a.
Out here it is. In a
but he's not in B.
And here, how do I check?
Is it in a? I apply
this function and see
if I get through.
So I'll get a true b of x here,
but I won't get a true pariah
that here I'll get
true for both them.
So this is equal to
a of x and p of x.
Now here I'm using
the same symbol as I would
use if these were just
two truth values.
I've used the same symbol
for the and on predicates.
And the, and on truth values go.
You have to be a
little more precise.
I have to say the end on
predicates is a
different operation.
Truth values. Then
we say a and, okay,
that's how we wrote it and,
and be applied to X equals a,
a applied to x.
And then that's the
operation on booleans.
So we really just define and on
predicates using the
end on Booleans.
But in Haskell we use
different names for them.
But I still don't get why
the output is you do bool.
Because what we want the output
we want to put you in a,
we want to put in B, and
we want to get this thing.
What is this thing?
It's a subset.
But in the function,
you get a of x,
you get true or false,
and we'll be off anti-aligned.
I get true or false.
It's just yeah.
And like whatever,
combat that for any x.
So you see this thing
comes out true or false
once we're given an x,
it says, I take an individual x,
x will be of type U.
And I apply a and,
and b to this thing of type u.
What is the result? So x is
one of these things here.
Well, here we are trying to
work out where it is
looking at these two.
And we give a true,
they're both true,
then it will be true.
If one of them is false and
it will give us a false.
It'll be over all function
as being defined
as you'd be bool.
Because we are giving
xt and edges. I view.
This is just like a
normal if I say f of x
equals x and v of x.
And what will let f be a
function of x is two Booleans.
Or what's happening here.
Okay, so we're defining
a function here.
I understand why it's
difficult to get because
most languages don't work like
this and we don't use
functions so much.
But this is what
makes language like
Haskell really powerful
is that we can do this,
we can find functions
from other functions.
And it turns out to be quite
a powerful way of computing.
Ran. I got when you've got that,
you've got a long way in your
understanding of Haskell,
So I'm glad you got it.
And if other people are
still having problems,
by all means, ask again or or.
Ask your, ask your friends
and discuss it
amongst yourselves.
But this is really
an example of something
we'll do a lot in Haskell.
We wanted to define
a new function.
We say, how do I
define a function?
What it does for a
given x o here I
say how to define
a new function made
out of two functions.
I'll define what he
does by saying what
it does to annex
what it does is to
apply the first function 2x plus
the second function 2x and
then take the
conjunction of those.
And that's happening here.
Just because of the typing.
We have two different notations
for and we normally
don't think of that.
If you think of what's
going on in the real world.
This intersection here is
intersecting two sets.
We define it in terms of
the unknown truth values.
Something is in bits in
this one as a Boolean
value, is it not?
And it's in this one, it's
a Boolean, value, it
in this one or not.
So it's in here.
It's in both of these.
That's all this is
saying. Thank you.
Ok. I think your next Yes.
Can you hear me? I can
hear you. Thank you.
Yeah. So I was late to
this Asia, East Asia.
So like what you,
what you are doing in the
beginning of this session is
that irradiation
of DeMorgan's law.
I want to ask, is this,
how we derive this
DeMorgan's law?
Or is kind of,
we have these rules,
we have this sequence.
We can reduce it by
applying the rules
backwards and we find that
we end up no assumptions.
So that tells us,
this is always valid.
That tells us that this
predicate is contained in this
predicate always in
any universe, plenty.
Or you could say a and
B, not of a or B is
contained in not a and not B. Oh,
that those two are equal.
We have to also show the
inequality the other way round.
That's just the inequality.
If we show that one, which
we can do in the same way.
But I'll leave as an
exercise for you guys.
Then we will have shown
they're equal because it
says one predicate is
contained in the other.
It says it's also contain the
other way to think of sets.
If one is contained in the other,
the other is contained
in the first,
and they're both equal.
That's what weekly.
That's the way we
define the equality
predicates that help, yeah.
And my question is that netbook,
in the textbook there's a white
rabbit or the other sound.
Like because in the book I say
that they're doing different.
Yeah, that was that was
a deduction. I did.
Where we show we show that
what Don does in the book
because I did it last
year in the lectures,
I'll show you the kind
of proof we give.
If we take not a or not b.
And here we're going to tell you,
it might have been the other
DeMorgan's law you have,
but this will be the same.
Okay? So now what I'm going to
do is to apply the rules to this.
I have an order on the right.
I can say that that's.
Not a, not b.
And because these are negated,
can bring both those
to the other side.
That's a, B.
This is valid if and
only if this is valid.
Because each of these
is a double root.
Does that make sense?
Yes. Okay. This is
the rule or on the
right and this is
the rule for not on the
right applied twice,
but I just add them together.
And now we'll do the same
thing here or others,
the same procedure that we
have to start with the not.
So that becomes a and the, okay.
You've got this aside and
take away this negation.
Now I use the rule on
the left, the room,
and on the left is that
we can get about that.
This is equivalent to, this
is equivalent to this,
but that's the same as that.
So these are
certainly equivalent.
This is equivalent to, this
is equivalent to this.
So what this says is in a
universe where this is valid,
this is valid and vice versa.
And that was the kind
of proof that was
given in that other one.
Is that what you
were talking about?
I think he probably is.
Yes. Yes. And now lacked
the n on the left.
Is that saying that a and b,
and this i is equivalent.
So a comma b.
Let me read what this says
is we can have of a and b true.
Because what this says
is if both of these are
true and something on
the right is true,
this there's nothing
on the right.
Yes. When these both be true.
The other way to use
this is instead of just
doing this with these,
you know, gamma deltas,
I can put gamma
that an adulterer.
They're everywhere.
Because we know that those
rules are also valid.
And now we can play
a trick to remember
if a rule is valid,
we can always add
things either sides,
long as we keep the
things the same.
And it's just like talking
about smaller universe.
If the rule I had originally
was valid in all universes.
And this rule with
the extra piece,
It's valid in all universities.
And now the trick is to say, oh,
well let's let gamma
be not a or not,
just that single thing.
If I start here.
That's certainly true
because now I have
the same thing on both sides.
If gamma equals not a or not b,
Amazon certainly satisfies not
a or not b because it's
the same on each side.
For that gamma. This is true.
It's true that not a or not
B entails not a or not b.
And keep that same gamma here.
That same gamma here.
Gamma. We find that.
Not a or B,
actually in a and B.
Or we can go that way by
letting gamma B that.
And now what we're
going to do is to go
the other way or doing the
same trick effectively.
So that was 11 derivation.
Because he knows.
Now we're going to set
a that gamma b, not a,
and B on this side is not a,
not a and B.
So I've got the same
thing on each side.
So then I bring that gamma
roll away round here,
find a and B
entails a, O, B.
And once we have those
two, we can just say,
if I choose this one for gamma,
then this is obviously true.
And now I can come around
and derive this much,
this one for gamma,
then this is obviously true.
And I can go around
here, improve that.
That's putting on the
two groups together.
So then at the end they are
both a subset of each other.
So at the end about
this opposite of
each other and we've shown
that Bogan's LO, Yes.
One last question is When we
arrived that this two are equal.
But graduates, like at last
I have not parenthesis,
not a or not b equal
to a and b to kind of
add and not, again,
suppose i to make it this n
to the n. And so at the end,
I have these two
equal to each other.
But the thing I have
not parentheses.
I got no parenthesis
a and B equals to o.
The rabbit is a and B is
equal to NOT parenthesis,
not a or not b.
Well, n equals not,
That's what you're talking about.
Yes. Just like can we add or
not at both sides
to make it back?
It should look like, like you
can add a to both sides
and this one cancels out.
So we can do that
because I was not
sure if we can I can
tell you that you're
actually going out to
the sides and then and then
these two naughts cancel out.
So you get that. Okay. Thank you.
I think that's all my questions.
But what I was saying here is
you're going to this tweak,
just learn to do it is
with and, and or not.
Once we have this method,
we will then extend it to
do other connectives like
implication and X0 and
all the other things you
may have learned about.
You did some Boolean
algebra before.
And you will find that
we can these bricks
the reduction with all the
different correctives.
So we will give you
Saturday after you've
submitted your work on this,
will actually give you some
more things to discuss.
The tutorial that will change
the tutorial slightly for
this week in the sense that
going to give you some work to
do which we haven't seen or at
least you haven't submitted
your work on it
before the tutorial,
that you can work in
tutorial and then for
the next week's tutorial
of pre-prepared.
So I'll be interested
to see how you think
that we're Does anyone
have more questions?
I see they're asking us
how gamma ray Altera
just generic sets.
Amaranth delta can be anything.
So it allows you to generalize
your argument because
gamma and delta can be
any sets of predicates.
And as we saw with that
trick, I just paid.
Then by substituting one
thing in for gamma or rather,
I can actually make use of
the same chain reasoning
different ways.
That was a good example for that.
Then what I would ask
you is your tents of
the past in terms of two things.
Firstly, difficulty, was
that reasonably okay?
I I want it to be so
easy that you think
wasn't worth taking.
I want it to be not so
hard that you think,
gosh, it's totally impossible.
So I'd like a three out
of the four questions,
was everyone reasonably
happy that they should
they should be able to do
it in terms of timing,
Did you feel very rushed or
a little bit rushed
or just about?
If you want to, you
can gave answers to
those questions
anonymously, yachts,
but still be very
helpful to us to
hear how you felt it was
him in terms of difficulty,
in terms of timing.
And the final thing
is I know that
some people had difficulties
with submission.
And we're going to try
and deal with this,
as we said with the with
the emails that came in,
we weren't able to answer all
your emails individually,
beverage as so many of them.
How many of you that we will try
and get every cancers
once we've worked out
what's happening at
any one thiol to
submit at all in
including my email,
if other things failed,
rushed anymore questions
in a renown poll?
Questions, that's fine.
We will have the
session on Monday
again and have a good weekend.
Make sure you get some respite.
Get your submissions in.
I'm or even before
time as soon as you
can tell the tutorial site to
just have those submitted.
And then I can I will
see you on Monday.
Thank you very much.
Indeed. I'm going
to leave now. Thank you.