Good morning. Going to go through
the basics of syllogisms
starting right from
the very beginning.
In the beginning, we have
a universe full of things.
And we want to say something about
the things in the universe.
So for instance, we may say there
are things that have
the property a.
So I've drawn the set of
things such that they
have the property a.
A property is represented as
a function from
things to booleans.
And in here we have
the set of things,
x, such that a of x is true.
And outside, we have the set of
things such that a of x is false.
We can then have
another property,
b, and everything
that is in a is in b.
So whenever a of x is true,
b of x is also true.
In here, a of x is false,
but b of x is true.
And out here, both
of them are false.
We write this relationship
as every a is b.
We can have another
property which is to
say that every a is NOT b.
Let's draw a picture of
that. In this example,
here's a. And if I want to
say that every a is NOT b,
then I put b here.
Every a is not b. For any x
for which a of x is true,
b of x is false.
It's also true that for any
x for which b of x is true,
a of x is false.
So that's the same as
saying every b is not a.
Now on the diagrams those
two look very different.
But that's just because
of the way we've
chosen to draw the diagram.
If I look at this apple. On here,
I've drawn a on one side
and b on the other side.
So that is like this
diagram put on an apple.
What if I try and draw
this diagram on the apple?
Is it a different diagram?
And now I'm going to draw a here.
And then I have to
draw b around it,
but suppose I draw
b round there,
I can make it bigger
and bigger until in
the end I can draw b round here.
So now we have there, b.
Of course, the things
in b are here.
Every a is in b and
the things in b are there.
These are the things
that are not b.
But if I now compare
both my apples,
then I've just got the circles.
And the only difference is
in the way I labeled b.
The only difference is
whether I consider on
this apple for b to be true in
this direction and
on this apple for
b to be true in that direction.
These two diagrams,
if we draw them on an
apple, become equivalent.
It's useful to have
a notation where
we don't have to draw
things on apples.
If we use a Venn diagram,
we can see the relationship
between these things
more clearly.
Here. We say I have a, I have B.
And whereas in an Euler diagram,
there's an assumption that every
region we see on the diagram -
here we see three regions:
this one, this one, and this one -
every region has
something in it. On
a Venn Diagram. We don't.
So here we can draw
this diagram and say,
what's special is that
of these four regions,
one of them isn't
in the Euler diagram
because it's empty.
And in this case, it's
this one that's empty.
In this case, which
region is empty?
We still have only
three regions here:
we have the thing where
they're both false,
where one of them is true,
where the other is true.
But we're missing any region
where they're both true.
So we're missing this piece.
The Venn diagram on an
apple would simply say,
let's draw something
like this for a.
And let say a is true on
this side and not a on this side.
This could be the
Greenwich Meridian.
And then we'll use the
equator for b, let's say
b is true up here,
and b is false down here.
So then we have all four
places represented.
And all that's happening
is that we're saying one of
these places is empty for
each of these diagrams.
And here you can
see the symmetry.
So really, although
for Aristotle,
these were very
different propositions.
For us, we can treat
them exactly similarly.