Good morning. We'll need this later.
Going to start by reviewing
very briefly some of the
material on syllogisms.
The important point is to
get across the idea of
a proposition because
that's what we
generalize to make a sequent.
So we start from
Aristotle's propositions
and move on to sequents,
which were introduced by Gentzen.
But we start very simply:
we have a universe of
things and we have
some collections of things
with particular properties.
So here are the
collection of things
that satisfy the property a.
For any thing in the
universe, let's say x,
then this is the set of things
such that 'a' holds of x.
We represent 'a' as a function.
So 'a' of x is a boolean
value, true or false.
And this is the set of things
such that 'a' of x is true.
Set of x, such that
'a' holds of x is what I've
drawn a diagram of here.
And we're interested
in the relationship
between different predicates.
So for example,
here's a predicate,
another one, b. There I've
drawn the set of things such that
b holds of x. And in this diagram,
everything that's in a is in B.
And I'm going to write that
in a symbolic notation.
As a satisfies b,
which I say as all a are b.
We then take another example,
and this time we'll say
this is a, this is b.
And here is the case
that no a are b.
Every a is contained in
the complement of b.
Every a is not b. And we
use this symbol for not.
If I take something in a and it
doesn't satisfy b, for every x in
a, b of x is false. No a are b.
If we now look at that, this
is completely symmetric.
So this tells us our
first logical rule.
If every a is NOT b,
then it's the same
as every b is not a.