To formalize Aristotle's theory
of syllogisms,
we introduced propositions
with this notation:
a satisfies b.
Which means in an
Euler diagram: here's
the universe and a
is contained in b.
And if we want to say
that a does NOT satisfy b,
we must provide a
counterexample.
And a counterexample is
an x in the universe such
that a holds of x and b doesn't.
That is, it's an x
for which a of x
is true and b of x is false.
And here we're
mixing notation from
Haskell with the
mathematical notation.
But you should learn
to translate between
those two. Gentzen's sequents are
a simple but very
powerful generalization
of this. A sequent
looks very similar.
It's talking about something and
says gamma satisfies delta.
But whereas here a and b are
predicates of type
u -> Bool, here
gamma and delta are finite
sets of predicates
which we'll represent
in Haskell as
lists of things from u -> Bool.
And the easiest way to
explain what we mean by
gamma satisfies delta is to
say what we mean by
a counterexample.
So we will say that
gamma does not
satisfy delta if we
have a counterexample,
which will be an x of type u
such that for all g in gamma,
because of course, gamma
is a list of predicates.
So for all predicates in
gamma, g of x equals true.
And for all d in delta,
d of x equals false.
So a counterexample is
given by exhibiting
an x such that it satisfies
every g in gamma,
and it satisfies no d in delta.